<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>CNS</title><link>https://nrouizem.github.io/test/cns_feed.xml</link><description>Daily curated &amp; summarized biopharma news.</description><atom:link href="https://nrouizem.github.io/test/cns_feed.xml" rel="self"/><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 01:19:25 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>How Capsida’s unconventional funding strategy and capsid technology promise to reshape CNS treatments</title><link>https://www.drugdiscoverytrends.com/how-capsidas-unconventional-funding-strategy-and-capsid-technology-promise-to-reshape-cns-treatments/</link><description>Capsida Biotherapeutics has gained significant momentum through partnerships with major pharmaceutical companies, with AbbVie announcing it will exercise its option on their neurodegenerative disease program, resulting in a $40 million license payment. The startup's innovative capsid technology and unique funding strategy position it to potentially transform treatments for central nervous system disorders.</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 21:05:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Vertex’s new pain drug gets first coverage nod from major insurer</title><link>https://www.biopharmadive.com/news/vertex-journavx-optum-united-health-coverage-tier-3/741850/</link><description>Optum Rx, a UnitedHealth Group subsidiary, has temporarily added Journavx to select commercial formularies as part of an interim decision pending a full review. The move signals a potential partnership opportunity while the pharmacy benefit manager evaluates the drug’s long-term inclusion.</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 22:59:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>J&amp;J Axes Late-Stage Depression Trial After Underwhelming Efficacy</title><link>https://www.biospace.com/drug-development/j-j-axes-late-stage-depression-trial-after-underwhelming-efficacy</link><description>Despite aticaprant's Phase III setback, analysts say J&amp;J's neuroscience strategy remains intact, bolstered by its recent $14.6 billion acquisition of Intra-Cellular Therapeutics. The company’s confidence is further reinforced by the continued success of Spravato, its treatment for resistant depression, positioning it to maintain momentum in the sector.</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2025 13:46:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Novo’s Studies of GLP-1s for Addiction Limited to Ongoing Phase II</title><link>https://www.biospace.com/drug-development/novos-studies-of-glp-1s-for-addiction-limited-to-ongoing-phase-ii</link><description>Novo Nordisk clarified it has no additional clinical trials exploring GLP-1 drugs for addiction beyond a Phase II study testing semaglutide and two other medications, despite recent speculation. The trial, which includes alcohol use disorder as a secondary endpoint, remains the sole focus for potential substance use applications, following a company official’s earlier comments.</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2025 14:29:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>J&amp;J scraps depression testing for potential blockbuster drug</title><link>https://www.biopharmadive.com/news/johnson-depression-studies-discontinue-aticaprant-neumora/741922/</link><description>A recent decision has dealt a "big blow" to a promising class of brain therapies, including Johnson &amp; Johnson’s experimental drug aticaprant and Neumora Therapeutics’ candidate, casting uncertainty over their development. While the article highlights setbacks for these specific treatments, it does not mention any new business deals, partnerships, or acquisitions related to the companies involved.</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2025 17:08:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Virtual physical therapy startup Hinge Health files to go public</title><link>https://endpts.com/virtual-physical-therapy-startup-hinge-health-files-to-go-public/</link><description>Hinge Health, a virtual physical therapy startup focused on treating musculoskeletal issues and chronic pain through remote software, has filed for an IPO, ending a lull in digital health public offerings. The company aims to list on a stock exchange, marking a potential resurgence in investor confidence for the telehealth sector.</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 04:00:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Sacklers to pay up to $7bn in Purdue Pharma’s opioid settlement plan</title><link>https://www.pharmaceutical-technology.com/news/sacklers-to-pay-up-to-7bn-in-purdue-pharmas-opioid-settlement-plan/</link><description>Purdue Pharma has unveiled a new bankruptcy plan detailing the payment structure for the largest opioid settlement in history. This plan aims to resolve claims against the company and provide financial support for addiction treatment and prevention efforts.</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 11:41:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Gantenerumab 'shows sign of preventing Alzheimer's dementia'</title><link>https://pharmaphorum.com/news/gantenerumab-shows-sign-preventing-alzheimers-dementia</link><description>A new study indicates that early intervention targeting amyloid in the brains of individuals with inherited Alzheimer's may postpone the onset of symptoms. However, skepticism remains among some experts regarding the efficacy of this approach.</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2025 11:13:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Roche’s discontinued Alzheimer’s drug shows signs of preventing onset</title><link>https://www.pharmaceutical-technology.com/news/roche-alzheimer-drug-could-prevent-onset/</link><description>A recent OLE study revealed that Roche's gantenerumab significantly reduced the risk of developing Alzheimer's symptoms by 50%. This promising result could lead to advancements in treatment options for those at risk of the disease.</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2025 11:43:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Synchron, Nvidia showcase AI for brain-computer interfaces</title><link>https://pharmaphorum.com/news/synchron-nvidia-showcase-ai-brain-computer-interfaces</link><description>Brain-computer interface specialist Synchron has unveiled a cutting-edge AI model that promises to drive the next generation of its innovative devices. This development marks a significant advancement in the field, potentially enhancing the interaction between technology and the human brain.</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2025 14:06:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>SV Health Investors nabs $250M to fund dementia-focused biotechs</title><link>https://endpts.com/sv-health-investors-nabs-250m-to-fund-dementia-focused-biotechs/</link><description>SV Health Investors has raised an additional $250 million for its Dementia Discovery Fund 2 to advance the search for new therapeutics targeting dementia, Alzheimer's, and other neurodegenerative diseases. This funding boosts their commitment to addressing these critical health challenges.</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2025 17:15:35 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>