<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>CNS</title><link>https://nrouizem.github.io/test/cns_feed.xml</link><description>Daily curated &amp; summarized biopharma news.</description><atom:link href="https://nrouizem.github.io/test/cns_feed.xml" rel="self"/><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2025 01:17:21 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>How atogepant trials are capturing migraine’s real-world impact</title><link>https://www.drugdiscoverytrends.com/how-atogepant-trials-are-capturing-migraines-real-world-impact/</link><description>Recent studies on atogepant have revealed the complexities of migraines, highlighting how clinical trials often fail to capture the dynamic, lived experiences of patients. These findings pave the way for more effective treatments by considering the unpredictable nature of migraines.</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2025 01:30:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>How Capsida’s unconventional funding strategy and capsid technology promise to reshape CNS treatments</title><link>https://www.drugdiscoverytrends.com/how-capsidas-unconventional-funding-strategy-and-capsid-technology-promise-to-reshape-cns-treatments/</link><description>Capsida Biotherapeutics has announced that AbbVie will exercise its option on their neurodegenerative disease program, triggering a $40 million license payment, solidifying Capsida's position in the biotech landscape. The startup has successfully utilized partnerships with Big Pharma to fund its innovative approach to central nervous system treatments.</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 21:05:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>A B-vitamin rescues Parkinson-like damage in flies, pointing to new neuroprotective strategy</title><link>https://www.drugdiscoverytrends.com/a-b-vitamin-rescues-parkinson-like-damage-in-flies-pointing-to-new-neuroprotective-strategy/</link><description>A recent study published in Science Signaling reveals that biotin (vitamin B7) may serve as a neuroprotective agent against manganese-induced neurotoxicity associated with Parkinson's disease, as evidenced by experiments conducted on fruit fly models and human dopaminergic neurons. By demonstrating that biotin supplementation can reverse neurologic damage from excessive manganese exposure, the findings point to a promising new strategy for neuroprotection.</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2025 02:10:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Vertex’s new pain drug gets first coverage nod from major insurer</title><link>https://www.biopharmadive.com/news/vertex-journavx-optum-united-health-coverage-tier-3/741850/</link><description>Optum Rx, a UnitedHealth Group subsidiary, has temporarily added Journavx to select commercial formularies as part of an interim decision pending a full review. The move signals a potential partnership opportunity while the pharmacy benefit manager evaluates the drug’s long-term inclusion.</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 22:59:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>J&amp;J Axes Late-Stage Depression Trial After Underwhelming Efficacy</title><link>https://www.biospace.com/drug-development/j-j-axes-late-stage-depression-trial-after-underwhelming-efficacy</link><description>Despite aticaprant's Phase III setback, analysts say J&amp;J's neuroscience strategy remains intact, bolstered by its recent $14.6 billion acquisition of Intra-Cellular Therapeutics. The company’s confidence is further reinforced by the continued success of Spravato, its treatment for resistant depression, positioning it to maintain momentum in the sector.</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2025 13:46:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>J&amp;J scraps depression testing for potential blockbuster drug</title><link>https://www.biopharmadive.com/news/johnson-depression-studies-discontinue-aticaprant-neumora/741922/</link><description>A recent decision has dealt a "big blow" to a promising class of brain therapies, including Johnson &amp; Johnson’s experimental drug aticaprant and Neumora Therapeutics’ candidate, casting uncertainty over their development. While the article highlights setbacks for these specific treatments, it does not mention any new business deals, partnerships, or acquisitions related to the companies involved.</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2025 17:08:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Virtual physical therapy startup Hinge Health files to go public</title><link>https://endpts.com/virtual-physical-therapy-startup-hinge-health-files-to-go-public/</link><description>Hinge Health, a virtual physical therapy startup focused on treating musculoskeletal issues and chronic pain through remote software, has filed for an IPO, ending a lull in digital health public offerings. The company aims to list on a stock exchange, marking a potential resurgence in investor confidence for the telehealth sector.</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 04:00:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Montara Therapeutics adds $20M to seed fundraise for neurology pipeline</title><link>https://endpts.com/montara-therapeutics-adds-20m-to-seed-fundraise-for-neurology-pipeline/</link><description>Montara Therapeutics has secured $20 million in expanded seed financing to further develop its preclinical CNS candidates, aiming to tackle safety issues that have hindered research and development in the field. This funding will support the company's efforts to advance innovative solutions in central nervous system therapies.</description><pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2025 12:00:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>MeiraGTx partners with cryptic AI startup Hologen to advance Parkinson's gene therapy</title><link>https://endpts.com/meiragtx-partners-with-cryptic-ai-startup-hologen-to-advance-parkinsons-gene-therapy/</link><description>A small-cap biotech is spinning out its Parkinson’s disease program into a new company in partnership with an AI startup co-founded by former Google CEO Eric Schmidt. This strategic move aims to enhance the development of gene therapies through innovative technology.</description><pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2025 15:32:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>MeiraGTx spins Parkinson’s, obesity gene therapies into AI startup</title><link>https://www.biopharmadive.com/news/meiragtx-ai-hologen-neuro-gene-therapy-parkinsons-obesity/742452/</link><description>MeiraGTx has entered into a joint venture with generative AI firm Hologen, securing an upfront payment of $200 million along with additional financial benefits. The company's CEO described the deal as "transformative" for MeiraGTx.</description><pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2025 16:05:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>