<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>CNS</title><link>https://nrouizem.github.io/test/cns_feed.xml</link><description>Daily curated &amp; summarized biopharma news.</description><atom:link href="https://nrouizem.github.io/test/cns_feed.xml" rel="self"/><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2025 01:20:31 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>How Capsida’s unconventional funding strategy and capsid technology promise to reshape CNS treatments</title><link>https://www.drugdiscoverytrends.com/how-capsidas-unconventional-funding-strategy-and-capsid-technology-promise-to-reshape-cns-treatments/</link><description>Capsida Biotherapeutics has announced that AbbVie will exercise its option on their first neurodegenerative disease program, resulting in a $40 million license payment for the startup. This partnership highlights Capsida's successful unconventional funding strategy, leveraging collaborations with Big Pharma to advance its innovative capsid technology for CNS treatments.</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 21:05:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>A B-vitamin rescues Parkinson-like damage in flies, pointing to new neuroprotective strategy</title><link>https://www.drugdiscoverytrends.com/a-b-vitamin-rescues-parkinson-like-damage-in-flies-pointing-to-new-neuroprotective-strategy/</link><description>A recent study published in Science Signaling reveals that biotin (vitamin B7) can serve as a neuroprotective agent against manganese-induced neurotoxicity associated with Parkinson's disease, using fruit fly models and human dopaminergic neurons. The findings suggest that biotin supplementation has the potential to reverse neurological damage from excessive manganese exposure.</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2025 02:10:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>J&amp;J Axes Late-Stage Depression Trial After Underwhelming Efficacy</title><link>https://www.biospace.com/drug-development/j-j-axes-late-stage-depression-trial-after-underwhelming-efficacy</link><description>Despite aticaprant's Phase III setback, analysts say J&amp;J's neuroscience strategy remains intact, bolstered by its recent $14.6 billion acquisition of Intra-Cellular Therapeutics. The company’s confidence is further reinforced by the continued success of Spravato, its treatment for resistant depression, positioning it to maintain momentum in the sector.</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2025 13:46:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>J&amp;J scraps depression testing for potential blockbuster drug</title><link>https://www.biopharmadive.com/news/johnson-depression-studies-discontinue-aticaprant-neumora/741922/</link><description>A recent decision has dealt a "big blow" to a promising class of brain therapies, including Johnson &amp; Johnson’s experimental drug aticaprant and Neumora Therapeutics’ candidate, casting uncertainty over their development. While the article highlights setbacks for these specific treatments, it does not mention any new business deals, partnerships, or acquisitions related to the companies involved.</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2025 17:08:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Montara Therapeutics adds $20M to seed fundraise for neurology pipeline</title><link>https://endpts.com/montara-therapeutics-adds-20m-to-seed-fundraise-for-neurology-pipeline/</link><description>Montara Therapeutics has secured $20 million in expanded seed financing to advance its preclinical CNS drug candidates, aiming to tackle safety concerns that have historically impeded research and development. This funding will help propel their innovative pipeline towards potential breakthroughs in central nervous system treatments.</description><pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2025 12:00:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>MeiraGTx partners with cryptic AI startup Hologen to advance Parkinson's gene therapy</title><link>https://endpts.com/meiragtx-partners-with-cryptic-ai-startup-hologen-to-advance-parkinsons-gene-therapy/</link><description>MeiraGTx is spinning out its Parkinson’s disease program into a new company in collaboration with a secretive AI startup co-founded by former Google CEO Eric Schmidt. This strategic move aims to enhance the development of innovative gene therapies for treating Parkinson's disease.</description><pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2025 15:32:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EC approves Otsuka and Lundbeck’s Rxulti for schizophrenia</title><link>https://www.pharmaceutical-technology.com/news/ec-otsuka-lundbeck-rxulti/</link><description>The European Commission has granted approval to Otsuka Pharmaceutical and Lundbeck for their atypical oral antipsychotic, Rxulti (brexpiprazole), specifically for the treatment of schizophrenia. This decision marks a significant advancement in mental health treatment options for patients experiencing this condition.</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2025 10:42:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>MeiraGTx and Hologen launch AI-backed gene therapy venture</title><link>https://www.pharmaceutical-technology.com/news/meiragtx-and-hologen-launch-ai-backed-gene-therapy-venture/</link><description>MeiraGTx is set to advance its Parkinson's gene therapy into Phase III trials, backed by up to $430 million in funding from Hologen. This investment signifies a significant boost for MeiraGTx's efforts in developing innovative treatments for the disease.</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2025 11:27:54 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>