<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>CNS</title><link>https://nrouizem.github.io/test/cns_feed.xml</link><description>Daily curated &amp; summarized biopharma news.</description><atom:link href="https://nrouizem.github.io/test/cns_feed.xml" rel="self"/><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 01:19:02 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>How Capsida’s unconventional funding strategy and capsid technology promise to reshape CNS treatments</title><link>https://www.drugdiscoverytrends.com/how-capsidas-unconventional-funding-strategy-and-capsid-technology-promise-to-reshape-cns-treatments/</link><description>Capsida Biotherapeutics has garnered significant funding through its partnerships with major pharmaceutical companies, culminating in AbbVie exercising its option on their neurodegenerative disease program for a $40 million license payment. This unique approach and innovative capsid technology position the startup to potentially revolutionize treatments for central nervous system disorders.</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 21:05:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>A B-vitamin rescues Parkinson-like damage in flies, pointing to new neuroprotective strategy</title><link>https://www.drugdiscoverytrends.com/a-b-vitamin-rescues-parkinson-like-damage-in-flies-pointing-to-new-neuroprotective-strategy/</link><description>A recent study highlighted in Science Signaling reveals that biotin (vitamin B7) may serve as a neuroprotective agent against manganese-induced neurotoxicity associated with Parkinson's disease. Using fruit fly models and human dopaminergic neurons, researchers demonstrated that biotin supplementation can reverse neurological damage caused by excessive manganese exposure.</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2025 02:10:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Vertex’s new pain drug gets first coverage nod from major insurer</title><link>https://www.biopharmadive.com/news/vertex-journavx-optum-united-health-coverage-tier-3/741850/</link><description>Optum Rx, a UnitedHealth Group subsidiary, has temporarily added Journavx to select commercial formularies as part of an interim decision pending a full review. The move signals a potential partnership opportunity while the pharmacy benefit manager evaluates the drug’s long-term inclusion.</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 22:59:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>J&amp;J Axes Late-Stage Depression Trial After Underwhelming Efficacy</title><link>https://www.biospace.com/drug-development/j-j-axes-late-stage-depression-trial-after-underwhelming-efficacy</link><description>Despite aticaprant's Phase III setback, analysts say J&amp;J's neuroscience strategy remains intact, bolstered by its recent $14.6 billion acquisition of Intra-Cellular Therapeutics. The company’s confidence is further reinforced by the continued success of Spravato, its treatment for resistant depression, positioning it to maintain momentum in the sector.</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2025 13:46:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>J&amp;J scraps depression testing for potential blockbuster drug</title><link>https://www.biopharmadive.com/news/johnson-depression-studies-discontinue-aticaprant-neumora/741922/</link><description>A recent decision has dealt a "big blow" to a promising class of brain therapies, including Johnson &amp; Johnson’s experimental drug aticaprant and Neumora Therapeutics’ candidate, casting uncertainty over their development. While the article highlights setbacks for these specific treatments, it does not mention any new business deals, partnerships, or acquisitions related to the companies involved.</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2025 17:08:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Virtual physical therapy startup Hinge Health files to go public</title><link>https://endpts.com/virtual-physical-therapy-startup-hinge-health-files-to-go-public/</link><description>Hinge Health, a virtual physical therapy startup focused on treating musculoskeletal issues and chronic pain through remote software, has filed for an IPO, ending a lull in digital health public offerings. The company aims to list on a stock exchange, marking a potential resurgence in investor confidence for the telehealth sector.</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 04:00:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Latigo raises $150M to get non-opioid pain drugs through key tests</title><link>https://www.biopharmadive.com/news/latigo-series-b-pain-non-opioid-nav/742635/</link><description>The startup secured a funding round featuring over a dozen investment firms, providing it with ample resources to advance late-stage data for its leading candidate. This influx of capital positions the company for significant progress in its development efforts.</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2025 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Latigo secures $150m for non-opioid pain treatment development</title><link>https://www.pharmaceutical-technology.com/news/latigo-non-opioid-pain-treatment/</link><description>Latigo has successfully raised $150 million in a Series funding round to accelerate the development of its Nav1.8 inhibitors. This significant capital infusion will support the company's ongoing research initiatives in the pharmaceutical space.</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2025 13:54:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Vertanical’s Phase 3 win for non-opioid painkiller; Apriori lays off 40% of staff</title><link>https://endpts.com/vertanicals-phase-3-win-for-non-opioid-painkiller-apriori-lays-off-40-of-staff/</link><description>Vertanical's non-opioid painkiller achieved success in Phase 3 trials, demonstrating its efficacy in treating chronic back pain. This latest development positions the German biotech favorably within the competitive pain management market.</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2025 14:58:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Vertanical's cannabis-based painkiller hits target in trials</title><link>https://pharmaphorum.com/news/vertanicals-cannabis-based-painkiller-hits-target-trials</link><description>Vertanical's cannabis-derived drug for chronic back pain has demonstrated efficacy in phase 3 trials and is poised to enter the market soon. The successful trial results position Vertanical for potential growth in the rapidly expanding medical cannabis sector.</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 09:28:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Sofinnova closes new fund and backs a trio of new biotechs</title><link>https://pharmaphorum.com/news/sofinnova-closes-new-fund-and-backs-trio-new-biotechs</link><description>Sofinnova Partners has successfully raised €165 million for its new biotech fund, focusing on innovative solutions in healthcare. The fund has already backed three startups dedicated to addressing Alzheimer's, fibrotic diseases, and advanced cell therapies.</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 11:28:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Sofinnova’s latest biotech fund sprouts three new startups</title><link>https://www.biopharmadive.com/news/sofinnova-fund-startups-bioclec-signadori-forth/742816/</link><description>Sofinnova is investing in startups focused on developing innovative treatments for fibrosis, cancer, and Alzheimer's as part of its broader pan-European strategy. This initiative aims to enhance healthcare solutions across the continent by supporting emerging companies in these critical therapeutic areas.</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 15:50:25 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>