<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>CNS</title><link>https://nrouizem.github.io/test/cns_feed.xml</link><description>Daily curated &amp; summarized biopharma news.</description><atom:link href="https://nrouizem.github.io/test/cns_feed.xml" rel="self"/><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 01:18:21 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>How Capsida’s unconventional funding strategy and capsid technology promise to reshape CNS treatments</title><link>https://www.drugdiscoverytrends.com/how-capsidas-unconventional-funding-strategy-and-capsid-technology-promise-to-reshape-cns-treatments/</link><description>Capsida Biotherapeutics has secured a significant $40 million license payment from AbbVie as the pharmaceutical giant exercises its option on their first neurodegenerative disease program. The gene therapy startup has primarily built its funding through strategic partnerships with major pharmaceutical companies, positioning itself to reshape treatments for central nervous system disorders.</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 21:05:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>A B-vitamin rescues Parkinson-like damage in flies, pointing to new neuroprotective strategy</title><link>https://www.drugdiscoverytrends.com/a-b-vitamin-rescues-parkinson-like-damage-in-flies-pointing-to-new-neuroprotective-strategy/</link><description>A recent study published in Science Signaling suggests that biotin (vitamin B7) may serve as a neuroprotective agent against manganese-induced neurotoxicity associated with Parkinson's disease. Utilizing fruit fly models and human dopaminergic neurons, researchers found that biotin supplementation could reverse neurological damage caused by excessive manganese exposure.</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2025 02:10:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>J&amp;J Axes Late-Stage Depression Trial After Underwhelming Efficacy</title><link>https://www.biospace.com/drug-development/j-j-axes-late-stage-depression-trial-after-underwhelming-efficacy</link><description>Despite aticaprant's Phase III setback, analysts say J&amp;J's neuroscience strategy remains intact, bolstered by its recent $14.6 billion acquisition of Intra-Cellular Therapeutics. The company’s confidence is further reinforced by the continued success of Spravato, its treatment for resistant depression, positioning it to maintain momentum in the sector.</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2025 13:46:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>J&amp;J scraps depression testing for potential blockbuster drug</title><link>https://www.biopharmadive.com/news/johnson-depression-studies-discontinue-aticaprant-neumora/741922/</link><description>A recent decision has dealt a "big blow" to a promising class of brain therapies, including Johnson &amp; Johnson’s experimental drug aticaprant and Neumora Therapeutics’ candidate, casting uncertainty over their development. While the article highlights setbacks for these specific treatments, it does not mention any new business deals, partnerships, or acquisitions related to the companies involved.</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2025 17:08:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>