<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>CNS</title><link>https://nrouizem.github.io/test/cns_feed.xml</link><description>Daily curated &amp; summarized biopharma news.</description><atom:link href="https://nrouizem.github.io/test/cns_feed.xml" rel="self"/><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2025 01:22:30 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Vertex’s new pain drug gets first coverage nod from major insurer</title><link>https://www.biopharmadive.com/news/vertex-journavx-optum-united-health-coverage-tier-3/741850/</link><description>Optum Rx, a UnitedHealth Group subsidiary, has temporarily added Journavx to select commercial formularies as part of an interim decision pending a full review. The move signals a potential partnership opportunity while the pharmacy benefit manager evaluates the drug’s long-term inclusion.</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 22:59:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>J&amp;J Axes Late-Stage Depression Trial After Underwhelming Efficacy</title><link>https://www.biospace.com/drug-development/j-j-axes-late-stage-depression-trial-after-underwhelming-efficacy</link><description>Despite aticaprant's Phase III setback, analysts say J&amp;J's neuroscience strategy remains intact, bolstered by its recent $14.6 billion acquisition of Intra-Cellular Therapeutics. The company’s confidence is further reinforced by the continued success of Spravato, its treatment for resistant depression, positioning it to maintain momentum in the sector.</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2025 13:46:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>At $300M Kardigan startup, former MyoKardia team unveils its first drug, and it comes from Ionis</title><link>https://endpts.com/at-300m-kardigan-startup-former-myokardia-team-unveils-its-first-drug-and-it-comes-from-ionis/</link><description>Former MyoKardia executives launched a heart health biotech startup with $300 million in funding, leveraging undisclosed partnerships to secure in-licensed clinical-stage assets for cardiac therapies. The stealth-mode company remains tight-lipped about specific deals but signals a focus on advancing innovative treatments, attracting attention for its seasoned leadership and strategic collaborations.</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2025 16:16:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>J&amp;J scraps depression testing for potential blockbuster drug</title><link>https://www.biopharmadive.com/news/johnson-depression-studies-discontinue-aticaprant-neumora/741922/</link><description>A recent decision has dealt a "big blow" to a promising class of brain therapies, including Johnson &amp; Johnson’s experimental drug aticaprant and Neumora Therapeutics’ candidate, casting uncertainty over their development. While the article highlights setbacks for these specific treatments, it does not mention any new business deals, partnerships, or acquisitions related to the companies involved.</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2025 17:08:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Virtual physical therapy startup Hinge Health files to go public</title><link>https://endpts.com/virtual-physical-therapy-startup-hinge-health-files-to-go-public/</link><description>Hinge Health, a virtual physical therapy startup focused on treating musculoskeletal issues and chronic pain through remote software, has filed for an IPO, ending a lull in digital health public offerings. The company aims to list on a stock exchange, marking a potential resurgence in investor confidence for the telehealth sector.</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 04:00:11 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>