<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>CNS</title><link>https://nrouizem.github.io/test/cns_feed.xml</link><description>Daily curated &amp; summarized biopharma news.</description><atom:link href="https://nrouizem.github.io/test/cns_feed.xml" rel="self"/><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Mar 2025 01:17:43 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>The FDA Fast-Tracked GNSC-001 gene therapy targets osteoarthritis at its root</title><link>https://www.drugdiscoverytrends.com/the-fda-fast-tracked-gnsc-001-gene-therapy-targets-osteoarthritis-at-its-root/</link><description>The FDA has fast-tracked GNSC-001, a gene therapy aimed at addressing the root causes of osteoarthritis, a condition impacting over 30 million Americans and costing the healthcare system nearly $460 billion annually. This innovative treatment represents a significant advancement in the quest for effective osteoarthritis therapies.</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2025 19:16:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>J&amp;J Axes Late-Stage Depression Trial After Underwhelming Efficacy</title><link>https://www.biospace.com/drug-development/j-j-axes-late-stage-depression-trial-after-underwhelming-efficacy</link><description>Despite aticaprant's Phase III setback, analysts say J&amp;J's neuroscience strategy remains intact, bolstered by its recent $14.6 billion acquisition of Intra-Cellular Therapeutics. The company’s confidence is further reinforced by the continued success of Spravato, its treatment for resistant depression, positioning it to maintain momentum in the sector.</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2025 13:46:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>AstraZeneca Builds Stomach Cancer Case for Imfinzi With Strong Phase III Data</title><link>https://www.biospace.com/drug-development/astrazeneca-builds-stomach-cancer-case-for-imfinzi-with-strong-phase-iii-data</link><description>AstraZeneca's cancer drug Imfinzi is poised to drive significant growth in 2025, with regulators set to decide on its expanded use in treating stomach and bladder cancers. The blockbuster therapy generated over $4.7 billion in sales last year, cementing its role as a key revenue driver for the pharmaceutical giant.</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2025 13:58:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Roche launches new Boston center; NIH centralizes peer review</title><link>https://www.biopharmadive.com/news/roche-boston-center-nih-peer-review-pfizer-james-list/741901/</link><description>Swiss pharma giant Novartis announced plans to centralize its cardiometabolic drug research at a new Allston, Massachusetts, hub, signaling a strategic focus on heart and metabolic disease innovation. Meanwhile, AskBio progressed a mid-phase gene therapy trial, and Pfizer tapped a GLP-1 expert, intensifying competition in the weight-loss and diabetes therapeutics race.</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2025 16:20:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>J&amp;J scraps depression testing for potential blockbuster drug</title><link>https://www.biopharmadive.com/news/johnson-depression-studies-discontinue-aticaprant-neumora/741922/</link><description>A recent decision has dealt a "big blow" to a promising class of brain therapies, including Johnson &amp; Johnson’s experimental drug aticaprant and Neumora Therapeutics’ candidate, casting uncertainty over their development. While the article highlights setbacks for these specific treatments, it does not mention any new business deals, partnerships, or acquisitions related to the companies involved.</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2025 17:08:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>How bluebird's buyout offer went from $100M upfront to $29M</title><link>https://endpts.com/how-bluebirds-buyout-offer-went-from-100m-upfront-to-29m/</link><description>Bluebird bio, once a gene therapy darling valued at $10 billion in 2018, was sold last month for just $29 million upfront in a fire sale, marking a dramatic fall amid sector struggles. The article hints at further challenges, noting “it almost…” but leaves the story unfinished, suggesting deeper turmoil or near-catastrophe in its trajectory.</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2025 18:25:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>FDA approves Neurotech therapy for rare eye disease</title><link>https://endpts.com/fda-approves-neurotech-therapy-for-rare-eye-disease/</link><description>The FDA approved Neurotech Pharmaceuticals’ first-of-its-kind cell therapy for macular telangiectasia type 2, a rare eye disease causing progressive central vision loss, marking a major advancement for patients with no prior treatment options. The therapy, which implants cells to repair retinal damage, could transform care for the condition, though the article does not mention specific business deals or partnerships related to its development.</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2025 19:57:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>J&amp;J’s Oral IL-23R Blocker Sets New Standard in Plaque Psoriasis, Beating BMS’ Sotyktu</title><link>https://www.biospace.com/drug-development/j-js-oral-il-23r-blocker-sets-new-standard-in-plaque-psoriasis-beating-bmss-sotyktu</link><description>New late-stage trial data reveals Johnson &amp; Johnson’s psoriasis drug icotrokinra outperformed Bristol Myers Squibb’s Sotyktu in clearing skin and reducing symptom severity for patients with plaque psoriasis. The findings could intensify competition in the dermatology treatment market, positioning J&amp;J’s therapy as a potential challenger in this therapeutic area.</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 14:03:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Arrowhead reveals small batch of open-label data for 'non-core' kidney drug</title><link>https://endpts.com/arrowhead-reveals-small-batch-of-open-label-data-for-non-core-kidney-drug/</link><description>Arrowhead Pharmaceuticals unveiled promising new open-label data from its ARO-C3 RNAi therapy program, showing potential to improve kidney disease outcomes by targeting complement pathways in a small study involving about a dozen patients. The early-stage results highlight the therapy's novel approach to addressing kidney disorders, though no partnerships or business deals related to the program were disclosed.</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 15:07:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mineralys shares climb on study data for blood pressure drug</title><link>https://www.biopharmadive.com/news/mineralys-lorundrostat-hypertension-study-results/742000/</link><description>New studies on Mineralys' hypertension treatment have validated the drug as a promising near-commercial product, with analysts hailing it as a "derisked, almost-commercial stage cardiometabolic asset." While no specific deals or partnerships were mentioned, the data bolsters the therapy’s market potential and positions it for future commercial opportunities.</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 15:30:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mineralys’ Hypertension Drug Drops Blood Pressure in Phase II/III, Setting Up Market Clash</title><link>https://www.biospace.com/drug-development/mineralys-hypertension-drug-drops-blood-pressure-in-phase-ii-iii-setting-up-market-clash</link><description>Mineralys Therapeutics saw its stock surge over 50% after announcing successful Phase 2 trial results for its hypertension drug, which significantly reduced blood pressure in patients across two clinical studies. The promising data positions the therapy as a potential leader in the $30 billion hypertension market, heightening investor interest in the company’s future regulatory and commercial plans.</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 16:11:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Beam shares promising first clinical data on gene editing treatment</title><link>https://endpts.com/beam-shares-promising-first-clinical-data-on-gene-editing-treatment/</link><description>Beam Therapeutics' experimental gene-editing therapy demonstrated promising results in a small trial, reducing mutant proteins linked to lung-damaging alpha-1 antitrypsin deficiency and boosting corrected protein levels in nine participants. The early data underscores the treatment's potential as a one-time fix for the genetic disorder, though the article does not mention any business deals, partnerships, or mergers.</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 16:42:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Novo’s Wegovy successor disappoints in second large trial</title><link>https://www.biopharmadive.com/news/novo-nordisk-cagrisema-study-results-diabetes-weight-loss/742008/</link><description>A recent study found that CagriSema, a weight-loss therapy for individuals with obesity and diabetes, demonstrated effectiveness in aiding weight loss but fell short of outperforming Eli Lilly’s rival drug Zepbound. While the results highlight CagriSema’s potential, they solidify Zepbound’s competitive edge in the burgeoning metabolic treatment market.</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 17:17:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Beam base editing therapy gets ‘proof of concept’ in rare lung disease</title><link>https://www.biopharmadive.com/news/beam-aatd-base-editing-initial-data-results-302/742015/</link><description>Beam Therapeutics' shares dropped sharply despite promising early study results showing its gene-editing technology could address the genetic cause of alpha-1 antitrypsin deficiency. The stock decline highlights investor concerns even as the company advances its innovative treatment potential.</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 17:25:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Virtual physical therapy startup Hinge Health files to go public</title><link>https://endpts.com/virtual-physical-therapy-startup-hinge-health-files-to-go-public/</link><description>Hinge Health, a virtual physical therapy startup focused on treating musculoskeletal issues and chronic pain through remote software, has filed for an IPO, ending a lull in digital health public offerings. The company aims to list on a stock exchange, marking a potential resurgence in investor confidence for the telehealth sector.</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 04:00:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bristol Myers buys out cell therapy partner 2seventy bio</title><link>https://endpts.com/bristol-myers-buys-out-cell-therapy-partner-2seventy-bio/</link><description>Bristol Myers Squibb has agreed to acquire 2seventy bio, its longtime partner in developing the CAR-T cell therapy Abecma for multiple myeloma, in a $286 million all-cash deal. The acquisition strengthens Bristol Myers' foothold in cancer therapies, building on the companies' existing collaboration aimed at advancing cutting-edge immunocellular treatments.</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 08:13:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Beam’s Gene Editor Achieves ‘First Ever’ Genetic Correction in AATD</title><link>https://www.biospace.com/drug-development/beams-gene-editor-achieves-first-ever-genetic-correction-in-aatd</link><description>William Blair analysts highlighted BEAM-302 as a breakthrough therapy, praising its superior efficacy in its sector in a recent investor note. While the report emphasized the drug's potential to redefine treatment standards, it did not mention any specific business deals, partnerships, or acquisitions related to the product.</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 13:52:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>2seventy bio, Bluebird’s cell therapy spinout, sells to Bristol Myers for less than $300M</title><link>https://www.biopharmadive.com/news/2seventy-bio-bristol-myers-deal-abecma-bluebird/742142/</link><description>2Seventy Bio's recent acquisition has terminated its brief stint as an independent firm, marking the end of a turbulent period marked by strategic restructuring and asset sales. The company, which shed research segments and saw its market value plummet by nearly 100%, now shifts focus under new ownership amid financial struggles.</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 16:05:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Arvinas gets positive breast cancer data, but finds differentiation a hard sell</title><link>https://www.biopharmadive.com/news/arvinas-pfizer-vepdegestrant-breast-cancer-data-veritac/742135/</link><description>Arvinas and Pfizer's partnered breast cancer drug, vepdegestrant, showed promising results in a specific patient subgroup compared to fulvestrant, though it didn't meet overall trial goals. The mixed outcomes highlight the experimental therapy's potential niche benefits while underscoring the challenges of broad efficacy in cancer treatment.</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 16:45:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Viking inks CordenPharma deal to boost obesity drug supply</title><link>https://www.biopharmadive.com/news/viking-cordenpharma-obesity-drug-manufacturing-deal/742139/</link><description>A biotech firm is investing $150 million in a strategic alliance to secure expanded production capacity for a high-profile weight-loss therapy, positioning itself to meet soaring demand. The partnership underscores the company’s aggressive push to capitalize on the competitive but rapidly growing market for obesity treatments.</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 17:25:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Agenus CMO touts immunotherapy advances on The Top Line</title><link>https://www.fiercebiotech.com/sponsored/agenus-cmo-touts-immunotherapy-advances-top-line</link><description>Agenus Chief Medical Officer highlighted significant advancements in immunotherapy during a recent discussion on The Top Line, emphasizing the company's commitment to innovative cancer treatments. The conversation underscored Agenus's strategic focus on enhancing patient outcomes through its developing therapies and ongoing research.</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 17:26:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Advancing the Future of Biomarker-Driven Immunotherapy</title><link>https://www.fiercebiotech.com/premium/webinar/1369042</link><description>An upcoming webinar will delve into the DUTRENEO trial's findings on the use of spatial biomarkers to enhance patient stratification for immunotherapy in muscle-invasive bladder cancer. The session will highlight transformative multi-omics approaches that aim to improve therapeutic selection by addressing challenges in predictive biomarkers.</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2025 17:43:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Sarepta Shares Crash 22% After Patient on DMD Gene Therapy Elevidys Dies</title><link>https://www.biospace.com/drug-development/sarepta-shares-crash-22-after-patient-on-dmd-gene-therapy-elevidys-dies</link><description>Sarepta Therapeutics is updating the label for its Duchenne muscular dystrophy gene therapy, Elevydis, following a patient's death attributed to liver injury. The decision aims to enhance safety awareness surrounding the treatment.</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 14:00:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Novartis’ Intrathecal Zolgensma Effective in Older Children</title><link>https://www.biospace.com/drug-development/Novartis-intrathecal-zolgensma-effective-in-older-children</link><description>Novartis is launching an intrathecal formulation of Zolgensma, targeting older patients affected by spinal muscular atrophy, following its initial market debut in 2019 as the first gene therapy for the condition. This new formulation aims to expand treatment options and improve patient outcomes in a previously underserved population.</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 20:32:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>In Wake of Elevidys Death, Duchenne Patient Community Vows to Push On</title><link>https://www.biospace.com/drug-development/in-wake-of-elevydis-death-duchenne-patient-community-vows-to-push-on</link><description>Sarepta faced scrutiny following the death of a patient who had received its gene therapy Elevidys, prompting a strong response from the advocacy group Parent Project Muscular Dystrophy. The group's involvement highlights ongoing concerns regarding the safety and efficacy of experimental treatments in the field of muscular dystrophy.</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2025 13:25:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Servier and Black Diamond sign deal for solid tumours therapy</title><link>https://www.pharmaceutical-technology.com/news/servier-black-diamond-deal/</link><description>Servier has entered into a licensing agreement with Black Diamond Therapeutics for BDTX-4933, a targeted therapy designed to combat solid tumors. This partnership highlights both companies' commitment to advancing innovative cancer treatments.</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2025 13:42:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Novartis builds case for new SMA gene therapy</title><link>https://www.biopharmadive.com/news/novartis-oav101-sma-gene-therapy-results-filing/743087/</link><description>Novartis reported promising late-stage data suggesting that its intrathecal drug, sharing the active ingredient of the gene therapy Zolgensma, may gain approval for a wider array of spinal muscular atrophy patients. This development could significantly enhance treatment options for those affected by the condition.</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2025 16:26:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>SV Health Investors nabs $250M to fund dementia-focused biotechs</title><link>https://endpts.com/sv-health-investors-nabs-250m-to-fund-dementia-focused-biotechs/</link><description>SV Health Investors has successfully raised $250 million for its Dementia Discovery Fund 2, aimed at advancing new therapeutics for dementia, Alzheimer's, and other neurodegenerative diseases. This significant funding boost underscores the investor's commitment to addressing critical challenges in neuroscience and improving patient outcomes.</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2025 17:15:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fabhalta is first FDA-approved therapy for rare disease C3G</title><link>https://pharmaphorum.com/news/fabhalta-first-fda-approved-therapy-rare-disease-c3g</link><description>Novartis' oral complement inhibitor Fabhalta has received approval as the first treatment for the rare kidney disease C3G, marking a significant advancement in addressing this condition. The company aims to achieve a $3 billion sales target, highlighting the drug's commercial potential.</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 12:21:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>China conditionally approves Hutchmed’s Tazverik for follicular lymphoma</title><link>https://www.pharmaceutical-technology.com/news/china-hutchmed-tazverik-fl/</link><description>Hutchmed's Tazverik has received conditional approval from the NMPA for the treatment of adults with relapsed or refractory follicular lymphoma. This milestone marks a significant advancement in cancer therapy options for patients in this demographic.</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 14:07:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The buildup to Chimerix's $935M cash exit to Jazz</title><link>https://endpts.com/the-buildup-to-chimerixs-935m-cash-exit-to-jazz/</link><description>Chimerix has garnered significant interest in its experimental brain tumor treatment, leading to a $935 million cash acquisition by Jazz Pharmaceuticals earlier this month. The deal underscores the growing value of innovative therapies in the oncology space, as Chimerix's treatment continues to show promise.</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 16:28:15 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>