<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>CNS</title><link>https://nrouizem.github.io/test/cns_feed.xml</link><description>Daily curated &amp; summarized biopharma news.</description><atom:link href="https://nrouizem.github.io/test/cns_feed.xml" rel="self"/><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 Mar 2025 01:16:48 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>How Capsida’s unconventional funding strategy and capsid technology promise to reshape CNS treatments</title><link>https://www.drugdiscoverytrends.com/how-capsidas-unconventional-funding-strategy-and-capsid-technology-promise-to-reshape-cns-treatments/</link><description>Capsida Biotherapeutics is set to receive a $40 million license payment from AbbVie, who will exercise its option on their neurodegenerative disease program. The startup has successfully grown its funding through collaborations with major pharmaceutical companies, leveraging its innovative capsid technology to reshape Central Nervous System treatments.</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 21:05:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>J&amp;J Axes Late-Stage Depression Trial After Underwhelming Efficacy</title><link>https://www.biospace.com/drug-development/j-j-axes-late-stage-depression-trial-after-underwhelming-efficacy</link><description>Despite aticaprant's Phase III setback, analysts say J&amp;J's neuroscience strategy remains intact, bolstered by its recent $14.6 billion acquisition of Intra-Cellular Therapeutics. The company’s confidence is further reinforced by the continued success of Spravato, its treatment for resistant depression, positioning it to maintain momentum in the sector.</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2025 13:46:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>J&amp;J scraps depression testing for potential blockbuster drug</title><link>https://www.biopharmadive.com/news/johnson-depression-studies-discontinue-aticaprant-neumora/741922/</link><description>A recent decision has dealt a "big blow" to a promising class of brain therapies, including Johnson &amp; Johnson’s experimental drug aticaprant and Neumora Therapeutics’ candidate, casting uncertainty over their development. While the article highlights setbacks for these specific treatments, it does not mention any new business deals, partnerships, or acquisitions related to the companies involved.</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2025 17:08:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Amgen reports more Phase 3 Uplizna data in myasthenia gravis ahead of FDA filing</title><link>https://endpts.com/amgen-reports-more-phase-3-uplizna-data-in-myasthenia-gravis-ahead-of-fda-filing/</link><description>Amgen has released new Phase 3 data for its rare disease drug Uplizna, aimed at treating myasthenia gravis, strengthening its position for label expansion ahead of an anticipated FDA filing this quarter. The 52-week results underscore the drug's effectiveness and safety, enhancing Amgen's prospects in the neurology market.</description><pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2025 11:22:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Montara Therapeutics adds $20M to seed fundraise for neurology pipeline</title><link>https://endpts.com/montara-therapeutics-adds-20m-to-seed-fundraise-for-neurology-pipeline/</link><description>Montara Therapeutics has secured $20 million in expanded seed financing to progress its preclinical CNS candidates, aiming to tackle safety concerns that have historically hindered research and development. This funding will help the company advance its innovative approaches in the treatment of central nervous system disorders.</description><pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2025 12:00:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EC approves Otsuka and Lundbeck’s Rxulti for schizophrenia</title><link>https://www.pharmaceutical-technology.com/news/ec-otsuka-lundbeck-rxulti/</link><description>The European Commission has granted approval for Otsuka Pharmaceutical and Lundbeck’s atypical oral antipsychotic, Rxulti (brexpiprazole), for the treatment of schizophrenia. This approval marks a significant advancement in options available for managing this mental health condition.</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2025 10:42:42 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>