<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Immunology</title><link>https://nrouizem.github.io/test/immunology_feed.xml</link><description>Daily curated &amp; summarized biopharma news.</description><atom:link href="https://nrouizem.github.io/test/immunology_feed.xml" rel="self"/><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2025 01:23:24 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>How an engineered algae-based biologic aims to break the annual $5B cycle of c. diff reinfection</title><link>https://www.drugdiscoverytrends.com/how-an-engineered-algae-based-biologic-aims-to-break-the-annual-5b-cycle-of-c-diff-reinfection/</link><description>Researchers are developing an engineered algae-based biologic to combat the Clostridioides difficile superbug, which causes 29,000 deaths each year in the U.S. due to severe diarrhea and colitis. This innovation aims to address the high rates of recurrence in C. diff infections, potentially breaking the annual $5 billion cycle associated with these reinfections.</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2025 05:06:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>How 3T Biosciences’ platform targets immunologically cold solid tumors</title><link>https://www.drugdiscoverytrends.com/3t-biosciences-targeted-strategy-for-mss-colorectal-cancer/</link><description>3T Biosciences is addressing the challenge of immunotherapy resistance in solid tumors, particularly focusing on microsatellite stable colorectal cancer (MSS CRC), which shows over 90% non-responsiveness to checkpoint inhibitors. Their innovative platform aims to enhance treatment efficacy for these immunologically cold solid tumors, promising a potential breakthrough in oncology.</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 05:12:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Avoiding aggregates: How new technology is helping mAb developers monitor a vital CQA</title><link>https://www.drugdiscoverytrends.com/avoiding-aggregates-how-new-technology-is-helping-mab-developers-monitor-a-vital-cqa/</link><description>The monoclonal antibodies (mAbs) market, currently valued over $330 billion, is projected to more than double by 2030, despite developers facing challenges in maintaining critical quality attributes (CQAs). Innovations in technology are emerging to help mAb developers effectively monitor and avoid aggregates, a vital CQA in the research pipeline.</description><pubDate>Sat, 08 Feb 2025 19:54:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Rosnilimab phase 2b trial shows promise in treating RA</title><link>https://www.drugdiscoverytrends.com/rosnilimab-phase-2b-trial-shows-promise-in-treating-ra/</link><description>A phase 2b trial of rosnilimab has shown promising results in treating rheumatoid arthritis (RA) by targeting the PD-1 pathway to potentially reset the immune system. Unlike existing therapies that often fail to provide long-term remission, rosnilimab aims to offer a more effective solution for patients struggling with the complex disease.</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2025 14:07:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Redefining vaccine trial recruitment</title><link>https://www.fiercebiotech.com/resource/redefining-vaccine-trial-recruitment</link><description>Avacare Clinical Research Network's new white paper highlights innovative, data-driven strategies to tackle recruitment challenges and boost diversity in vaccine trials, ensuring more efficient and representative study outcomes. Sponsored by Avacare, the resource offers actionable insights for optimizing trial design and participant engagement through cutting-edge approaches.</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2025 14:26:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Solutions for CAR-Engineered Cell Characterization</title><link>https://www.fiercebiotech.com/resource/solutions-car-engineered-cell-characterization</link><description>Cell Signaling Technology (CST) has unveiled purpose-built tools, including recombinant antibodies targeting scFv linkers like G4S and Whitlow/218, to accelerate CAR-engineered cell characterization and development. The solutions aim to bypass the costly, time-intensive process of anti-idiotype antibody creation while streamlining workflows for researchers.</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2025 14:49:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Accelerating and Enabling Consistency of Bioprocessing Scale-up</title><link>https://www.fiercebiotech.com/premium/webinar/1368685</link><description>Discover how to streamline bioprocessing scale-up for monoclonal antibody (mAb) production through media optimization, High-Intensity Perfusion (HIP) CHO solutions, and innovative bioreactor designs in an upcoming webinar featuring experts Vivian Ott and Maren Grun. The session will delve into strategies for enhancing manufacturing efficiency, sustainability, and rapid commercialization, supported by case studies on successful process intensification and scalable technologies.</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2025 19:38:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Using Client Centricity as Fuel for Innovative Biologics Development and Manufacturing Solutions</title><link>https://www.fiercebiotech.com/resource/using-client-centricity-fuel-innovative-biologics-development-and-manufacturing-solutions</link><description>Rentschler Biopharma has released a client-centric whitepaper offering actionable insights for biopharma professionals to optimize biologics development and manufacturing while maintaining high-quality standards. The resource targets process development scientists, manufacturing leads, and executives seeking innovative strategies to streamline production without compromising on efficiency or compliance.</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Mar 2025 16:39:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Sun Pharma to acquire Checkpoint Therapeutics and its anti-PD-L1 antibody</title><link>https://endpts.com/sun-pharma-to-acquire-checkpoint-therapeutics-and-its-anti-pd-l1-antibody/</link><description>Checkpoint Therapeutics has pivoted from seeking a partnership for its newly approved cancer drug to being acquired outright by India’s Sun Pharma in a strategic immuno-oncology expansion. The deal, valued at $4.10 per share, marks a swift exit for Checkpoint and reinforces Sun Pharma’s growing footprint in cutting-edge cancer therapies.</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 12:20:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Amgen, Kyowa Kirin’s Rocatinlimab Picks Up Steam With Late-Stage Atopic Dermatitis Win</title><link>https://www.biospace.com/drug-development/amgens-rocatinlimab-picks-up-steam-with-late-stage-atopic-dermatitis-win</link><description>"September 2024 trial results for rocatinlimab, an experimental antibody, drew mixed analyst reactions due to its underwhelming efficacy in treating a targeted condition. The lukewarm data sparked debate about the drug's future potential, with some holding out hope for protocol adjustments while others questioned its market viability."</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 13:57:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Arrowhead reveals small batch of open-label data for 'non-core' kidney drug</title><link>https://endpts.com/arrowhead-reveals-small-batch-of-open-label-data-for-non-core-kidney-drug/</link><description>Arrowhead Pharmaceuticals unveiled promising new open-label data from its ARO-C3 RNAi therapy program, showing potential to improve kidney disease outcomes by targeting complement pathways in a small study involving about a dozen patients. The early-stage results highlight the therapy's novel approach to addressing kidney disorders, though no partnerships or business deals related to the program were disclosed.</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 15:07:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>J&amp;J, Protagonist outline first IBD win for potential immunological blockbuster</title><link>https://endpts.com/jj-protagonist-outline-first-ibd-win-for-potential-immunological-blockbuster/</link><description>Johnson &amp; Johnson and Protagonist Therapeutics have partnered to develop an oral IL-23 drug, aiming to create a breakthrough immunology treatment. The companies announced progress toward this goal on Monday, signaling potential advancements in bringing the blockbuster drug candidate closer to market.</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 16:04:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Emergent sells once-troubled Baltimore site to Syngene</title><link>https://endpts.com/emergent-sells-once-troubled-baltimore-site-to-syngene/</link><description>Emergent BioSolutions has sold its Baltimore manufacturing facility, previously linked to contaminated Covid-19 vaccine production, to Indian CDMO Syngene for $36.5 million, marking Syngene's first U.S. manufacturing foothold as it expands global operations. The deal underscores Syngene's strategic push into the American market while addressing Emergent's efforts to streamline its asset portfolio following past quality challenges.</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 17:17:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BioNTech's shares dip after posting lukewarm revenue guidance</title><link>https://endpts.com/biontechs-shares-dip-after-posting-lukewarm-revenue-guidance/</link><description>BioNTech shares fell 2% after projecting lower 2025 revenues, citing reduced COVID-19 vaccine demand and oversupply challenges despite a solid $4.2 billion revenue in 2023. The company plans to pivot toward advancing cancer treatments and cost-cutting measures while preparing for new vaccine launches to offset declining pandemic-related sales.</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 19:37:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The true cost of steroid-toxicity</title><link>https://www.drugdiscoverytrends.com/the-true-cost-of-steroid-toxicity/</link><description>Glucocorticoids, widely known as steroids, remain the standard treatment for various autoimmune disorders due to their effectiveness in reducing inflammation and immune system activity. However, recent discussions highlight the long-term costs and complications associated with steroid toxicity, prompting a reevaluation of their use in clinical practice.</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 01:33:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Corrected: Merck opens billion-dollar US facility to make Gardasil</title><link>https://endpts.com/merck-opens-billion-dollar-facility-to-make-bladder-cancer-immunotherapy/</link><description>Merck has launched a new North Carolina-based manufacturing facility to produce HPV vaccines, including Gardasil and Gardasil 9, to meet rising global demand for cervical cancer prevention. The plant’s opening aligns with Merck’s strategy to expand production capacity amid increasing vaccine rollout efforts worldwide.</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 14:50:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Merck opens $1B vaccine plant in North Carolina</title><link>https://www.biopharmadive.com/news/merck-manufacturing-north-carolina-vaccines/742146/</link><description>Merck has unveiled a new U.S. factory amid mounting pressure on pharmaceutical firms to reshore drug manufacturing to strengthen domestic supply chains. The move reflects a broader industry shift as companies aim to reduce reliance on overseas production and address regulatory and geopolitical risks.</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 17:15:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>How technology advances are helping scientists unlock the mysteries of zoonotic diseases</title><link>https://www.drugdiscoverytrends.com/how-technology-advances-are-helping-scientists-unlock-the-mysteries-of-zoonotic-diseases/</link><description>In 2024, the World Health Organization added 24 pathogens to its pandemic watchlist, including three zoonotic diseases: avian influenza, mpox, and the Sin Nombre virus, the latter of which has a 30% fatality rate. Advances in technology are aiding scientists in understanding and addressing the complexities of these zoonotic diseases.</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 17:27:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Merck dodges ‘failure to warn’ claims in federal Gardasil cases</title><link>https://endpts.com/merck-dodges-failure-to-warn-claims-in-federal-gardasil-cases/</link><description>Merck secured a legal victory as a federal judge dismissed claims that the pharmaceutical giant failed to adequately warn patients about potential risks of its Gardasil HPV vaccine. U.S. District Judge Kenneth Bell ruled plaintiffs didn’t sufficiently prove Merck concealed risks, marking a significant win for the company amid ongoing litigation.</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 18:39:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>A new obesity biotech launches; Gilead plans to quickly advance once-yearly PrEP for HIV</title><link>https://www.biopharmadive.com/news/a-new-obesity-biotech-launches-gilead-plans-to-quickly-advance-once-yearly/742243/</link><description>Harbour BioMed has established Élancé Therapeutics to focus on the development of bispecific antibody drugs aimed at weight loss. In related news, Geron's CEO is stepping down after a 14-year tenure.</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2025 16:15:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Amgen's Uplizna Deepens Response Against Myasthenia Gravis at 1 Year</title><link>https://www.biospace.com/drug-development/amgens-uplizna-deepens-response-against-myasthenia-gravis-at-1-year</link><description>Amgen is set to file a regulatory submission for Uplizna, which is currently approved for a rare ocular autoimmune disorder, to expand its use for myasthenia gravis in the first half of 2025. Analysts are highlighting the strength of the data supporting this move.</description><pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2025 13:28:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Canada pitches in to Entos' facility build; Vetter expands in Germany</title><link>https://endpts.com/canada-pitches-in-to-entos-facility-build-vetter-expands-in-germany/</link><description>The Government of Canada is providing $62 million in funding to Entos Pharmaceuticals to support the development of its novel vaccine technologies. This investment aims to bolster Canada's biomanufacturing capabilities and enhance public health initiatives.</description><pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2025 14:26:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Acelyrin, Pliant turn to ‘poison pill’ as Kevin Tang’s Concentra pursues both companies</title><link>https://endpts.com/acelyrin-pliant-turn-to-poison-pill-as-kevin-tangs-concentra-pursues-both-companies/</link><description>Acelyrin and Pliant Therapeutics have both implemented "poison pill" strategies to deter potential takeover attempts amid speculation that they are targets for Kevin Tang’s Concentra Biosciences. This move comes as Acelyrin, an immunology biotech, continues to grapple with multiple clinical setbacks.</description><pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2025 14:50:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>FDA chooses flu vaccine strains despite cancelled meeting</title><link>https://pharmaphorum.com/news/fda-chooses-flu-vaccine-strains-despite-cancelled-meeting</link><description>The FDA has announced its recommendations for the composition of influenza vaccines for the 2025-26 season, opting to finalize the decision without consulting its external advisors. This move highlights a shift in the agency's approach to vaccine formulation amid ongoing efforts to improve flu prevention strategies.</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2025 13:29:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Altimmune To Test Investigational GLP-1–Based Obesity Drug for Alcohol Use Disorder</title><link>https://www.biospace.com/drug-development/altimmune-to-test-investigational-glp-1-based-obesity-drug-for-alcohol-use-disorder</link><description>A Maryland-based biopharma has partnered with Eli Lilly and Novo Nordisk to trial a GLP-1 agonist aimed at treating alcohol- and liver-related conditions. This collaboration highlights the growing interest in innovative therapies for these health issues.</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2025 14:29:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Altimmune to put its incretin into addiction trials; Tarsus aims to raise $125M</title><link>https://endpts.com/altimmune-to-put-its-incretin-into-addiction-trials-tarsus-aims-to-raise-125m/</link><description>Altimmune announced plans to test its incretin-based treatment for addiction, following a similar initiative by Novo Nordisk. The move highlights a growing interest in leveraging incretins for therapeutic applications beyond diabetes and weight management.</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2025 15:17:18 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>