<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Immunology</title><link>https://nrouizem.github.io/test/immunology_feed.xml</link><description>Daily curated &amp; summarized biopharma news.</description><atom:link href="https://nrouizem.github.io/test/immunology_feed.xml" rel="self"/><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 Mar 2025 01:16:48 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>How 3T Biosciences’ platform targets immunologically cold solid tumors</title><link>https://www.drugdiscoverytrends.com/3t-biosciences-targeted-strategy-for-mss-colorectal-cancer/</link><description>3T Biosciences is tackling the challenge of immunotherapy resistance in solid tumors, particularly focusing on microsatellite stable colorectal cancer (MSS CRC), where over 90% of cases do not respond to checkpoint inhibitors. Their innovative platform aims to improve treatment outcomes for various cancer types that exhibit resistance to current immunotherapy approaches.</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 05:12:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Avoiding aggregates: How new technology is helping mAb developers monitor a vital CQA</title><link>https://www.drugdiscoverytrends.com/avoiding-aggregates-how-new-technology-is-helping-mab-developers-monitor-a-vital-cqa/</link><description>The monoclonal antibody (mAb) market, currently valued at over $330 billion, is projected to more than double by 2030, amid expanding research and development efforts. Developers are increasingly focusing on new technologies to effectively measure and maintain critical quality attributes (CQAs) to address ongoing challenges in mAb production.</description><pubDate>Sat, 08 Feb 2025 19:54:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Rosnilimab phase 2b trial shows promise in treating RA</title><link>https://www.drugdiscoverytrends.com/rosnilimab-phase-2b-trial-shows-promise-in-treating-ra/</link><description>Results from the phase 2b trial of rosnilimab show promise in treating rheumatoid arthritis (RA) by targeting the PD-1 pathway, potentially resetting the immune system for improved patient outcomes. Current treatments often fail to provide long-term remission, necessitating ongoing adjustments among existing therapies.</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2025 14:07:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Solutions for CAR-Engineered Cell Characterization</title><link>https://www.fiercebiotech.com/resource/solutions-car-engineered-cell-characterization</link><description>Cell Signaling Technology (CST) has unveiled purpose-built tools, including recombinant antibodies targeting scFv linkers like G4S and Whitlow/218, to accelerate CAR-engineered cell characterization and development. The solutions aim to bypass the costly, time-intensive process of anti-idiotype antibody creation while streamlining workflows for researchers.</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2025 14:49:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Accelerating and Enabling Consistency of Bioprocessing Scale-up</title><link>https://www.fiercebiotech.com/premium/webinar/1368685</link><description>Discover how to streamline bioprocessing scale-up for monoclonal antibody (mAb) production through media optimization, High-Intensity Perfusion (HIP) CHO solutions, and innovative bioreactor designs in an upcoming webinar featuring experts Vivian Ott and Maren Grun. The session will delve into strategies for enhancing manufacturing efficiency, sustainability, and rapid commercialization, supported by case studies on successful process intensification and scalable technologies.</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2025 19:38:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>What FDA, NIH hearings say about Trump drug, health policy</title><link>https://endpts.com/what-fda-nih-hearings-say-about-trump-drug-health-policy/</link><description>President Trump's nominees for NIH director and FDA commissioner faced little opposition in their confirmation hearings, avoiding contentious discussions while offering broadly cautious responses. However, subtle hints about their policy views raised questions about potential future shifts in health agency priorities.</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2025 17:45:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Multi-Modality Testing of EGFR</title><link>https://www.fiercebiotech.com/resource/multi-modality-testing-egfr</link><description>Neogenomics highlights its new white paper advocating a multi-modality testing approach to improve clinical trials, offering deeper insights into patient responses and treatment effectiveness. The sponsored resource, available for download, underscores how integrating diverse testing methods can advance oncology research and therapeutic outcomes.</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2025 18:04:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Arrowhead reveals small batch of open-label data for 'non-core' kidney drug</title><link>https://endpts.com/arrowhead-reveals-small-batch-of-open-label-data-for-non-core-kidney-drug/</link><description>Arrowhead Pharmaceuticals unveiled promising new open-label data from its ARO-C3 RNAi therapy program, showing potential to improve kidney disease outcomes by targeting complement pathways in a small study involving about a dozen patients. The early-stage results highlight the therapy's novel approach to addressing kidney disorders, though no partnerships or business deals related to the program were disclosed.</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 15:07:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>J&amp;J, Protagonist outline first IBD win for potential immunological blockbuster</title><link>https://endpts.com/jj-protagonist-outline-first-ibd-win-for-potential-immunological-blockbuster/</link><description>Johnson &amp; Johnson and Protagonist Therapeutics have partnered to develop an oral IL-23 drug, aiming to create a breakthrough immunology treatment. The companies announced progress toward this goal on Monday, signaling potential advancements in bringing the blockbuster drug candidate closer to market.</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 16:04:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The true cost of steroid-toxicity</title><link>https://www.drugdiscoverytrends.com/the-true-cost-of-steroid-toxicity/</link><description>Glucocorticoids, or steroids, are widely used as the standard treatment for autoimmune disorders due to their effectiveness in suppressing inflammation and reducing immune system activity. However, the article highlights the hidden costs and potential long-term toxicity associated with steroid use, raising concerns about their overall safety.</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 01:33:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>How technology advances are helping scientists unlock the mysteries of zoonotic diseases</title><link>https://www.drugdiscoverytrends.com/how-technology-advances-are-helping-scientists-unlock-the-mysteries-of-zoonotic-diseases/</link><description>The World Health Organization has added 24 pathogens to its pandemic watchlist in 2024, including three zoonotic diseases: avian influenza, mpox, and Sin Nombre virus, the latter having a 30% fatality rate. Advances in technology are aiding scientists in understanding these zoonotic diseases and their potential impacts on public health.</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 17:27:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Amgen's Uplizna Deepens Response Against Myasthenia Gravis at 1 Year</title><link>https://www.biospace.com/drug-development/amgens-uplizna-deepens-response-against-myasthenia-gravis-at-1-year</link><description>Amgen is preparing to file a regulatory submission for Uplizna, previously approved for a rare ocular autoimmune disorder, for use in treating myasthenia gravis in the first half of 2025. Analysts describe the data supporting this move as "strong."</description><pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2025 13:28:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Acelyrin, Pliant turn to ‘poison pill’ as Kevin Tang’s Concentra pursues both companies</title><link>https://endpts.com/acelyrin-pliant-turn-to-poison-pill-as-kevin-tangs-concentra-pursues-both-companies/</link><description>Acelyrin and Pliant Therapeutics have implemented “poison pill” defenses as they are considered potential takeover targets for Kevin Tang’s Concentra Biosciences. This strategic move comes amid Acelyrin's struggles in the immunology sector, marked by clinical setbacks.</description><pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2025 14:50:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Altimmune To Test Investigational GLP-1–Based Obesity Drug for Alcohol Use Disorder</title><link>https://www.biospace.com/drug-development/altimmune-to-test-investigational-glp-1-based-obesity-drug-for-alcohol-use-disorder</link><description>A Maryland-based biopharma is participating in clinical trials for a GLP-1 agonist aimed at treating alcohol- and liver-related conditions, joining major companies Eli Lilly and Novo Nordisk in this research effort. This collaboration highlights the growing interest in innovative therapeutic approaches within the biopharmaceutical industry.</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2025 14:29:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Altimmune to put its incretin into addiction trials; Tarsus aims to raise $125M</title><link>https://endpts.com/altimmune-to-put-its-incretin-into-addiction-trials-tarsus-aims-to-raise-125m/</link><description>Altimmune plans to test its incretin for potential applications in addiction, following a similar initiative by Novo Nordisk. This move highlights the growing interest in leveraging diabetes medications for broader therapeutic uses.</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2025 15:17:18 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>