<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Immunology</title><link>https://nrouizem.github.io/test/immunology_feed.xml</link><description>Daily curated &amp; summarized biopharma news.</description><atom:link href="https://nrouizem.github.io/test/immunology_feed.xml" rel="self"/><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Mar 2025 01:17:43 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Avoiding aggregates: How new technology is helping mAb developers monitor a vital CQA</title><link>https://www.drugdiscoverytrends.com/avoiding-aggregates-how-new-technology-is-helping-mab-developers-monitor-a-vital-cqa/</link><description>The monoclonal antibodies (mAbs) market, valued at over $330 billion, is poised to more than double by 2030 amid growing research and development challenges. New technology advancements are emerging to assist developers in monitoring critical quality attributes (CQAs), particularly in avoiding aggregates.</description><pubDate>Sat, 08 Feb 2025 19:54:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Rosnilimab phase 2b trial shows promise in treating RA</title><link>https://www.drugdiscoverytrends.com/rosnilimab-phase-2b-trial-shows-promise-in-treating-ra/</link><description>Rosnilimab, a novel treatment for rheumatoid arthritis (RA), shows promise in a phase 2b trial by targeting the PD-1 pathway to reset the immune system, offering hope for long-term remission. This innovative approach aims to provide sustained relief for patients who often cycle through current therapies like methotrexate and biologics.</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2025 14:07:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Solutions for CAR-Engineered Cell Characterization</title><link>https://www.fiercebiotech.com/resource/solutions-car-engineered-cell-characterization</link><description>Cell Signaling Technology (CST) has unveiled purpose-built tools, including recombinant antibodies targeting scFv linkers like G4S and Whitlow/218, to accelerate CAR-engineered cell characterization and development. The solutions aim to bypass the costly, time-intensive process of anti-idiotype antibody creation while streamlining workflows for researchers.</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2025 14:49:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>What FDA, NIH hearings say about Trump drug, health policy</title><link>https://endpts.com/what-fda-nih-hearings-say-about-trump-drug-health-policy/</link><description>President Trump's nominees for NIH director and FDA commissioner faced little opposition in their confirmation hearings, avoiding contentious discussions while offering broadly cautious responses. However, subtle hints about their policy views raised questions about potential future shifts in health agency priorities.</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2025 17:45:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Multi-Modality Testing of EGFR</title><link>https://www.fiercebiotech.com/resource/multi-modality-testing-egfr</link><description>Neogenomics highlights its new white paper advocating a multi-modality testing approach to improve clinical trials, offering deeper insights into patient responses and treatment effectiveness. The sponsored resource, available for download, underscores how integrating diverse testing methods can advance oncology research and therapeutic outcomes.</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2025 18:04:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Arrowhead reveals small batch of open-label data for 'non-core' kidney drug</title><link>https://endpts.com/arrowhead-reveals-small-batch-of-open-label-data-for-non-core-kidney-drug/</link><description>Arrowhead Pharmaceuticals unveiled promising new open-label data from its ARO-C3 RNAi therapy program, showing potential to improve kidney disease outcomes by targeting complement pathways in a small study involving about a dozen patients. The early-stage results highlight the therapy's novel approach to addressing kidney disorders, though no partnerships or business deals related to the program were disclosed.</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 15:07:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>J&amp;J, Protagonist outline first IBD win for potential immunological blockbuster</title><link>https://endpts.com/jj-protagonist-outline-first-ibd-win-for-potential-immunological-blockbuster/</link><description>Johnson &amp; Johnson and Protagonist Therapeutics have partnered to develop an oral IL-23 drug, aiming to create a breakthrough immunology treatment. The companies announced progress toward this goal on Monday, signaling potential advancements in bringing the blockbuster drug candidate closer to market.</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 16:04:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The true cost of steroid-toxicity</title><link>https://www.drugdiscoverytrends.com/the-true-cost-of-steroid-toxicity/</link><description>Glucocorticoids, or steroids, remain the standard treatment for various autoimmune disorders due to their effectiveness in suppressing inflammation and alleviating symptoms. However, the article highlights the hidden costs and potential long-term toxicity associated with steroid use, raising concerns about their overall impact on patient health.</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 01:33:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Corrected: Merck opens billion-dollar US facility to make Gardasil</title><link>https://endpts.com/merck-opens-billion-dollar-facility-to-make-bladder-cancer-immunotherapy/</link><description>Merck has launched a new North Carolina-based manufacturing facility to produce HPV vaccines, including Gardasil and Gardasil 9, to meet rising global demand for cervical cancer prevention. The plant’s opening aligns with Merck’s strategy to expand production capacity amid increasing vaccine rollout efforts worldwide.</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 14:50:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Agenus CMO touts immunotherapy advances on The Top Line</title><link>https://www.fiercebiotech.com/sponsored/agenus-cmo-touts-immunotherapy-advances-top-line</link><description>Agenus Chief Medical Officer highlighted significant advancements in immunotherapy during a recent discussion on The Top Line, emphasizing the company's commitment to innovative cancer treatments. The conversation underscored Agenus's strategic focus on enhancing patient outcomes through its developing therapies and ongoing research.</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 17:26:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>How technology advances are helping scientists unlock the mysteries of zoonotic diseases</title><link>https://www.drugdiscoverytrends.com/how-technology-advances-are-helping-scientists-unlock-the-mysteries-of-zoonotic-diseases/</link><description>In 2024, the World Health Organization expanded its pandemic watchlist by adding 24 pathogens, including three zoonotic diseases: avian influenza, mpox (formerly monkeypox), and the Sin Nombre virus, which has a 30% fatality rate. The article explores how technological advancements are aiding scientists in understanding these complex zoonotic diseases.</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 17:27:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Advancing the Future of Biomarker-Driven Immunotherapy</title><link>https://www.fiercebiotech.com/premium/webinar/1369042</link><description>An upcoming webinar will delve into the DUTRENEO trial's findings on the use of spatial biomarkers to enhance patient stratification for immunotherapy in muscle-invasive bladder cancer. The session will highlight transformative multi-omics approaches that aim to improve therapeutic selection by addressing challenges in predictive biomarkers.</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2025 17:43:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Altimmune Jumps On Takeover Rumors After Launching Alcohol Use Disorder Study</title><link>https://www.biospace.com/business/altimmune-jumps-on-takeover-rumors-after-launching-alcohol-use-disorder-study</link><description>The company announced its plans to initiate testing of a dual receptor agonist targeting GLP-1 and glucagon for the treatment of alcohol use disorder and alcohol-related liver disease. This innovative approach aims to address significant health challenges associated with excessive alcohol consumption.</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2025 12:44:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trispecific Antibodies Unlocking New Promises In Targeted Therapies</title><link>https://www.biospace.com/press-releases/trispecific-antibodies-unlocking-new-promises-in-targeted-therapies</link><description>Please provide the article you would like me to summarize.</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 19:31:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Immunovant Will Drop One Myasthenia Gravis Asset, Continuing to Favor Another</title><link>https://www.biospace.com/drug-development/immunovant-will-drop-one-myasthenia-gravis-asset-continuing-to-favor-another</link><description>Immunovant reported positive analyst feedback on batoclimab for treating chronic autoimmune disorders but announced its decision to prioritize another next-generation asset for this indication. The company remains committed to advancing its pipeline while exploring innovative solutions for patients.</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 15:33:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Immunovant claims study success for immune disease drug but holds off on submission</title><link>https://www.biopharmadive.com/news/immunovant-roivant-batoclimab-myasthenia-gravis-1402-data/742921/</link><description>The company is concentrating on developing a next-generation drug as it completes testing of batoclimab for thyroid eye disease. This strategic focus indicates a commitment to advancing its innovative drug pipeline amidst ongoing clinical endeavors.</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 15:45:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Sanofi wagers $600M on a dual-targeting antibody drug for autoimmune disease</title><link>https://www.biopharmadive.com/news/sanofi-dren-deal-bispecific-myeloid-cell-engager-autoimmune/743041/</link><description>Sanofi has secured a deal with startup Dren Bio to obtain a myeloid cell engager, aiming to enhance therapeutic options for treating inflammatory conditions. This partnership positions Sanofi to compete with other initiatives focused on "resetting" the immune systems of affected patients.</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2025 15:20:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Sanofi outlays $1.9bn to purchase Dren Bio’s bispecific antibody</title><link>https://www.pharmaceutical-technology.com/news/sanofi-outlays-1-9bn-to-purchase-dren-bios-bispecific-antibody/</link><description>Sanofi has made a strategic move to acquire Dren Bio's clinical asset, enhancing its focus on immunology. This acquisition is part of Sanofi's broader goal to establish itself as a leader in the immunology sector.</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2025 16:34:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Menarini to enhance BPDCN detection with VisualDx’s link</title><link>https://www.pharmaceutical-technology.com/news/menarini-bpdcn-visualdx/</link><description>Menarini Group has entered into a partnership with VisualDx to improve the diagnosis of patients with Blastic Plasmacytoid Dendritic Cell Neoplasm (BPDCN). This collaboration aims to leverage advanced visual diagnostics to enhance patient outcomes in this rare cancer.</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 10:16:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>J&amp;J Wins Crohn’s Expansion for Tremfya as Stelara Biosimilars Enter US Market</title><link>https://www.biospace.com/drug-development/j-j-wins-crohns-expansion-for-tremfya-as-stelara-biosimilars-enter-us-market</link><description>Johnson &amp; Johnson's label expansion for Tremfya aims to position it as a successor to Stelara, which is encountering increasing competition from biosimilars. This strategic move highlights J&amp;J's efforts to maintain its market leadership in immunology treatments.</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 12:46:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>AstraZeneca deepens China investment; Editas loses CFO to Dyne</title><link>https://www.biopharmadive.com/news/astrazeneca-deepens-china-investment-editas-loses-cfo-to-dyne/743158/</link><description>A pharmaceutical company is investing $2.5 billion to establish a research and development center in Beijing. Additionally, Adaptimmune has issued a warning about a potential cash shortfall, while Pfizer has divested its remaining stake in Haleon.</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 16:15:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Delayed CDC meeting on vaccines is rescheduled to April</title><link>https://www.biopharmadive.com/news/cdc-acip-meeting-rescheduled-vaccines-measles/743189/</link><description>A panel of CDC advisers will convene in February to address the ongoing measles outbreak and review vaccination guidelines for various immunizations. The meeting aims to provide updated recommendations to enhance public health responses to the outbreak.</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 16:17:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>