<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Immunology</title><link>https://nrouizem.github.io/test/immunology_feed.xml</link><description>Daily curated &amp; summarized biopharma news.</description><atom:link href="https://nrouizem.github.io/test/immunology_feed.xml" rel="self"/><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 01:18:21 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>How 3T Biosciences’ platform targets immunologically cold solid tumors</title><link>https://www.drugdiscoverytrends.com/3t-biosciences-targeted-strategy-for-mss-colorectal-cancer/</link><description>3T Biosciences is tackling the challenge of immunotherapy resistance in solid tumors, particularly in microsatellite stable colorectal cancer (MSS CRC), where over 90% of cases show limited response to current treatments. The company's innovative platform aims to enhance responses in immunologically cold solid tumors, addressing a critical need in oncology.</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 05:12:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Avoiding aggregates: How new technology is helping mAb developers monitor a vital CQA</title><link>https://www.drugdiscoverytrends.com/avoiding-aggregates-how-new-technology-is-helping-mab-developers-monitor-a-vital-cqa/</link><description>The monoclonal antibodies (mAbs) market, currently valued over $330 billion, is projected to more than double by 2030, highlighting significant growth potential in this sector. Developers are increasingly focusing on new technologies to address challenges in measuring and maintaining critical quality attributes (CQAs), particularly in preventing aggregates.</description><pubDate>Sat, 08 Feb 2025 19:54:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Rosnilimab phase 2b trial shows promise in treating RA</title><link>https://www.drugdiscoverytrends.com/rosnilimab-phase-2b-trial-shows-promise-in-treating-ra/</link><description>A phase 2b trial of rosnilimab, which targets the PD-1 pathway to reset the immune system, shows promise in providing long-term relief for rheumatoid arthritis (RA) patients who often struggle with existing treatments. This novel approach could offer a breakthrough for those cycling through therapies like methotrexate and biologics without sustained remission.</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2025 14:07:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Solutions for CAR-Engineered Cell Characterization</title><link>https://www.fiercebiotech.com/resource/solutions-car-engineered-cell-characterization</link><description>Cell Signaling Technology (CST) has unveiled purpose-built tools, including recombinant antibodies targeting scFv linkers like G4S and Whitlow/218, to accelerate CAR-engineered cell characterization and development. The solutions aim to bypass the costly, time-intensive process of anti-idiotype antibody creation while streamlining workflows for researchers.</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2025 14:49:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Accelerating and Enabling Consistency of Bioprocessing Scale-up</title><link>https://www.fiercebiotech.com/premium/webinar/1368685</link><description>Discover how to streamline bioprocessing scale-up for monoclonal antibody (mAb) production through media optimization, High-Intensity Perfusion (HIP) CHO solutions, and innovative bioreactor designs in an upcoming webinar featuring experts Vivian Ott and Maren Grun. The session will delve into strategies for enhancing manufacturing efficiency, sustainability, and rapid commercialization, supported by case studies on successful process intensification and scalable technologies.</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2025 19:38:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Arrowhead reveals small batch of open-label data for 'non-core' kidney drug</title><link>https://endpts.com/arrowhead-reveals-small-batch-of-open-label-data-for-non-core-kidney-drug/</link><description>Arrowhead Pharmaceuticals unveiled promising new open-label data from its ARO-C3 RNAi therapy program, showing potential to improve kidney disease outcomes by targeting complement pathways in a small study involving about a dozen patients. The early-stage results highlight the therapy's novel approach to addressing kidney disorders, though no partnerships or business deals related to the program were disclosed.</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 15:07:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>J&amp;J, Protagonist outline first IBD win for potential immunological blockbuster</title><link>https://endpts.com/jj-protagonist-outline-first-ibd-win-for-potential-immunological-blockbuster/</link><description>Johnson &amp; Johnson and Protagonist Therapeutics have partnered to develop an oral IL-23 drug, aiming to create a breakthrough immunology treatment. The companies announced progress toward this goal on Monday, signaling potential advancements in bringing the blockbuster drug candidate closer to market.</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 16:04:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The true cost of steroid-toxicity</title><link>https://www.drugdiscoverytrends.com/the-true-cost-of-steroid-toxicity/</link><description>Glucocorticoids, widely used for treating autoimmune disorders due to their effectiveness in reducing inflammation and immune system activity, seem like a low-cost option at first glance. However, the article highlights the long-term toxicity and hidden costs associated with their prolonged use, urging a reevaluation of their role in treatment protocols.</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 01:33:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Agenus CMO touts immunotherapy advances on The Top Line</title><link>https://www.fiercebiotech.com/sponsored/agenus-cmo-touts-immunotherapy-advances-top-line</link><description>Agenus's Chief Medical Officer highlighted significant progress in the company's immunotherapy advancements during a recent interview on The Top Line. The discussion underscored Agenus's commitment to developing innovative cancer treatments and enhancing patient outcomes.</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 17:26:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>How technology advances are helping scientists unlock the mysteries of zoonotic diseases</title><link>https://www.drugdiscoverytrends.com/how-technology-advances-are-helping-scientists-unlock-the-mysteries-of-zoonotic-diseases/</link><description>In 2024, the World Health Organization included 24 new pathogens on its pandemic watchlist, highlighting the growing concern over zoonotic diseases like avian influenza, mpox, and Sin Nombre virus, which has a high fatality rate. The article discusses how advancements in technology are aiding scientists in understanding these complex diseases.</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 17:27:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Amgen's Uplizna Deepens Response Against Myasthenia Gravis at 1 Year</title><link>https://www.biospace.com/drug-development/amgens-uplizna-deepens-response-against-myasthenia-gravis-at-1-year</link><description>Amgen is set to file a regulatory submission for Uplizna, currently approved for a rare ocular autoimmune disorder, for use in treating myasthenia gravis by mid-2025, following what analysts describe as "strong" data. This move reflects Amgen's commitment to expanding the therapeutic applications of its existing treatments.</description><pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2025 13:28:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Altimmune To Test Investigational GLP-1–Based Obesity Drug for Alcohol Use Disorder</title><link>https://www.biospace.com/drug-development/altimmune-to-test-investigational-glp-1-based-obesity-drug-for-alcohol-use-disorder</link><description>A Maryland-based biopharma is partnering with Eli Lilly and Novo Nordisk to trial a GLP-1 agonist aimed at addressing alcohol- and liver-related conditions. This collaboration aims to explore innovative treatment options in the growing field of metabolic health.</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2025 14:29:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Concern as measles cases doubled in Europe last year</title><link>https://pharmaphorum.com/news/concern-measles-cases-doubled-europe-last-year</link><description>A significant surge in measles cases across Europe in 2024 has sparked urgent demands for increased vaccination efforts. Health officials emphasize the importance of cooperation among nations to combat the outbreak and protect public health.</description><pubDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2025 18:35:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>5 CAR T Cell Therapies With Autoimmune Readouts in 2025</title><link>https://www.biospace.com/drug-development/5-car-t-cell-therapies-with-autoimmune-readouts-in-2025</link><description>Biopharma is set to expand the successful application of CAR T therapies from cancer to autoimmune disorders, with several early- to mid-stage trial results anticipated this year. This shift reflects the industry's commitment to exploring innovative treatments beyond oncology.</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2025 04:01:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Altimmune Jumps On Takeover Rumors After Launching Alcohol Use Disorder Study</title><link>https://www.biospace.com/business/altimmune-jumps-on-takeover-rumors-after-launching-alcohol-use-disorder-study</link><description>The company revealed its plans to initiate testing of a GLP-1/glucagon dual receptor agonist aimed at addressing alcohol use disorder and alcohol-related liver disease. This innovative approach highlights the growing focus on novel therapies for alcohol-related health issues.</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2025 12:44:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>AstraZeneca adds ‘in vivo’ cell therapy capabilities with EsoBiotech deal</title><link>https://www.biopharmadive.com/news/astrazeneca-esobiotech-acquire-in-vivo-cell-therapy/742643/</link><description>A pharmaceutical company is acquiring a Belgian startup for up to $1 billion, aiming to leverage its innovative technology for cancer and autoimmune treatments. This strategic purchase reflects the company's commitment to advancing its therapeutic pipeline.</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2025 13:28:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>