<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Immunology</title><link>https://nrouizem.github.io/test/immunology_feed.xml</link><description>Daily curated &amp; summarized biopharma news.</description><atom:link href="https://nrouizem.github.io/test/immunology_feed.xml" rel="self"/><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2025 01:17:21 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>How 3T Biosciences’ platform targets immunologically cold solid tumors</title><link>https://www.drugdiscoverytrends.com/3t-biosciences-targeted-strategy-for-mss-colorectal-cancer/</link><description>3T Biosciences is addressing the challenge of immunotherapy resistance in solid tumors, particularly focusing on microsatellite stable colorectal cancer (MSS CRC), which shows a high failure rate to respond to existing treatments. Their innovative platform aims to target immunologically cold solid tumors, potentially improving therapeutic outcomes in oncology.</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 05:12:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Avoiding aggregates: How new technology is helping mAb developers monitor a vital CQA</title><link>https://www.drugdiscoverytrends.com/avoiding-aggregates-how-new-technology-is-helping-mab-developers-monitor-a-vital-cqa/</link><description>The monoclonal antibodies (mAbs) market, valued at over $330 billion, is projected to exceed $660 billion by 2030, driven by a growing research pipeline. Developers are increasingly focused on overcoming challenges related to measuring and maintaining critical quality attributes (CQAs) to ensure product efficacy and safety.</description><pubDate>Sat, 08 Feb 2025 19:54:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Rosnilimab phase 2b trial shows promise in treating RA</title><link>https://www.drugdiscoverytrends.com/rosnilimab-phase-2b-trial-shows-promise-in-treating-ra/</link><description>A recent phase 2b trial has demonstrated that rosnilimab, a novel treatment for rheumatoid arthritis (RA), shows promise by specifically targeting the PD-1 pathway to reset the immune system. This approach could offer a new option for patients who struggle to achieve long-term remission with existing therapies.</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2025 14:07:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Solutions for CAR-Engineered Cell Characterization</title><link>https://www.fiercebiotech.com/resource/solutions-car-engineered-cell-characterization</link><description>Cell Signaling Technology (CST) has unveiled purpose-built tools, including recombinant antibodies targeting scFv linkers like G4S and Whitlow/218, to accelerate CAR-engineered cell characterization and development. The solutions aim to bypass the costly, time-intensive process of anti-idiotype antibody creation while streamlining workflows for researchers.</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2025 14:49:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>J&amp;J, Protagonist outline first IBD win for potential immunological blockbuster</title><link>https://endpts.com/jj-protagonist-outline-first-ibd-win-for-potential-immunological-blockbuster/</link><description>Johnson &amp; Johnson and Protagonist Therapeutics have partnered to develop an oral IL-23 drug, aiming to create a breakthrough immunology treatment. The companies announced progress toward this goal on Monday, signaling potential advancements in bringing the blockbuster drug candidate closer to market.</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 16:04:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The true cost of steroid-toxicity</title><link>https://www.drugdiscoverytrends.com/the-true-cost-of-steroid-toxicity/</link><description>Glucocorticoids, or steroids, are widely used as the standard treatment for autoimmune disorders due to their effectiveness in suppressing inflammation and immune activity. However, emerging concerns about the long-term toxicity and costs associated with steroid use highlight the need for more sustainable treatment alternatives.</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 01:33:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Corrected: Merck opens billion-dollar US facility to make Gardasil</title><link>https://endpts.com/merck-opens-billion-dollar-facility-to-make-bladder-cancer-immunotherapy/</link><description>Merck has launched a new North Carolina-based manufacturing facility to produce HPV vaccines, including Gardasil and Gardasil 9, to meet rising global demand for cervical cancer prevention. The plant’s opening aligns with Merck’s strategy to expand production capacity amid increasing vaccine rollout efforts worldwide.</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 14:50:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>How technology advances are helping scientists unlock the mysteries of zoonotic diseases</title><link>https://www.drugdiscoverytrends.com/how-technology-advances-are-helping-scientists-unlock-the-mysteries-of-zoonotic-diseases/</link><description>In 2024, the World Health Organization added 24 pathogens to its pandemic watchlist, highlighting three zoonotic diseases: avian influenza, mpox, and the Sin Nombre virus, which has a 30% fatality rate. The article discusses how advancements in technology are aiding scientists in understanding these dangerous diseases and their transmission from animals to humans.</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 17:27:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Amgen's Uplizna Deepens Response Against Myasthenia Gravis at 1 Year</title><link>https://www.biospace.com/drug-development/amgens-uplizna-deepens-response-against-myasthenia-gravis-at-1-year</link><description>Amgen intends to submit a regulatory filing for Uplizna, which is currently approved for a rare ocular autoimmune disorder, for use in treating myasthenia gravis by the first half of 2025. Analysts are expressing optimism about the strong data supporting this expansion.</description><pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2025 13:28:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Acelyrin, Pliant turn to ‘poison pill’ as Kevin Tang’s Concentra pursues both companies</title><link>https://endpts.com/acelyrin-pliant-turn-to-poison-pill-as-kevin-tangs-concentra-pursues-both-companies/</link><description>Acelyrin and Pliant Therapeutics have implemented "poison pill" strategies in response to potential takeover interest from Kevin Tang’s Concentra Biosciences. This move comes as Acelyrin, an immunology biotech, grapples with several clinical challenges.</description><pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2025 14:50:24 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>