<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Immunology</title><link>https://nrouizem.github.io/test/immunology_feed.xml</link><description>Daily curated &amp; summarized biopharma news.</description><atom:link href="https://nrouizem.github.io/test/immunology_feed.xml" rel="self"/><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2025 01:20:31 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>How 3T Biosciences’ platform targets immunologically cold solid tumors</title><link>https://www.drugdiscoverytrends.com/3t-biosciences-targeted-strategy-for-mss-colorectal-cancer/</link><description>3T Biosciences is addressing the therapeutic challenge of immunotherapy resistance in solid tumors, particularly in microsatellite stable colorectal cancer (MSS CRC), where over 90% of cases do not respond to existing checkpoint inhibitors. Their innovative platform aims to enhance treatment effectiveness by targeting immunologically cold solid tumors and improving patient outcomes in oncology.</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 05:12:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Avoiding aggregates: How new technology is helping mAb developers monitor a vital CQA</title><link>https://www.drugdiscoverytrends.com/avoiding-aggregates-how-new-technology-is-helping-mab-developers-monitor-a-vital-cqa/</link><description>The monoclonal antibodies (mAbs) market, currently valued at over $330 billion, is projected to exceed $660 billion by 2030, bolstered by a growing research pipeline. Developers are increasingly focused on overcoming challenges in monitoring critical quality attributes (CQAs), with new technologies emerging to help prevent the formation of aggregates in mAb production.</description><pubDate>Sat, 08 Feb 2025 19:54:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Rosnilimab phase 2b trial shows promise in treating RA</title><link>https://www.drugdiscoverytrends.com/rosnilimab-phase-2b-trial-shows-promise-in-treating-ra/</link><description>A phase 2b trial of rosnilimab shows promise in treating rheumatoid arthritis (RA) by targeting the PD-1 pathway to reset the immune system, potentially offering a new approach for patients who have not achieved long-term remission with existing therapies. This novel treatment could address the unmet needs of those cycling through traditional options like methotrexate and biologics.</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2025 14:07:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Solutions for CAR-Engineered Cell Characterization</title><link>https://www.fiercebiotech.com/resource/solutions-car-engineered-cell-characterization</link><description>Cell Signaling Technology (CST) has unveiled purpose-built tools, including recombinant antibodies targeting scFv linkers like G4S and Whitlow/218, to accelerate CAR-engineered cell characterization and development. The solutions aim to bypass the costly, time-intensive process of anti-idiotype antibody creation while streamlining workflows for researchers.</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2025 14:49:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Arrowhead reveals small batch of open-label data for 'non-core' kidney drug</title><link>https://endpts.com/arrowhead-reveals-small-batch-of-open-label-data-for-non-core-kidney-drug/</link><description>Arrowhead Pharmaceuticals unveiled promising new open-label data from its ARO-C3 RNAi therapy program, showing potential to improve kidney disease outcomes by targeting complement pathways in a small study involving about a dozen patients. The early-stage results highlight the therapy's novel approach to addressing kidney disorders, though no partnerships or business deals related to the program were disclosed.</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 15:07:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>J&amp;J, Protagonist outline first IBD win for potential immunological blockbuster</title><link>https://endpts.com/jj-protagonist-outline-first-ibd-win-for-potential-immunological-blockbuster/</link><description>Johnson &amp; Johnson and Protagonist Therapeutics have partnered to develop an oral IL-23 drug, aiming to create a breakthrough immunology treatment. The companies announced progress toward this goal on Monday, signaling potential advancements in bringing the blockbuster drug candidate closer to market.</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 16:04:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The true cost of steroid-toxicity</title><link>https://www.drugdiscoverytrends.com/the-true-cost-of-steroid-toxicity/</link><description>Glucocorticoids, often known as steroids, remain the standard treatment for autoimmune disorders due to their effectiveness in suppressing inflammation and alleviating symptoms. However, the article highlights the hidden costs of steroid toxicity, which can lead to significant long-term health issues.</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 01:33:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>How technology advances are helping scientists unlock the mysteries of zoonotic diseases</title><link>https://www.drugdiscoverytrends.com/how-technology-advances-are-helping-scientists-unlock-the-mysteries-of-zoonotic-diseases/</link><description>In 2024, the World Health Organization added 24 pathogens to its pandemic watchlist, highlighting three new zoonotic diseases: avian influenza, mpox (previously known as monkeypox), and the Sin Nombre virus, which has a high fatality rate. Advances in technology are aiding scientists in understanding and combatting these emerging threats to public health.</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 17:27:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Amgen's Uplizna Deepens Response Against Myasthenia Gravis at 1 Year</title><link>https://www.biospace.com/drug-development/amgens-uplizna-deepens-response-against-myasthenia-gravis-at-1-year</link><description>Amgen is set to file a regulatory submission for Uplizna, currently approved for a rare ocular autoimmune disorder, for use in myasthenia gravis in the first half of 2025, backed by strong data. Analysts are optimistic about the potential of this expansion in the drug's application.</description><pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2025 13:28:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Acelyrin, Pliant turn to ‘poison pill’ as Kevin Tang’s Concentra pursues both companies</title><link>https://endpts.com/acelyrin-pliant-turn-to-poison-pill-as-kevin-tangs-concentra-pursues-both-companies/</link><description>Acelyrin and Pliant Therapeutics have both initiated "poison pill" strategies in response to potential takeover interest from Concentra Biosciences, led by Kevin Tang. This move comes as Acelyrin faces ongoing challenges in its immunology initiatives, signaling a proactive defense against acquisition threats.</description><pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2025 14:50:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Altimmune To Test Investigational GLP-1–Based Obesity Drug for Alcohol Use Disorder</title><link>https://www.biospace.com/drug-development/altimmune-to-test-investigational-glp-1-based-obesity-drug-for-alcohol-use-disorder</link><description>Maryland-based biopharma has partnered with Eli Lilly and Novo Nordisk to conduct trials on a GLP-1 agonist aimed at treating alcohol- and liver-related conditions. This collaboration highlights the growing interest in innovative therapies for addressing these health challenges.</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2025 14:29:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Altimmune to put its incretin into addiction trials; Tarsus aims to raise $125M</title><link>https://endpts.com/altimmune-to-put-its-incretin-into-addiction-trials-tarsus-aims-to-raise-125m/</link><description>Altimmune announced plans to test its incretin product in addiction treatment, following a similar strategy recently adopted by Novo Nordisk. The company highlights the potential of its drug in addressing addiction issues, signaling a focus on innovative therapies in the pharmaceutical landscape.</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2025 15:17:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Concern as measles cases doubled in Europe last year</title><link>https://pharmaphorum.com/news/concern-measles-cases-doubled-europe-last-year</link><description>A significant increase in measles cases across Europe in 2024 has sparked urgent demands for a coordinated effort to boost vaccination rates. Public health officials emphasize the critical need for immediate action to prevent further outbreaks and protect communities.</description><pubDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2025 18:35:24 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>