<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Immunology</title><link>https://nrouizem.github.io/test/immunology_feed.xml</link><description>Daily curated &amp; summarized biopharma news.</description><atom:link href="https://nrouizem.github.io/test/immunology_feed.xml" rel="self"/><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2025 01:49:09 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>How 3T Biosciences’ platform targets immunologically cold solid tumors</title><link>https://www.drugdiscoverytrends.com/3t-biosciences-targeted-strategy-for-mss-colorectal-cancer/</link><description>Immunotherapy resistance in solid tumors, particularly microsatellite stable colorectal cancer (MSS CRC), poses a major challenge in oncology, as over 90% of MSS CRC cases show limited response to current checkpoint inhibitor therapies. The article highlights how 3T Biosciences’ innovative platform aims to address this issue by targeting immunologically cold solid tumors.</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 05:12:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>How conversational AI can detect pharma safety events</title><link>https://www.drugdiscoverytrends.com/how-conversational-ai-can-detect-pharma-safety-events/</link><description>Pharmaceutical manufacturers face challenges in capturing critical safety events despite their importance in ensuring patient safety and regulatory compliance. The article discusses how conversational AI can enhance the detection and reporting of these safety events, thereby improving overall outcomes in the industry.</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2025 16:52:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Avoiding aggregates: How new technology is helping mAb developers monitor a vital CQA</title><link>https://www.drugdiscoverytrends.com/avoiding-aggregates-how-new-technology-is-helping-mab-developers-monitor-a-vital-cqa/</link><description>The market for monoclonal antibodies (mAbs) is projected to exceed $330 billion and more than double by 2030, but developers face significant challenges in measuring and maintaining critical quality attributes (CQAs). New technologies are emerging to help mAb developers effectively monitor these vital CQAs, addressing the growing demands of the research pipeline.</description><pubDate>Sat, 08 Feb 2025 19:54:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Rosnilimab phase 2b trial shows promise in treating RA</title><link>https://www.drugdiscoverytrends.com/rosnilimab-phase-2b-trial-shows-promise-in-treating-ra/</link><description>A phase 2b trial for rosnilimab, a novel treatment for rheumatoid arthritis (RA), shows promise by targeting the PD-1 pathway to help reset the immune system and potentially provide long-term remission for patients. This new approach aims to address the limitations of current therapies that often leave patients without sustained relief.</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2025 14:07:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Solutions for CAR-Engineered Cell Characterization</title><link>https://www.fiercebiotech.com/resource/solutions-car-engineered-cell-characterization</link><description>Cell Signaling Technology (CST) has unveiled purpose-built tools, including recombinant antibodies targeting scFv linkers like G4S and Whitlow/218, to accelerate CAR-engineered cell characterization and development. The solutions aim to bypass the costly, time-intensive process of anti-idiotype antibody creation while streamlining workflows for researchers.</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2025 14:49:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Accelerating and Enabling Consistency of Bioprocessing Scale-up</title><link>https://www.fiercebiotech.com/premium/webinar/1368685</link><description>Discover how to streamline bioprocessing scale-up for monoclonal antibody (mAb) production through media optimization, High-Intensity Perfusion (HIP) CHO solutions, and innovative bioreactor designs in an upcoming webinar featuring experts Vivian Ott and Maren Grun. The session will delve into strategies for enhancing manufacturing efficiency, sustainability, and rapid commercialization, supported by case studies on successful process intensification and scalable technologies.</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2025 19:38:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Priority Review Vouchers: By the Numbers</title><link>https://www.biospace.com/business/priority-review-vouchers-by-the-numbers</link><description>2024 set a record as the busiest year for FDA priority review vouchers, with 80 awarded across three agency programs, signaling heightened activity in pharmaceutical development. Companies have already invested $513 million this year in purchasing these vouchers, which accelerate regulatory reviews, underscoring their high value in strategic industry deals.</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2025 14:06:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>FDA Weathers Bait-and-Switch Storm as Staff and Sites Come and Go</title><link>https://www.biospace.com/fda/fda-weathers-bait-and-switch-storm-as-staff-and-sites-come-and-go</link><description>Marty Makary, poised to lead the FDA under a potential Trump administration, testified before Congress as the agency faces significant upheaval and policy reversals. The hearing highlighted ongoing turbulence within the FDA, with lawmakers scrutinizing its direction amid rapid organizational and regulatory shifts.</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2025 15:50:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>J&amp;J, Protagonist outline first IBD win for potential immunological blockbuster</title><link>https://endpts.com/jj-protagonist-outline-first-ibd-win-for-potential-immunological-blockbuster/</link><description>Johnson &amp; Johnson and Protagonist Therapeutics have partnered to develop an oral IL-23 drug, aiming to create a breakthrough immunology treatment. The companies announced progress toward this goal on Monday, signaling potential advancements in bringing the blockbuster drug candidate closer to market.</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 16:04:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mineralys’ Hypertension Drug Drops Blood Pressure in Phase II/III, Setting Up Market Clash</title><link>https://www.biospace.com/drug-development/mineralys-hypertension-drug-drops-blood-pressure-in-phase-ii-iii-setting-up-market-clash</link><description>Mineralys Therapeutics saw its stock surge over 50% after announcing successful Phase 2 trial results for its hypertension drug, which significantly reduced blood pressure in patients across two clinical studies. The promising data positions the therapy as a potential leader in the $30 billion hypertension market, heightening investor interest in the company’s future regulatory and commercial plans.</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 16:11:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>FDA blocks drug and device reviewers from taking HHS' buyout offer</title><link>https://endpts.com/fda-blocks-drug-and-device-reviewers-from-taking-hhs-buyout-offer/</link><description>The FDA has prohibited its medical product reviewers and manufacturing facility inspectors from accepting a recent HHS severance buyout offer worth up to $25,000, according to an internal Monday announcement. The decision blocks staff from accessing the voluntary exit package proposed just days earlier, halting potential workforce reductions in critical regulatory roles.</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 16:29:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Healthcare tackles AI oversight with no aid from Trump administration</title><link>https://www.biopharmadive.com/news/health-artificial-intelligence-governance-trump-standards/742208/</link><description>The president&amp;rsquo;s deregulatory agenda will mean more responsibility rests on healthcare stakeholders to get artificial intelligence right....</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 17:39:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The true cost of steroid-toxicity</title><link>https://www.drugdiscoverytrends.com/the-true-cost-of-steroid-toxicity/</link><description>Glucocorticoids, popular for their effectiveness in treating autoimmune disorders, provide quick relief by suppressing inflammation and immune activity. However, the article emphasizes the significant long-term costs associated with steroid toxicity, raising concerns about their prolonged use despite their initial affordability.</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 01:33:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Corrected: Merck opens billion-dollar US facility to make Gardasil</title><link>https://endpts.com/merck-opens-billion-dollar-facility-to-make-bladder-cancer-immunotherapy/</link><description>Merck has launched a new North Carolina-based manufacturing facility to produce HPV vaccines, including Gardasil and Gardasil 9, to meet rising global demand for cervical cancer prevention. The plant’s opening aligns with Merck’s strategy to expand production capacity amid increasing vaccine rollout efforts worldwide.</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 14:50:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Douglas Kelly, deputy science director at FDA’s device center, leaves agency</title><link>https://www.biopharmadive.com/news/douglas-kelly-fda-depart-cdrh-resign/742197/</link><description>Kelly, a key figure at the CDRH known for negotiating the latest user fee agreement and securing vital talent, announced his exit via LinkedIn, marking the end of a tenure marked by strategic deals and leadership hires. His departure shifts focus to future regulatory strategies, given his instrumental role in shaping critical agreements pivotal to the agency's operations.</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 15:05:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Merck opens $1B vaccine plant in North Carolina</title><link>https://www.biopharmadive.com/news/merck-manufacturing-north-carolina-vaccines/742146/</link><description>Merck has unveiled a new U.S. factory amid mounting pressure on pharmaceutical firms to reshore drug manufacturing to strengthen domestic supply chains. The move reflects a broader industry shift as companies aim to reduce reliance on overseas production and address regulatory and geopolitical risks.</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 17:15:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>How technology advances are helping scientists unlock the mysteries of zoonotic diseases</title><link>https://www.drugdiscoverytrends.com/how-technology-advances-are-helping-scientists-unlock-the-mysteries-of-zoonotic-diseases/</link><description>The World Health Organization has added 24 pathogens to its pandemic watchlist for 2024, including three zoonotic diseases: avian influenza, mpox (formerly monkeypox), and the Sin Nombre virus, which has a 30% fatality rate. This highlights the growing concern and scientific focus on zoonotic diseases that can transition from animals to humans.</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 17:27:25 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>