<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Immunology</title><link>https://nrouizem.github.io/test/immunology_feed.xml</link><description>Daily curated &amp; summarized biopharma news.</description><atom:link href="https://nrouizem.github.io/test/immunology_feed.xml" rel="self"/><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 01:19:25 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Avoiding aggregates: How new technology is helping mAb developers monitor a vital CQA</title><link>https://www.drugdiscoverytrends.com/avoiding-aggregates-how-new-technology-is-helping-mab-developers-monitor-a-vital-cqa/</link><description>The monoclonal antibodies (mAbs) market, currently valued over $330 billion, is projected to more than double by 2030, driven by a growing research pipeline. As developers tackle challenges like measuring critical quality attributes, innovative technologies are emerging to help monitor these vital factors effectively.</description><pubDate>Sat, 08 Feb 2025 19:54:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Rosnilimab phase 2b trial shows promise in treating RA</title><link>https://www.drugdiscoverytrends.com/rosnilimab-phase-2b-trial-shows-promise-in-treating-ra/</link><description>Rosnilimab, a new treatment targeting the PD-1 pathway, has shown promise in a phase 2b trial for rheumatoid arthritis by aiming to reset the immune system for better long-term remission. Unlike traditional therapies that often leave patients without sustained relief, rosnilimab offers a novel approach through the selective depletion of pathogenic cells.</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2025 14:07:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Solutions for CAR-Engineered Cell Characterization</title><link>https://www.fiercebiotech.com/resource/solutions-car-engineered-cell-characterization</link><description>Cell Signaling Technology (CST) has unveiled purpose-built tools, including recombinant antibodies targeting scFv linkers like G4S and Whitlow/218, to accelerate CAR-engineered cell characterization and development. The solutions aim to bypass the costly, time-intensive process of anti-idiotype antibody creation while streamlining workflows for researchers.</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2025 14:49:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Accelerating and Enabling Consistency of Bioprocessing Scale-up</title><link>https://www.fiercebiotech.com/premium/webinar/1368685</link><description>Discover how to streamline bioprocessing scale-up for monoclonal antibody (mAb) production through media optimization, High-Intensity Perfusion (HIP) CHO solutions, and innovative bioreactor designs in an upcoming webinar featuring experts Vivian Ott and Maren Grun. The session will delve into strategies for enhancing manufacturing efficiency, sustainability, and rapid commercialization, supported by case studies on successful process intensification and scalable technologies.</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2025 19:38:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>J&amp;J, Protagonist outline first IBD win for potential immunological blockbuster</title><link>https://endpts.com/jj-protagonist-outline-first-ibd-win-for-potential-immunological-blockbuster/</link><description>Johnson &amp; Johnson and Protagonist Therapeutics have partnered to develop an oral IL-23 drug, aiming to create a breakthrough immunology treatment. The companies announced progress toward this goal on Monday, signaling potential advancements in bringing the blockbuster drug candidate closer to market.</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 16:04:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The true cost of steroid-toxicity</title><link>https://www.drugdiscoverytrends.com/the-true-cost-of-steroid-toxicity/</link><description>Glucocorticoids, or steroids, remain the standard treatment for autoimmune disorders due to their rapid anti-inflammatory effects and low initial cost. However, a growing awareness of steroid toxicity highlights the long-term health risks and potential burdens on patients and healthcare systems.</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 01:33:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Corrected: Merck opens billion-dollar US facility to make Gardasil</title><link>https://endpts.com/merck-opens-billion-dollar-facility-to-make-bladder-cancer-immunotherapy/</link><description>Merck has launched a new North Carolina-based manufacturing facility to produce HPV vaccines, including Gardasil and Gardasil 9, to meet rising global demand for cervical cancer prevention. The plant’s opening aligns with Merck’s strategy to expand production capacity amid increasing vaccine rollout efforts worldwide.</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 14:50:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Agenus CMO touts immunotherapy advances on The Top Line</title><link>https://www.fiercebiotech.com/sponsored/agenus-cmo-touts-immunotherapy-advances-top-line</link><description>Agenus Chief Marketing Officer highlighted significant advancements in their immunotherapy pipeline during a recent appearance on The Top Line, emphasizing the company's commitment to innovative cancer treatments. The discussion included insights into upcoming clinical trials and potential partnerships aimed at enhancing their therapeutic offerings in the oncology space.</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 17:26:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>How technology advances are helping scientists unlock the mysteries of zoonotic diseases</title><link>https://www.drugdiscoverytrends.com/how-technology-advances-are-helping-scientists-unlock-the-mysteries-of-zoonotic-diseases/</link><description>In 2024, the World Health Organization expanded its pandemic watchlist to include 24 pathogens, with a focus on three new zoonotic diseases: avian influenza, mpox, and Sin Nombre virus, which has a 30% fatality rate. The article discusses how technological advancements are aiding scientists in understanding and addressing these infectious diseases.</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 17:27:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Advancing the Future of Biomarker-Driven Immunotherapy</title><link>https://www.fiercebiotech.com/premium/webinar/1369042</link><description>The upcoming webinar will delve into the DUTRENEO trial's findings on predictive biomarkers for neoadjuvant therapy in muscle-invasive bladder cancer, highlighting the potential of spatial biomarkers and multi-omics approaches. It aims to address challenges in patient stratification for immune checkpoint inhibitors and discuss implications for future clinical trial designs.</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2025 17:43:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Altimmune Jumps On Takeover Rumors After Launching Alcohol Use Disorder Study</title><link>https://www.biospace.com/business/altimmune-jumps-on-takeover-rumors-after-launching-alcohol-use-disorder-study</link><description>The company has announced it will test its GLP-1/glucagon dual receptor agonist for treating alcohol use disorder and alcohol-related liver disease. This innovative approach aims to address significant health challenges associated with excessive alcohol consumption.</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2025 12:44:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trispecific Antibodies Unlocking New Promises In Targeted Therapies</title><link>https://www.biospace.com/press-releases/trispecific-antibodies-unlocking-new-promises-in-targeted-therapies</link><description>Please provide the article you'd like me to summarize.</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 19:31:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Immunovant Will Drop One Myasthenia Gravis Asset, Continuing to Favor Another</title><link>https://www.biospace.com/drug-development/immunovant-will-drop-one-myasthenia-gravis-asset-continuing-to-favor-another</link><description>Analysts expressed satisfaction with batoclimab's efficacy in treating a chronic autoimmune disorder; however, Immunovant announced it will shift its focus to a different next-generation asset for this indication. This strategic pivot highlights the company's commitment to advancing its portfolio in autoimmune therapies.</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 15:33:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Immunovant claims study success for immune disease drug but holds off on submission</title><link>https://www.biopharmadive.com/news/immunovant-roivant-batoclimab-myasthenia-gravis-1402-data/742921/</link><description>The company is prioritizing the development of a next-generation drug as it concludes testing for batoclimab in thyroid eye disease. These advancements signal a strong commitment to enhancing treatment options in the pharmaceutical landscape.</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 15:45:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Blood cancers dominate CAR-T pipeline</title><link>https://www.pharmaceutical-technology.com/analyst-comment/blood-cancers-car-t-pipeline/</link><description>Gilead's Yescarta and Immuneel Therapeutics' Qartemi are among the 13 CAR-T therapeutics that have successfully gained regulatory approval. These advancements highlight significant progress in the development of innovative cancer treatments.</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2025 08:11:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Sanofi to pay $600M upfront for Dren Bio’s bispecific B cell depleter</title><link>https://endpts.com/sanofi-to-pay-600m-upfront-for-dren-bios-bispecific-b-cell-depleter/</link><description>Sanofi is acquiring a B cell-depleting antibody from Dren Bio for $600 million, aimed at treating cancer and autoimmune diseases. This strategic move underscores Sanofi's commitment to expanding its oncology and immunology portfolio.</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2025 10:31:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Monte Rosa reports first data for molecular glue program</title><link>https://endpts.com/monte-rosa-reports-first-data-for-molecular-glue-program/</link><description>Monte Rosa Therapeutics announced promising Phase 1 data for a program developed in partnership with Novartis, which aims to transform the treatment of immune-mediated diseases. The study, conducted with healthy volunteers, has garnered attention from industry observers for its potential impact.</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2025 11:47:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Sanofi signs $1.9bn deal to buy Dren Bio autoimmune drug</title><link>https://pharmaphorum.com/news/sanofi-signs-19bn-deal-buy-dren-bio-autoimmune-drug</link><description>Sanofi has acquired a drug from Dren Bio, marking its entry into the promising area of deep B-cell depletion technology for treating autoimmune diseases. This strategic move aims to enhance Sanofi's portfolio and address unmet needs in this therapeutic space.</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2025 12:08:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Sanofi wagers $600M on a dual-targeting antibody drug for autoimmune disease</title><link>https://www.biopharmadive.com/news/sanofi-dren-deal-bispecific-myeloid-cell-engager-autoimmune/743041/</link><description>Sanofi has acquired startup Dren Bio to gain access to its innovative myeloid cell engager, which is designed to compete with various treatments aimed at resetting immune systems for individuals with inflammatory conditions. This strategic move positions Sanofi to enhance its portfolio in the growing field of immunotherapy.</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2025 15:20:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>