<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Immunology</title><link>https://nrouizem.github.io/test/immunology_feed.xml</link><description>Daily curated &amp; summarized biopharma news.</description><atom:link href="https://nrouizem.github.io/test/immunology_feed.xml" rel="self"/><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 01:19:02 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Avoiding aggregates: How new technology is helping mAb developers monitor a vital CQA</title><link>https://www.drugdiscoverytrends.com/avoiding-aggregates-how-new-technology-is-helping-mab-developers-monitor-a-vital-cqa/</link><description>The monoclonal antibodies (mAbs) market is valued at over $330 billion and is projected to exceed $700 billion by 2030, with developers encountering challenges in monitoring critical quality attributes (CQAs). New technologies are emerging to help mAb developers effectively track and maintain these essential quality measures, particularly in preventing aggregates.</description><pubDate>Sat, 08 Feb 2025 19:54:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Rosnilimab phase 2b trial shows promise in treating RA</title><link>https://www.drugdiscoverytrends.com/rosnilimab-phase-2b-trial-shows-promise-in-treating-ra/</link><description>The phase 2b trial of rosnilimab demonstrates promise in treating rheumatoid arthritis by targeting the PD-1 pathway to reset the immune system and provide potential long-term remission. Unlike current therapies that often fall short, this novel approach aims to offer sustained relief for patients cycling through various treatments.</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2025 14:07:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Solutions for CAR-Engineered Cell Characterization</title><link>https://www.fiercebiotech.com/resource/solutions-car-engineered-cell-characterization</link><description>Cell Signaling Technology (CST) has unveiled purpose-built tools, including recombinant antibodies targeting scFv linkers like G4S and Whitlow/218, to accelerate CAR-engineered cell characterization and development. The solutions aim to bypass the costly, time-intensive process of anti-idiotype antibody creation while streamlining workflows for researchers.</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2025 14:49:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Accelerating and Enabling Consistency of Bioprocessing Scale-up</title><link>https://www.fiercebiotech.com/premium/webinar/1368685</link><description>Discover how to streamline bioprocessing scale-up for monoclonal antibody (mAb) production through media optimization, High-Intensity Perfusion (HIP) CHO solutions, and innovative bioreactor designs in an upcoming webinar featuring experts Vivian Ott and Maren Grun. The session will delve into strategies for enhancing manufacturing efficiency, sustainability, and rapid commercialization, supported by case studies on successful process intensification and scalable technologies.</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2025 19:38:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Arrowhead reveals small batch of open-label data for 'non-core' kidney drug</title><link>https://endpts.com/arrowhead-reveals-small-batch-of-open-label-data-for-non-core-kidney-drug/</link><description>Arrowhead Pharmaceuticals unveiled promising new open-label data from its ARO-C3 RNAi therapy program, showing potential to improve kidney disease outcomes by targeting complement pathways in a small study involving about a dozen patients. The early-stage results highlight the therapy's novel approach to addressing kidney disorders, though no partnerships or business deals related to the program were disclosed.</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 15:07:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>J&amp;J, Protagonist outline first IBD win for potential immunological blockbuster</title><link>https://endpts.com/jj-protagonist-outline-first-ibd-win-for-potential-immunological-blockbuster/</link><description>Johnson &amp; Johnson and Protagonist Therapeutics have partnered to develop an oral IL-23 drug, aiming to create a breakthrough immunology treatment. The companies announced progress toward this goal on Monday, signaling potential advancements in bringing the blockbuster drug candidate closer to market.</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 16:04:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The true cost of steroid-toxicity</title><link>https://www.drugdiscoverytrends.com/the-true-cost-of-steroid-toxicity/</link><description>Glucocorticoids are the standard treatment for autoimmune disorders due to their effectiveness in suppressing inflammation and immune activity. However, the article highlights the considerable long-term costs and toxicity associated with their use, which may impact patient health adversely.</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 01:33:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Agenus CMO touts immunotherapy advances on The Top Line</title><link>https://www.fiercebiotech.com/sponsored/agenus-cmo-touts-immunotherapy-advances-top-line</link><description>Agenus Chief Medical Officer highlighted significant advancements in immunotherapy during an appearance on The Top Line, emphasizing the company's commitment to innovative cancer treatments. The discussion also spotlighted Agenus’ strategic collaborations aimed at enhancing their pipeline and accelerating the development of novel therapies.</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 17:26:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>How technology advances are helping scientists unlock the mysteries of zoonotic diseases</title><link>https://www.drugdiscoverytrends.com/how-technology-advances-are-helping-scientists-unlock-the-mysteries-of-zoonotic-diseases/</link><description>In 2024, the World Health Organization added 24 pathogens to its pandemic watchlist, highlighting significant zoonotic threats such as avian influenza, mpox, and Sin Nombre virus, which poses a 30% fatality rate. The article discusses how technological advancements are aiding scientists in understanding these emerging zoonotic diseases.</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 17:27:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Amgen's Uplizna Deepens Response Against Myasthenia Gravis at 1 Year</title><link>https://www.biospace.com/drug-development/amgens-uplizna-deepens-response-against-myasthenia-gravis-at-1-year</link><description>Amgen is set to file a regulatory submission for Uplizna, which is currently approved for a rare ocular autoimmune disorder, for use in treating myasthenia gravis in the first half of 2025, buoyed by strong data. Analysts note this expansion could significantly enhance the drug's market potential.</description><pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2025 13:28:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Altimmune To Test Investigational GLP-1–Based Obesity Drug for Alcohol Use Disorder</title><link>https://www.biospace.com/drug-development/altimmune-to-test-investigational-glp-1-based-obesity-drug-for-alcohol-use-disorder</link><description>A Maryland-based biopharma is collaborating with Eli Lilly and Novo Nordisk to trial a GLP-1 agonist aimed at treating alcohol- and liver-related conditions. This partnership highlights the growing interest in innovative therapies for addressing these significant health issues.</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2025 14:29:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Advancing the Future of Biomarker-Driven Immunotherapy</title><link>https://www.fiercebiotech.com/premium/webinar/1369042</link><description>Join an exclusive webinar discussing the DUTRENEO trial's findings on predictive biomarkers for neoadjuvant therapy in muscle-invasive bladder cancer (MIBC), emphasizing the promise of spatial biomarkers and multi-omics in improving patient stratification. Experts will delve into the challenges of traditional biomarkers and the potential of innovative approaches to enhance therapeutic selection in future clinical trials.</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2025 17:43:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>5 CAR T Cell Therapies With Autoimmune Readouts in 2025</title><link>https://www.biospace.com/drug-development/5-car-t-cell-therapies-with-autoimmune-readouts-in-2025</link><description>Biopharmaceutical companies are expanding the application of CAR T therapies beyond cancer to target autoimmune disorders, with multiple early- to mid-stage trial results anticipated in the coming year. This strategic shift reflects the industry's commitment to innovating treatments for complex diseases.</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2025 04:01:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Altimmune Jumps On Takeover Rumors After Launching Alcohol Use Disorder Study</title><link>https://www.biospace.com/business/altimmune-jumps-on-takeover-rumors-after-launching-alcohol-use-disorder-study</link><description>The company announced its plans to initiate testing of a GLP-1/glucagon dual receptor agonist aimed at addressing alcohol use disorder and alcohol-related liver disease. This innovative approach could pave the way for new treatment options in these challenging health issues.</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2025 12:44:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>AstraZeneca adds ‘in vivo’ cell therapy capabilities with EsoBiotech deal</title><link>https://www.biopharmadive.com/news/astrazeneca-esobiotech-acquire-in-vivo-cell-therapy/742643/</link><description>A pharmaceutical company is acquiring a Belgian startup for up to $1 billion, recognizing the potential of its technology in the treatment of cancer and autoimmune conditions. This strategic move aims to enhance the company's capabilities in developing innovative therapies.</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2025 13:28:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Japan's RegCell raises $45.8M for Treg cell therapies, will move to US</title><link>https://endpts.com/japans-regcell-raises-45-8m-for-treg-cell-therapies-will-move-to-us/</link><description>Cell therapy biotech RegCell has secured $45.8 million in funding to advance its development of new cell therapies for autoimmune diseases by linking scientific innovations from Japan with the US biotech sector. This investment positions RegCell to enhance its research capabilities and potential impact within the industry.</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 12:00:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trispecific Antibodies Unlocking New Promises In Targeted Therapies</title><link>https://www.biospace.com/press-releases/trispecific-antibodies-unlocking-new-promises-in-targeted-therapies</link><description>Please provide the article you'd like me to summarize.</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 19:31:02 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>