<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Immunology</title><link>https://nrouizem.github.io/test/immunology_feed.xml</link><description>Daily curated &amp; summarized biopharma news.</description><atom:link href="https://nrouizem.github.io/test/immunology_feed.xml" rel="self"/><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2025 01:18:03 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Avoiding aggregates: How new technology is helping mAb developers monitor a vital CQA</title><link>https://www.drugdiscoverytrends.com/avoiding-aggregates-how-new-technology-is-helping-mab-developers-monitor-a-vital-cqa/</link><description>The monoclonal antibodies (mAbs) market, currently valued at over $330 billion, is set to more than double by 2030, driven by a growing research pipeline. Developers are increasingly focusing on measuring and maintaining critical quality attributes (CQAs), with new technology emerging to help monitor vital aspects, such as preventing aggregates.</description><pubDate>Sat, 08 Feb 2025 19:54:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Rosnilimab phase 2b trial shows promise in treating RA</title><link>https://www.drugdiscoverytrends.com/rosnilimab-phase-2b-trial-shows-promise-in-treating-ra/</link><description>The phase 2b trial of rosnilimab shows promise in treating rheumatoid arthritis (RA) by targeting the PD-1 pathway to reset the immune system and selectively deplete pathogenic cells. This novel approach could offer hope for patients struggling with long-term remission using current RA therapies.</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2025 14:07:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Solutions for CAR-Engineered Cell Characterization</title><link>https://www.fiercebiotech.com/resource/solutions-car-engineered-cell-characterization</link><description>Cell Signaling Technology (CST) has unveiled purpose-built tools, including recombinant antibodies targeting scFv linkers like G4S and Whitlow/218, to accelerate CAR-engineered cell characterization and development. The solutions aim to bypass the costly, time-intensive process of anti-idiotype antibody creation while streamlining workflows for researchers.</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2025 14:49:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Accelerating and Enabling Consistency of Bioprocessing Scale-up</title><link>https://www.fiercebiotech.com/premium/webinar/1368685</link><description>Discover how to streamline bioprocessing scale-up for monoclonal antibody (mAb) production through media optimization, High-Intensity Perfusion (HIP) CHO solutions, and innovative bioreactor designs in an upcoming webinar featuring experts Vivian Ott and Maren Grun. The session will delve into strategies for enhancing manufacturing efficiency, sustainability, and rapid commercialization, supported by case studies on successful process intensification and scalable technologies.</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2025 19:38:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Arrowhead reveals small batch of open-label data for 'non-core' kidney drug</title><link>https://endpts.com/arrowhead-reveals-small-batch-of-open-label-data-for-non-core-kidney-drug/</link><description>Arrowhead Pharmaceuticals unveiled promising new open-label data from its ARO-C3 RNAi therapy program, showing potential to improve kidney disease outcomes by targeting complement pathways in a small study involving about a dozen patients. The early-stage results highlight the therapy's novel approach to addressing kidney disorders, though no partnerships or business deals related to the program were disclosed.</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 15:07:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>J&amp;J, Protagonist outline first IBD win for potential immunological blockbuster</title><link>https://endpts.com/jj-protagonist-outline-first-ibd-win-for-potential-immunological-blockbuster/</link><description>Johnson &amp; Johnson and Protagonist Therapeutics have partnered to develop an oral IL-23 drug, aiming to create a breakthrough immunology treatment. The companies announced progress toward this goal on Monday, signaling potential advancements in bringing the blockbuster drug candidate closer to market.</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 16:04:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The true cost of steroid-toxicity</title><link>https://www.drugdiscoverytrends.com/the-true-cost-of-steroid-toxicity/</link><description>Glucocorticoids, often called steroids, remain the standard treatment for various autoimmune disorders due to their effectiveness in rapidly alleviating inflammation and symptoms. However, the long-term toxicity associated with their use may lead to significant hidden costs in patient management and healthcare systems.</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 01:33:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Corrected: Merck opens billion-dollar US facility to make Gardasil</title><link>https://endpts.com/merck-opens-billion-dollar-facility-to-make-bladder-cancer-immunotherapy/</link><description>Merck has launched a new North Carolina-based manufacturing facility to produce HPV vaccines, including Gardasil and Gardasil 9, to meet rising global demand for cervical cancer prevention. The plant’s opening aligns with Merck’s strategy to expand production capacity amid increasing vaccine rollout efforts worldwide.</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 14:50:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Agenus CMO touts immunotherapy advances on The Top Line</title><link>https://www.fiercebiotech.com/sponsored/agenus-cmo-touts-immunotherapy-advances-top-line</link><description>Agenus' Chief Medical Officer highlighted the company's recent advancements in immunotherapy during an appearance on "The Top Line," emphasizing the positive impact on patient treatment options. The update reflects Agenus' commitment to innovative cancer therapies and its ongoing research efforts in the field.</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 17:26:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>How technology advances are helping scientists unlock the mysteries of zoonotic diseases</title><link>https://www.drugdiscoverytrends.com/how-technology-advances-are-helping-scientists-unlock-the-mysteries-of-zoonotic-diseases/</link><description>In 2024, the World Health Organization added 24 pathogens to its pandemic watchlist, highlighting three zoonotic diseases: avian influenza, mpox (formerly monkeypox), and the Sin Nombre virus, which has a significant fatality rate. The article emphasizes how technological advancements are aiding scientists in understanding and combating these emerging health threats.</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 17:27:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Advancing the Future of Biomarker-Driven Immunotherapy</title><link>https://www.fiercebiotech.com/premium/webinar/1369042</link><description>Join an upcoming webinar on the DUTRENEO trial, highlighting innovative approaches in spatial biomarkers and multi-omics for improving patient stratification in neoadjuvant therapy for muscle-invasive bladder cancer. Experts will discuss the challenges of traditional biomarkers and the potential of integrating multi-modal strategies to enhance therapeutic selection in future clinical trials.</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2025 17:43:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>5 CAR T Cell Therapies With Autoimmune Readouts in 2025</title><link>https://www.biospace.com/drug-development/5-car-t-cell-therapies-with-autoimmune-readouts-in-2025</link><description>Biopharma is expanding the application of CAR T therapies from cancer treatments to targeting autoimmune disorders, with multiple early- to mid-stage results anticipated in the coming year. This strategic shift highlights the industry's ongoing innovation and commitment to addressing diverse medical challenges.</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2025 04:01:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Altimmune Jumps On Takeover Rumors After Launching Alcohol Use Disorder Study</title><link>https://www.biospace.com/business/altimmune-jumps-on-takeover-rumors-after-launching-alcohol-use-disorder-study</link><description>The company has announced plans to test its GLP-1/glucagon dual receptor agonist for treating alcohol use disorder and alcohol-related liver disease. This innovative approach aims to explore new therapeutic options for conditions associated with alcohol consumption.</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2025 12:44:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Japan's RegCell raises $45.8M for Treg cell therapies, will move to US</title><link>https://endpts.com/japans-regcell-raises-45-8m-for-treg-cell-therapies-will-move-to-us/</link><description>Cell therapy biotech RegCell has successfully raised $45.8 million to advance its efforts in developing new cell therapies for autoimmune conditions, aiming to connect Japanese scientific innovations with the US biotech sector. This funding includes $8.5 million in investments, positioning RegCell to enhance its research and development initiatives.</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 12:00:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trispecific Antibodies Unlocking New Promises In Targeted Therapies</title><link>https://www.biospace.com/press-releases/trispecific-antibodies-unlocking-new-promises-in-targeted-therapies</link><description>Please provide the article you'd like me to summarize.</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 19:31:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Updated: Immunovant will not take rare disease drug to regulators despite Phase 3 win</title><link>https://endpts.com/immunovant-will-not-take-immune-drug-to-regulators-despite-phase-3-success/</link><description>Immunovant has decided not to pursue approval for its candidate aimed at treating the autoimmune disorder myasthenia gravis (MG), despite positive results from its pivotal trial. The company announced this decision on Wednesday, indicating a shift in its clinical strategy.</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 11:56:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Immunovant Will Drop One Myasthenia Gravis Asset, Continuing to Favor Another</title><link>https://www.biospace.com/drug-development/immunovant-will-drop-one-myasthenia-gravis-asset-continuing-to-favor-another</link><description>Immunovant is shifting its focus to another next-generation asset for chronic autoimmune disorders, despite analysts expressing satisfaction with the performance of batoclimab. The company aims to leverage this new opportunity for growth and innovation in their product pipeline.</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 15:33:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Immunovant claims study success for immune disease drug but holds off on submission</title><link>https://www.biopharmadive.com/news/immunovant-roivant-batoclimab-myasthenia-gravis-1402-data/742921/</link><description>The company is actively progressing its next-generation drug as it completes testing for batoclimab in thyroid eye disease. This focus highlights their commitment to advancing innovative treatments in the healthcare sector.</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 15:45:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>