<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Oncology</title><link>https://nrouizem.github.io/test/oncology_feed.xml</link><description>Daily curated &amp; summarized biopharma news.</description><atom:link href="https://nrouizem.github.io/test/oncology_feed.xml" rel="self"/><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 01:19:02 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Landmark Bio’s mission to prevent cell therapy ‘do-overs’</title><link>https://www.drugdiscoverytrends.com/landmark-bios-mission-to-prevent-cell-therapy-do-overs/</link><description>Landmark Bio aims to guide biotech startups in avoiding common pitfalls in cell therapy by emphasizing the importance of planning for large-scale manufacturing before first-in-human trials. The company focuses on preventing costly setbacks and 'do-overs' in the development process, ensuring a smoother transition from research to clinical application.</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2025 15:58:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The FDA Fast-Tracked GNSC-001 gene therapy targets osteoarthritis at its root</title><link>https://www.drugdiscoverytrends.com/the-fda-fast-tracked-gnsc-001-gene-therapy-targets-osteoarthritis-at-its-root/</link><description>The FDA has fast-tracked GNSC-001, an innovative gene therapy aimed at addressing osteoarthritis, a condition impacting over 30 million Americans and imposing significant financial burdens on the healthcare system. This breakthrough treatment targets the root causes of the degenerative joint disease, representing a major advancement in its management.</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2025 19:16:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Flatiron Health sees shift from “what if” to “what is” in real-world evidence in oncology</title><link>https://www.drugdiscoverytrends.com/flatiron-health-sees-shift-from-what-if-to-what-is-in-real-world-evidence-in-oncology/</link><description>Flatiron Health is witnessing a transition in oncology from speculative discussions about AI's potential in healthcare to concrete applications, as skepticism fades in the wake of advancements like ChatGPT. This shift is reflected in their evolving approach to cancer care infrastructure and real-world evidence generation.</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2025 03:39:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Rosnilimab phase 2b trial shows promise in treating RA</title><link>https://www.drugdiscoverytrends.com/rosnilimab-phase-2b-trial-shows-promise-in-treating-ra/</link><description>The phase 2b trial of rosnilimab demonstrates promise in treating rheumatoid arthritis by targeting the PD-1 pathway to reset the immune system and provide potential long-term remission. Unlike current therapies that often fall short, this novel approach aims to offer sustained relief for patients cycling through various treatments.</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2025 14:07:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>COTA Healthcare announces AI milestone in real-world oncology data</title><link>https://www.drugdiscoverytrends.com/cota-healthcare-announces-ai-milestone-in-real-world-oncology-data/</link><description>COTA Healthcare has announced a significant advancement in real-world oncology data through the launch of its generative AI platform, which enhances the accuracy and profitability of large-scale cancer data curation. This breakthrough marks a transformative shift from earlier attempts to automate the labor-intensive process of real-world data abstraction in the oncology field.</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2025 19:00:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Q&amp;A: AnaptysBio’s CMO on rosnilimab’s ‘compelling’ phase 2b RA results</title><link>https://www.drugdiscoverytrends.com/qa-anaptysbios-cmo-on-rosnilimabs-compelling-phase-2b-ra-results/</link><description>AnaptysBio announced encouraging results from its Phase 2b RENOIR clinical trial for rosnilimab, with nearly 70% of participants achieving low disease activity by Week 14. The therapy met its primary endpoint, showing significant improvements in DAS28-CRP scores compared to placebo.</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2025 16:41:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>AstraZeneca Builds Stomach Cancer Case for Imfinzi With Strong Phase III Data</title><link>https://www.biospace.com/drug-development/astrazeneca-builds-stomach-cancer-case-for-imfinzi-with-strong-phase-iii-data</link><description>AstraZeneca's cancer drug Imfinzi is poised to drive significant growth in 2025, with regulators set to decide on its expanded use in treating stomach and bladder cancers. The blockbuster therapy generated over $4.7 billion in sales last year, cementing its role as a key revenue driver for the pharmaceutical giant.</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2025 13:58:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Roche launches new Boston center; NIH centralizes peer review</title><link>https://www.biopharmadive.com/news/roche-boston-center-nih-peer-review-pfizer-james-list/741901/</link><description>Swiss pharma giant Novartis announced plans to centralize its cardiometabolic drug research at a new Allston, Massachusetts, hub, signaling a strategic focus on heart and metabolic disease innovation. Meanwhile, AskBio progressed a mid-phase gene therapy trial, and Pfizer tapped a GLP-1 expert, intensifying competition in the weight-loss and diabetes therapeutics race.</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2025 16:20:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Multi-Modality Testing of EGFR</title><link>https://www.fiercebiotech.com/resource/multi-modality-testing-egfr</link><description>Neogenomics highlights its new white paper advocating a multi-modality testing approach to improve clinical trials, offering deeper insights into patient responses and treatment effectiveness. The sponsored resource, available for download, underscores how integrating diverse testing methods can advance oncology research and therapeutic outcomes.</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2025 18:04:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>How bluebird's buyout offer went from $100M upfront to $29M</title><link>https://endpts.com/how-bluebirds-buyout-offer-went-from-100m-upfront-to-29m/</link><description>Bluebird bio, once a gene therapy darling valued at $10 billion in 2018, was sold last month for just $29 million upfront in a fire sale, marking a dramatic fall amid sector struggles. The article hints at further challenges, noting “it almost…” but leaves the story unfinished, suggesting deeper turmoil or near-catastrophe in its trajectory.</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2025 18:25:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>FDA approves Neurotech therapy for rare eye disease</title><link>https://endpts.com/fda-approves-neurotech-therapy-for-rare-eye-disease/</link><description>The FDA approved Neurotech Pharmaceuticals’ first-of-its-kind cell therapy for macular telangiectasia type 2, a rare eye disease causing progressive central vision loss, marking a major advancement for patients with no prior treatment options. The therapy, which implants cells to repair retinal damage, could transform care for the condition, though the article does not mention specific business deals or partnerships related to its development.</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2025 19:57:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Sun Pharma to acquire Checkpoint Therapeutics and its anti-PD-L1 antibody</title><link>https://endpts.com/sun-pharma-to-acquire-checkpoint-therapeutics-and-its-anti-pd-l1-antibody/</link><description>Checkpoint Therapeutics has pivoted from seeking a partnership for its newly approved cancer drug to being acquired outright by India’s Sun Pharma in a strategic immuno-oncology expansion. The deal, valued at $4.10 per share, marks a swift exit for Checkpoint and reinforces Sun Pharma’s growing footprint in cutting-edge cancer therapies.</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 12:20:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Amgen, Kyowa Kirin’s Rocatinlimab Picks Up Steam With Late-Stage Atopic Dermatitis Win</title><link>https://www.biospace.com/drug-development/amgens-rocatinlimab-picks-up-steam-with-late-stage-atopic-dermatitis-win</link><description>"September 2024 trial results for rocatinlimab, an experimental antibody, drew mixed analyst reactions due to its underwhelming efficacy in treating a targeted condition. The lukewarm data sparked debate about the drug's future potential, with some holding out hope for protocol adjustments while others questioned its market viability."</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 13:57:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>J&amp;J’s Oral IL-23R Blocker Sets New Standard in Plaque Psoriasis, Beating BMS’ Sotyktu</title><link>https://www.biospace.com/drug-development/j-js-oral-il-23r-blocker-sets-new-standard-in-plaque-psoriasis-beating-bmss-sotyktu</link><description>New late-stage trial data reveals Johnson &amp; Johnson’s psoriasis drug icotrokinra outperformed Bristol Myers Squibb’s Sotyktu in clearing skin and reducing symptom severity for patients with plaque psoriasis. The findings could intensify competition in the dermatology treatment market, positioning J&amp;J’s therapy as a potential challenger in this therapeutic area.</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 14:03:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Arrowhead reveals small batch of open-label data for 'non-core' kidney drug</title><link>https://endpts.com/arrowhead-reveals-small-batch-of-open-label-data-for-non-core-kidney-drug/</link><description>Arrowhead Pharmaceuticals unveiled promising new open-label data from its ARO-C3 RNAi therapy program, showing potential to improve kidney disease outcomes by targeting complement pathways in a small study involving about a dozen patients. The early-stage results highlight the therapy's novel approach to addressing kidney disorders, though no partnerships or business deals related to the program were disclosed.</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 15:07:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mineralys shares climb on study data for blood pressure drug</title><link>https://www.biopharmadive.com/news/mineralys-lorundrostat-hypertension-study-results/742000/</link><description>New studies on Mineralys' hypertension treatment have validated the drug as a promising near-commercial product, with analysts hailing it as a "derisked, almost-commercial stage cardiometabolic asset." While no specific deals or partnerships were mentioned, the data bolsters the therapy’s market potential and positions it for future commercial opportunities.</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 15:30:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mineralys’ Hypertension Drug Drops Blood Pressure in Phase II/III, Setting Up Market Clash</title><link>https://www.biospace.com/drug-development/mineralys-hypertension-drug-drops-blood-pressure-in-phase-ii-iii-setting-up-market-clash</link><description>Mineralys Therapeutics saw its stock surge over 50% after announcing successful Phase 2 trial results for its hypertension drug, which significantly reduced blood pressure in patients across two clinical studies. The promising data positions the therapy as a potential leader in the $30 billion hypertension market, heightening investor interest in the company’s future regulatory and commercial plans.</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 16:11:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Beam shares promising first clinical data on gene editing treatment</title><link>https://endpts.com/beam-shares-promising-first-clinical-data-on-gene-editing-treatment/</link><description>Beam Therapeutics' experimental gene-editing therapy demonstrated promising results in a small trial, reducing mutant proteins linked to lung-damaging alpha-1 antitrypsin deficiency and boosting corrected protein levels in nine participants. The early data underscores the treatment's potential as a one-time fix for the genetic disorder, though the article does not mention any business deals, partnerships, or mergers.</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 16:42:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Novo’s Wegovy successor disappoints in second large trial</title><link>https://www.biopharmadive.com/news/novo-nordisk-cagrisema-study-results-diabetes-weight-loss/742008/</link><description>A recent study found that CagriSema, a weight-loss therapy for individuals with obesity and diabetes, demonstrated effectiveness in aiding weight loss but fell short of outperforming Eli Lilly’s rival drug Zepbound. While the results highlight CagriSema’s potential, they solidify Zepbound’s competitive edge in the burgeoning metabolic treatment market.</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 17:17:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Beam base editing therapy gets ‘proof of concept’ in rare lung disease</title><link>https://www.biopharmadive.com/news/beam-aatd-base-editing-initial-data-results-302/742015/</link><description>Beam Therapeutics' shares dropped sharply despite promising early study results showing its gene-editing technology could address the genetic cause of alpha-1 antitrypsin deficiency. The stock decline highlights investor concerns even as the company advances its innovative treatment potential.</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 17:25:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BioNTech's shares dip after posting lukewarm revenue guidance</title><link>https://endpts.com/biontechs-shares-dip-after-posting-lukewarm-revenue-guidance/</link><description>BioNTech shares fell 2% after projecting lower 2025 revenues, citing reduced COVID-19 vaccine demand and oversupply challenges despite a solid $4.2 billion revenue in 2023. The company plans to pivot toward advancing cancer treatments and cost-cutting measures while preparing for new vaccine launches to offset declining pandemic-related sales.</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 19:37:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Making Just-in-Time Oncology Trials Work: Overcoming Barriers and Unlocking Potential</title><link>https://www.fiercebiotech.com/premium/webinar/1368918</link><description>Just-in-time (JIT) oncology trials aim to accelerate research and improve patient access by activating trial sites only after identifying eligible patients, requiring strong collaboration between sponsors, sites, and IRBs to streamline processes and pre-negotiate agreements. An upcoming webinar will explore strategies like data-driven prescreening, standardized protocols, and centralized oversight to overcome operational barriers and expand the use of JIT trials in delivering faster, cost-effective cancer treatments.</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 19:50:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Virtual physical therapy startup Hinge Health files to go public</title><link>https://endpts.com/virtual-physical-therapy-startup-hinge-health-files-to-go-public/</link><description>Hinge Health, a virtual physical therapy startup focused on treating musculoskeletal issues and chronic pain through remote software, has filed for an IPO, ending a lull in digital health public offerings. The company aims to list on a stock exchange, marking a potential resurgence in investor confidence for the telehealth sector.</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 04:00:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bristol Myers buys out cell therapy partner 2seventy bio</title><link>https://endpts.com/bristol-myers-buys-out-cell-therapy-partner-2seventy-bio/</link><description>Bristol Myers Squibb has agreed to acquire 2seventy bio, its longtime partner in developing the CAR-T cell therapy Abecma for multiple myeloma, in a $286 million all-cash deal. The acquisition strengthens Bristol Myers' foothold in cancer therapies, building on the companies' existing collaboration aimed at advancing cutting-edge immunocellular treatments.</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 08:13:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Arvinas and Pfizer’s PROTAC vepdegestrant works in subset of breast cancer patients</title><link>https://endpts.com/arvinas-and-pfizers-protac-vepdegestrant-works-in-subset-of-breast-cancer-patients/</link><description>Arvinas and Pfizer's partnered experimental breast cancer drug, vepdegestrant, failed to outperform existing therapies in the Phase 3 VERITAC-2 trial, casting doubt on its competitive potential. The results highlight challenges for the collaboration’s aim to deliver a differentiated treatment in the crowded protein degrader landscape.</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 11:56:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Beam’s Gene Editor Achieves ‘First Ever’ Genetic Correction in AATD</title><link>https://www.biospace.com/drug-development/beams-gene-editor-achieves-first-ever-genetic-correction-in-aatd</link><description>William Blair analysts highlighted BEAM-302 as a breakthrough therapy, praising its superior efficacy in its sector in a recent investor note. While the report emphasized the drug's potential to redefine treatment standards, it did not mention any specific business deals, partnerships, or acquisitions related to the product.</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 13:52:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Pfizer, Arvinas Post Mixed Late-Stage Breast Cancer Data for Closely Watched PROTAC Drug</title><link>https://www.biospace.com/drug-development/pfizer-arvinas-post-mixed-late-stage-breast-cancer-data-for-closely-watched-protac-drug</link><description>Vepdegestrant’s mixed trial results—stalling on broad progression-free survival but showing promise in a niche patient group—sparked a 43% plunge in Arvinas’ stock, with analysts casting doubt on the drug's long-term viability. While no new deals were announced, the setback raises questions about the company’s ability to attract future partnerships or advance the drug’s commercial prospects.</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 14:08:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Corrected: Merck opens billion-dollar US facility to make Gardasil</title><link>https://endpts.com/merck-opens-billion-dollar-facility-to-make-bladder-cancer-immunotherapy/</link><description>Merck has launched a new North Carolina-based manufacturing facility to produce HPV vaccines, including Gardasil and Gardasil 9, to meet rising global demand for cervical cancer prevention. The plant’s opening aligns with Merck’s strategy to expand production capacity amid increasing vaccine rollout efforts worldwide.</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 14:50:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>2seventy bio, Bluebird’s cell therapy spinout, sells to Bristol Myers for less than $300M</title><link>https://www.biopharmadive.com/news/2seventy-bio-bristol-myers-deal-abecma-bluebird/742142/</link><description>2Seventy Bio's recent acquisition has terminated its brief stint as an independent firm, marking the end of a turbulent period marked by strategic restructuring and asset sales. The company, which shed research segments and saw its market value plummet by nearly 100%, now shifts focus under new ownership amid financial struggles.</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 16:05:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Arvinas gets positive breast cancer data, but finds differentiation a hard sell</title><link>https://www.biopharmadive.com/news/arvinas-pfizer-vepdegestrant-breast-cancer-data-veritac/742135/</link><description>Arvinas and Pfizer's partnered breast cancer drug, vepdegestrant, showed promising results in a specific patient subgroup compared to fulvestrant, though it didn't meet overall trial goals. The mixed outcomes highlight the experimental therapy's potential niche benefits while underscoring the challenges of broad efficacy in cancer treatment.</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 16:45:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Viking inks CordenPharma deal to boost obesity drug supply</title><link>https://www.biopharmadive.com/news/viking-cordenpharma-obesity-drug-manufacturing-deal/742139/</link><description>A biotech firm is investing $150 million in a strategic alliance to secure expanded production capacity for a high-profile weight-loss therapy, positioning itself to meet soaring demand. The partnership underscores the company’s aggressive push to capitalize on the competitive but rapidly growing market for obesity treatments.</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 17:25:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Agenus CMO touts immunotherapy advances on The Top Line</title><link>https://www.fiercebiotech.com/sponsored/agenus-cmo-touts-immunotherapy-advances-top-line</link><description>Agenus Chief Medical Officer highlighted significant advancements in immunotherapy during an appearance on The Top Line, emphasizing the company's commitment to innovative cancer treatments. The discussion also spotlighted Agenus’ strategic collaborations aimed at enhancing their pipeline and accelerating the development of novel therapies.</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 17:26:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Advancing the Future of Biomarker-Driven Immunotherapy</title><link>https://www.fiercebiotech.com/premium/webinar/1369042</link><description>Join an exclusive webinar discussing the DUTRENEO trial's findings on predictive biomarkers for neoadjuvant therapy in muscle-invasive bladder cancer (MIBC), emphasizing the promise of spatial biomarkers and multi-omics in improving patient stratification. Experts will delve into the challenges of traditional biomarkers and the potential of innovative approaches to enhance therapeutic selection in future clinical trials.</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2025 17:43:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>5 CAR T Cell Therapies With Autoimmune Readouts in 2025</title><link>https://www.biospace.com/drug-development/5-car-t-cell-therapies-with-autoimmune-readouts-in-2025</link><description>Biopharmaceutical companies are expanding the application of CAR T therapies beyond cancer to target autoimmune disorders, with multiple early- to mid-stage trial results anticipated in the coming year. This strategic shift reflects the industry's commitment to innovating treatments for complex diseases.</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2025 04:01:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>AstraZeneca spotlights first-in-human data for B7-H4-targeting ADC in endometrial cancer</title><link>https://endpts.com/astrazeneca-reveals-first-in-human-data-for-b7-h4-targeting-adc-in-endometrial-cancer/</link><description>AstraZeneca is refining plans for a Phase 3 study of its B7-H4-targeting antibody-drug conjugate (ADC) following positive response and survival outcomes in endometrial cancer patients from an early-stage trial. This progression highlights the company's commitment to advancing its oncology pipeline amid promising results.</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2025 11:20:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Otsuka's Taiho buys Swiss startup Araris with three ADCs nearing the clinic</title><link>https://endpts.com/otsukas-taiho-buys-swiss-startup-araris-with-three-adcs-nearing-the-clinic/</link><description>Otsuka's subsidiary is acquiring a small Swiss drug developer known for its promising pipeline of three antibody-drug conjugates aimed at advancing oncology research and development. This strategic acquisition highlights the growing interest and investment in innovative cancer treatments.</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2025 11:30:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>AstraZeneca adds ‘in vivo’ cell therapy capabilities with EsoBiotech deal</title><link>https://www.biopharmadive.com/news/astrazeneca-esobiotech-acquire-in-vivo-cell-therapy/742643/</link><description>A pharmaceutical company is acquiring a Belgian startup for up to $1 billion, recognizing the potential of its technology in the treatment of cancer and autoimmune conditions. This strategic move aims to enhance the company's capabilities in developing innovative therapies.</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2025 13:28:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Orca Bio's T cell therapy may help blood cancer patients avoid transplant issues</title><link>https://endpts.com/orca-bios-t-cell-therapy-may-help-blood-cancer-patients-avoid-transplant-issues/</link><description>Orca Bio announced that its T cell therapy significantly decreases the risk of complications associated with bone marrow transplants in patients with specific blood cancers. This breakthrough positions Orca Bio as a promising player in the field of cancer treatment, highlighting the potential of its innovative approach.</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2025 15:16:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Orca Bio to seek approval of T cell transplant after positive trial data</title><link>https://www.biopharmadive.com/news/orca-bio-t-cell-therapy-transplant-aml-study-results/742667/</link><description>Orca's innovative treatment, which combines purified donor-derived T cells and stem cells, demonstrated a safer alternative to standard transplants for certain blood cancers. These promising results highlight the potential for improving patient outcomes in oncology.</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2025 15:30:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Taiho buys Swiss biotech and its ADC tech for $400M</title><link>https://www.biopharmadive.com/news/taiho-araris-acquire-antibody-drug-conjugate-adc-linker/742666/</link><description>The pharma company has announced its acquisition of Araris Biotech to enhance its portfolio with three preclinical antibody-drug conjugates (ADCs) and a linking technology that Araris touts as superior to current platforms. This strategic move signifies the company's commitment to advancing its capabilities in targeted cancer therapies.</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2025 16:13:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>AstraZeneca inks deal with Alteogen for subcutaneous cancer drugs</title><link>https://endpts.com/astrazeneca-inks-deal-with-alteogen-for-subcutaneous-cancer-drugs/</link><description>AstraZeneca is investing approximately $1.35 billion in South Korean biotech Alteogen to advance the development of under-the-skin formulations for various oncology treatments. The deal includes the licensing of ALT-B4, a compound designed to enhance drug delivery through a specialized enzyme.</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2025 19:40:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>How Proscia is using AI embeddings to transform drug discovery in pathology</title><link>https://www.drugdiscoverytrends.com/how-proscia-is-using-ai-embeddings-to-transform-drug-discovery-in-pathology/</link><description>Proscia is employing AI-powered pathology analysis to revolutionize drug discovery by identifying patients who would benefit from a lung cancer drug candidate once on the brink of abandonment. Their algorithm, developed in collaboration with two sponsors, utilizes machine learning to differentiate between responders and non-responders, showcasing the potential of digital pathology in pharmaceutical development.</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2025 20:43:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CRISPR startup Arbor Biotechnologies raises $73.9M as it nears first trial</title><link>https://endpts.com/crispr-startup-arbor-raises-73-9m-as-it-nears-first-trial/</link><description>Arbor Biotechnologies has secured $73.9 million in Series C financing to advance its first therapy into clinical trials, aimed at preventing disease. Founded by CRISPR pioneer Feng Zhang, the startup is poised to make significant strides in the biopharmaceutical sector.</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 10:30:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>AstraZeneca buys cell therapy biotech for up to $1bn</title><link>https://pharmaphorum.com/news/astrazeneca-buys-cell-therapy-biotech-1bn</link><description>AstraZeneca is set to acquire the Belgian in vivo cell therapy biotech EsoBiotec and has announced two licensing agreements with drug delivery company Alteogen. These strategic moves aim to enhance AstraZeneca's capabilities in innovative therapies and drug delivery solutions.</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 10:30:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Japan's RegCell raises $45.8M for Treg cell therapies, will move to US</title><link>https://endpts.com/japans-regcell-raises-45-8m-for-treg-cell-therapies-will-move-to-us/</link><description>Cell therapy biotech RegCell has secured $45.8 million in funding to advance its development of new cell therapies for autoimmune diseases by linking scientific innovations from Japan with the US biotech sector. This investment positions RegCell to enhance its research capabilities and potential impact within the industry.</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 12:00:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Sixteen-year-old dies after receiving Sarepta’s Duchenne therapy Elevidys</title><link>https://endpts.com/sixteen-year-old-dies-after-receiving-sareptas-duchenne-therapy-elevidys/</link><description>Sarepta's Duchenne muscular dystrophy gene therapy, Elevidys, has come under scrutiny following the death of a 16-year-old boy from liver failure after receiving the treatment. The company reported the incident on Tuesday, highlighting the ongoing challenges and risks associated with gene therapies.</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 13:21:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EnteroBiotix cues up larger trial of microbiome IBS therapy</title><link>https://pharmaphorum.com/news/enterobiotix-cues-larger-trial-microbiome-ibs-therapy</link><description>EnteroBiotix has announced positive phase 2a proof-of-concept results for its innovative therapy targeting irritable bowel syndrome (IBS), leveraging gut microbiome species. This promising data is a significant step towards advancing treatment options for IBS patients.</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 13:37:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Sarepta Shares Crash 22% After Patient on DMD Gene Therapy Elevidys Dies</title><link>https://www.biospace.com/drug-development/sarepta-shares-crash-22-after-patient-on-dmd-gene-therapy-elevidys-dies</link><description>Sarepta Therapeutics announced that it will update the label for its Duchenne muscular dystrophy gene therapy, Elevydis, following the death of a patient due to liver injury associated with the treatment. The company aims to enhance transparency regarding safety signals in light of this incident.</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 14:00:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Duchenne patient dies after receiving Sarepta gene therapy</title><link>https://www.biopharmadive.com/news/sarepta-elevidys-duchenne-gene-therapy-death-liver-failure/742765/</link><description>A young man who received treatment with Elevidys has died from acute liver failure, raising concerns among analysts about the safety of the drug. This incident may lead medical professionals to reconsider prescribing this treatment in the future.</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 14:20:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Sofinnova’s latest biotech fund sprouts three new startups</title><link>https://www.biopharmadive.com/news/sofinnova-fund-startups-bioclec-signadori-forth/742816/</link><description>Sofinnova is investing in startups focused on developing innovative treatments for fibrosis, cancer, and Alzheimer's as part of its broader pan-European strategy. This initiative aims to enhance healthcare solutions across the continent by supporting emerging companies in these critical therapeutic areas.</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 15:50:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trispecific Antibodies Unlocking New Promises In Targeted Therapies</title><link>https://www.biospace.com/press-releases/trispecific-antibodies-unlocking-new-promises-in-targeted-therapies</link><description>Please provide the article you'd like me to summarize.</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 19:31:02 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>