<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Oncology</title><link>https://nrouizem.github.io/test/oncology_feed.xml</link><description>Daily curated &amp; summarized biopharma news.</description><atom:link href="https://nrouizem.github.io/test/oncology_feed.xml" rel="self"/><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2025 01:49:09 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>How atogepant trials are capturing migraine’s real-world impact</title><link>https://www.drugdiscoverytrends.com/how-atogepant-trials-are-capturing-migraines-real-world-impact/</link><description>Recent studies on atogepant are illustrating the fluctuating nature of migraines and how traditional clinical trials may overlook the complex, real-world experiences of patients. By capturing the dynamic aspects of migraine occurrences, these trials aim to improve treatment understandings and outcomes.</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2025 01:30:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>How 3T Biosciences’ platform targets immunologically cold solid tumors</title><link>https://www.drugdiscoverytrends.com/3t-biosciences-targeted-strategy-for-mss-colorectal-cancer/</link><description>Immunotherapy resistance in solid tumors, particularly microsatellite stable colorectal cancer (MSS CRC), poses a major challenge in oncology, as over 90% of MSS CRC cases show limited response to current checkpoint inhibitor therapies. The article highlights how 3T Biosciences’ innovative platform aims to address this issue by targeting immunologically cold solid tumors.</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 05:12:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>How Capsida’s unconventional funding strategy and capsid technology promise to reshape CNS treatments</title><link>https://www.drugdiscoverytrends.com/how-capsidas-unconventional-funding-strategy-and-capsid-technology-promise-to-reshape-cns-treatments/</link><description>Capsida Biotherapeutics revealed that its partner AbbVie will exercise its option on their neurodegenerative disease program, resulting in a $40 million license payment. The startup has gained significant funding through strategic partnerships with Big Pharma, setting the stage for innovative advancements in CNS treatments.</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 21:05:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Landmark Bio’s mission to prevent cell therapy ‘do-overs’</title><link>https://www.drugdiscoverytrends.com/landmark-bios-mission-to-prevent-cell-therapy-do-overs/</link><description>Biotech startups often find themselves trapped in a cycle of repeating mistakes by hastily moving to first-in-human trials without adequate plans for large-scale manufacturing, much like the classic film Groundhog Day. Landmark Bio aims to break this cycle by helping these companies avoid costly 'do-overs' in cell therapy development.</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2025 15:58:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The FDA Fast-Tracked GNSC-001 gene therapy targets osteoarthritis at its root</title><link>https://www.drugdiscoverytrends.com/the-fda-fast-tracked-gnsc-001-gene-therapy-targets-osteoarthritis-at-its-root/</link><description>The FDA has fast-tracked GNSC-001, a groundbreaking gene therapy designed to address osteoarthritis at its source, responding to a significant unmet medical need affecting over 30 million Americans. This innovative treatment aims to reduce the substantial $459.5 billion burden on the healthcare system caused by this degenerative joint disease.</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2025 19:16:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Flatiron Health sees shift from “what if” to “what is” in real-world evidence in oncology</title><link>https://www.drugdiscoverytrends.com/flatiron-health-sees-shift-from-what-if-to-what-is-in-real-world-evidence-in-oncology/</link><description>Flatiron Health is shifting its focus in AI for healthcare from speculation to tangible outcomes, as head of outcomes research Blythe Adamson notes a decreased skepticism in the wake of advancements like ChatGPT. This change reflects a broader trend in oncology where real-world evidence is increasingly being utilized to enhance cancer care infrastructure.</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2025 03:39:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Rosnilimab phase 2b trial shows promise in treating RA</title><link>https://www.drugdiscoverytrends.com/rosnilimab-phase-2b-trial-shows-promise-in-treating-ra/</link><description>A phase 2b trial for rosnilimab, a novel treatment for rheumatoid arthritis (RA), shows promise by targeting the PD-1 pathway to help reset the immune system and potentially provide long-term remission for patients. This new approach aims to address the limitations of current therapies that often leave patients without sustained relief.</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2025 14:07:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>COTA Healthcare announces AI milestone in real-world oncology data</title><link>https://www.drugdiscoverytrends.com/cota-healthcare-announces-ai-milestone-in-real-world-oncology-data/</link><description>COTA Healthcare has announced a significant breakthrough in real-world oncology data through its new generative AI platform, which promises to enhance the accuracy and profitability of cancer data curation. This development marks a pivotal shift in the industry’s approach to automating cancer data abstraction.</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2025 19:00:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Successful Scale-Up Of An Upstream Viral Vector Process Using An Adherent Platform</title><link>https://www.fiercebiotech.com/premium/webinar/1368645</link><description>Cytiva's webinar, featuring Brian Gardell, explores scaling challenges in viral vector manufacturing for cell and gene therapies, emphasizing the need for cost-effective, standardized processes to meet clinical demand. The session highlights a case study on successfully scaling a helper-dependent adenovirus (HDAd) production process from bench optimization to commercial readiness using adherent culture platforms.</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2025 16:40:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Q&amp;A: AnaptysBio’s CMO on rosnilimab’s ‘compelling’ phase 2b RA results</title><link>https://www.drugdiscoverytrends.com/qa-anaptysbios-cmo-on-rosnilimabs-compelling-phase-2b-ra-results/</link><description>AnaptysBio has reported promising results from its Phase 2b RENOIR clinical trial for the investigational therapy rosnilimab, with nearly 70% of participants showing low disease activity by Week 14. The study successfully met its primary endpoint, demonstrating significant efficacy compared to placebo, but the article does not mention any business deals or partnerships.</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2025 16:41:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Accelerating and Enabling Consistency of Bioprocessing Scale-up</title><link>https://www.fiercebiotech.com/premium/webinar/1368685</link><description>Discover how to streamline bioprocessing scale-up for monoclonal antibody (mAb) production through media optimization, High-Intensity Perfusion (HIP) CHO solutions, and innovative bioreactor designs in an upcoming webinar featuring experts Vivian Ott and Maren Grun. The session will delve into strategies for enhancing manufacturing efficiency, sustainability, and rapid commercialization, supported by case studies on successful process intensification and scalable technologies.</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2025 19:38:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Finding Patients, Closing Treatment Gaps, and Building Better Messaging through AI and Real-World Data</title><link>https://www.fiercebiotech.com/premium/webinar/1368842</link><description>OM1's upcoming webinar, featuring experts Joseph Zabinski and Kathryn Starzyk, explores how AI-driven digital phenotyping and real-world data can help pharmaceutical teams identify underserved patient populations and align therapies with unmet clinical needs. The session will demonstrate strategies to bridge treatment gaps, refine market messaging, and ensure therapies reach overlooked communities through advanced analytics.</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 20:09:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>J&amp;J Axes Late-Stage Depression Trial After Underwhelming Efficacy</title><link>https://www.biospace.com/drug-development/j-j-axes-late-stage-depression-trial-after-underwhelming-efficacy</link><description>Despite aticaprant's Phase III setback, analysts say J&amp;J's neuroscience strategy remains intact, bolstered by its recent $14.6 billion acquisition of Intra-Cellular Therapeutics. The company’s confidence is further reinforced by the continued success of Spravato, its treatment for resistant depression, positioning it to maintain momentum in the sector.</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2025 13:46:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>AstraZeneca Builds Stomach Cancer Case for Imfinzi With Strong Phase III Data</title><link>https://www.biospace.com/drug-development/astrazeneca-builds-stomach-cancer-case-for-imfinzi-with-strong-phase-iii-data</link><description>AstraZeneca's cancer drug Imfinzi is poised to drive significant growth in 2025, with regulators set to decide on its expanded use in treating stomach and bladder cancers. The blockbuster therapy generated over $4.7 billion in sales last year, cementing its role as a key revenue driver for the pharmaceutical giant.</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2025 13:58:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>At $300M Kardigan startup, former MyoKardia team unveils its first drug, and it comes from Ionis</title><link>https://endpts.com/at-300m-kardigan-startup-former-myokardia-team-unveils-its-first-drug-and-it-comes-from-ionis/</link><description>Former MyoKardia executives launched a heart health biotech startup with $300 million in funding, leveraging undisclosed partnerships to secure in-licensed clinical-stage assets for cardiac therapies. The stealth-mode company remains tight-lipped about specific deals but signals a focus on advancing innovative treatments, attracting attention for its seasoned leadership and strategic collaborations.</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2025 16:16:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Roche launches new Boston center; NIH centralizes peer review</title><link>https://www.biopharmadive.com/news/roche-boston-center-nih-peer-review-pfizer-james-list/741901/</link><description>Swiss pharma giant Novartis announced plans to centralize its cardiometabolic drug research at a new Allston, Massachusetts, hub, signaling a strategic focus on heart and metabolic disease innovation. Meanwhile, AskBio progressed a mid-phase gene therapy trial, and Pfizer tapped a GLP-1 expert, intensifying competition in the weight-loss and diabetes therapeutics race.</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2025 16:20:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>J&amp;J scraps depression testing for potential blockbuster drug</title><link>https://www.biopharmadive.com/news/johnson-depression-studies-discontinue-aticaprant-neumora/741922/</link><description>A recent decision has dealt a "big blow" to a promising class of brain therapies, including Johnson &amp; Johnson’s experimental drug aticaprant and Neumora Therapeutics’ candidate, casting uncertainty over their development. While the article highlights setbacks for these specific treatments, it does not mention any new business deals, partnerships, or acquisitions related to the companies involved.</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2025 17:08:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Multi-Modality Testing of EGFR</title><link>https://www.fiercebiotech.com/resource/multi-modality-testing-egfr</link><description>Neogenomics highlights its new white paper advocating a multi-modality testing approach to improve clinical trials, offering deeper insights into patient responses and treatment effectiveness. The sponsored resource, available for download, underscores how integrating diverse testing methods can advance oncology research and therapeutic outcomes.</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2025 18:04:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>How bluebird's buyout offer went from $100M upfront to $29M</title><link>https://endpts.com/how-bluebirds-buyout-offer-went-from-100m-upfront-to-29m/</link><description>Bluebird bio, once a gene therapy darling valued at $10 billion in 2018, was sold last month for just $29 million upfront in a fire sale, marking a dramatic fall amid sector struggles. The article hints at further challenges, noting “it almost…” but leaves the story unfinished, suggesting deeper turmoil or near-catastrophe in its trajectory.</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2025 18:25:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>FDA approves Neurotech therapy for rare eye disease</title><link>https://endpts.com/fda-approves-neurotech-therapy-for-rare-eye-disease/</link><description>The FDA approved Neurotech Pharmaceuticals’ first-of-its-kind cell therapy for macular telangiectasia type 2, a rare eye disease causing progressive central vision loss, marking a major advancement for patients with no prior treatment options. The therapy, which implants cells to repair retinal damage, could transform care for the condition, though the article does not mention specific business deals or partnerships related to its development.</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2025 19:57:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Sun Pharma to acquire Checkpoint Therapeutics and its anti-PD-L1 antibody</title><link>https://endpts.com/sun-pharma-to-acquire-checkpoint-therapeutics-and-its-anti-pd-l1-antibody/</link><description>Checkpoint Therapeutics has pivoted from seeking a partnership for its newly approved cancer drug to being acquired outright by India’s Sun Pharma in a strategic immuno-oncology expansion. The deal, valued at $4.10 per share, marks a swift exit for Checkpoint and reinforces Sun Pharma’s growing footprint in cutting-edge cancer therapies.</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 12:20:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Novo Nordisk’s CagriSema shows 15.7% weight loss in second pivotal trial</title><link>https://endpts.com/novo-nordisks-cagrisema-shows-15-7-weight-loss-in-second-pivotal-trial/</link><description>Novo Nordisk announced Monday that its drug CagriSema achieved 15.7% weight loss in patients with obesity and type 2 diabetes after over a year of use, marking a potential advancement in dual-treatment therapies. The result underscores the drug’s efficacy in addressing these interconnected conditions, positioning it as a promising contender in the competitive metabolic health market.</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 12:21:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>J&amp;J’s Oral IL-23R Blocker Sets New Standard in Plaque Psoriasis, Beating BMS’ Sotyktu</title><link>https://www.biospace.com/drug-development/j-js-oral-il-23r-blocker-sets-new-standard-in-plaque-psoriasis-beating-bmss-sotyktu</link><description>New late-stage trial data reveals Johnson &amp; Johnson’s psoriasis drug icotrokinra outperformed Bristol Myers Squibb’s Sotyktu in clearing skin and reducing symptom severity for patients with plaque psoriasis. The findings could intensify competition in the dermatology treatment market, positioning J&amp;J’s therapy as a potential challenger in this therapeutic area.</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 14:03:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BMS’ Sotyktu Notches Phase III Win in Psoriatic Arthritis</title><link>https://www.biospace.com/drug-development/bms-sotyktu-notches-phase-iii-win-in-psoriatic-arthritis</link><description>In the plaque psoriasis market, Sotyktu is locked in a competitive battle with Amgen’s Otezla while bracing for new rivalry from Alumis’ investigational TYK2 inhibitor. The intensifying competition underscores the dynamic landscape of psoriasis treatments as emerging therapies threaten to disrupt established players.</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 14:07:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Novo Dips After CagriSema’s Latest Lower-Than-Expected Weight Loss Readout</title><link>https://www.biospace.com/drug-development/novo-dips-after-cagrisemas-latest-lower-than-expected-weight-loss-readout</link><description>New clinical trial results revealed CagriSema, a weight-loss drug from Novo, achieved 15.7% weight reduction in diabetic patients over 68 weeks but delivered a disappointing 22.7% in non-diabetic patients by December 2024, falling short of the company’s projected 25% efficacy. The underwhelming performance in non-diabetic trials raises questions about the drug’s competitive edge in the crowded obesity treatment market.</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 14:14:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Arrowhead reveals small batch of open-label data for 'non-core' kidney drug</title><link>https://endpts.com/arrowhead-reveals-small-batch-of-open-label-data-for-non-core-kidney-drug/</link><description>Arrowhead Pharmaceuticals unveiled promising new open-label data from its ARO-C3 RNAi therapy program, showing potential to improve kidney disease outcomes by targeting complement pathways in a small study involving about a dozen patients. The early-stage results highlight the therapy's novel approach to addressing kidney disorders, though no partnerships or business deals related to the program were disclosed.</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 15:07:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mineralys shares climb on study data for blood pressure drug</title><link>https://www.biopharmadive.com/news/mineralys-lorundrostat-hypertension-study-results/742000/</link><description>New studies on Mineralys' hypertension treatment have validated the drug as a promising near-commercial product, with analysts hailing it as a "derisked, almost-commercial stage cardiometabolic asset." While no specific deals or partnerships were mentioned, the data bolsters the therapy’s market potential and positions it for future commercial opportunities.</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 15:30:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trevi Therapeutics stock soars on Phase 2a chronic cough data</title><link>https://endpts.com/trevi-therapeutics-stock-soars-on-phase-2a-chronic-cough-data/</link><description>Trevi Therapeutics' chronic cough drug demonstrated a 57% reduction in 24-hour cough frequency versus placebo in a Phase 2a trial, outperforming investor expectations and sparking a 40% surge in its stock ($TRVI) at market open. The breakthrough underscores the treatment’s potential and has ignited optimism among investors about the company’s clinical and commercial prospects.</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 15:51:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>J&amp;J, Protagonist outline first IBD win for potential immunological blockbuster</title><link>https://endpts.com/jj-protagonist-outline-first-ibd-win-for-potential-immunological-blockbuster/</link><description>Johnson &amp; Johnson and Protagonist Therapeutics have partnered to develop an oral IL-23 drug, aiming to create a breakthrough immunology treatment. The companies announced progress toward this goal on Monday, signaling potential advancements in bringing the blockbuster drug candidate closer to market.</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 16:04:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mineralys’ Hypertension Drug Drops Blood Pressure in Phase II/III, Setting Up Market Clash</title><link>https://www.biospace.com/drug-development/mineralys-hypertension-drug-drops-blood-pressure-in-phase-ii-iii-setting-up-market-clash</link><description>Mineralys Therapeutics saw its stock surge over 50% after announcing successful Phase 2 trial results for its hypertension drug, which significantly reduced blood pressure in patients across two clinical studies. The promising data positions the therapy as a potential leader in the $30 billion hypertension market, heightening investor interest in the company’s future regulatory and commercial plans.</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 16:11:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>#AAD25 roundup: Data from Amgen, Bristol Myers, J&amp;J, Alumis and more</title><link>https://endpts.com/aad25-roundup-data-from-amgen-bristol-myers-jj-alumis-and-more/</link><description>At the American Academy of Dermatology annual meeting, key players like Amgen, Bristol Myers Squibb, Alumis, and Kyowa Kirin spotlighted updates on their dermatology drug pipelines, though no mergers or acquisitions were highlighted. The event emphasized breakthroughs in treatments for conditions like psoriasis and eczema, showcasing the industry’s focus on advancing innovative therapies for skin diseases.</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 16:37:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Deep Dive: Cardiovascular Disease Back in the Spotlight</title><link>https://www.biospace.com/drug-development/deep-dive-cardiovascular-disease-back-in-the-spotlight</link><description>BioSpace highlights the rapid evolution of emerging therapeutic modalities, from gene editing to cell therapies, as biotech and pharma companies race to innovate in a competitive market. The article underscores the intensifying battles for dominance in this space, with advancements poised to reshape treatment paradigms and spur significant industry growth.</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 16:40:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Beam shares promising first clinical data on gene editing treatment</title><link>https://endpts.com/beam-shares-promising-first-clinical-data-on-gene-editing-treatment/</link><description>Beam Therapeutics' experimental gene-editing therapy demonstrated promising results in a small trial, reducing mutant proteins linked to lung-damaging alpha-1 antitrypsin deficiency and boosting corrected protein levels in nine participants. The early data underscores the treatment's potential as a one-time fix for the genetic disorder, though the article does not mention any business deals, partnerships, or mergers.</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 16:42:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Novo’s Wegovy successor disappoints in second large trial</title><link>https://www.biopharmadive.com/news/novo-nordisk-cagrisema-study-results-diabetes-weight-loss/742008/</link><description>A recent study found that CagriSema, a weight-loss therapy for individuals with obesity and diabetes, demonstrated effectiveness in aiding weight loss but fell short of outperforming Eli Lilly’s rival drug Zepbound. While the results highlight CagriSema’s potential, they solidify Zepbound’s competitive edge in the burgeoning metabolic treatment market.</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 17:17:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Beam base editing therapy gets ‘proof of concept’ in rare lung disease</title><link>https://www.biopharmadive.com/news/beam-aatd-base-editing-initial-data-results-302/742015/</link><description>Beam Therapeutics' shares dropped sharply despite promising early study results showing its gene-editing technology could address the genetic cause of alpha-1 antitrypsin deficiency. The stock decline highlights investor concerns even as the company advances its innovative treatment potential.</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 17:25:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BioNTech's shares dip after posting lukewarm revenue guidance</title><link>https://endpts.com/biontechs-shares-dip-after-posting-lukewarm-revenue-guidance/</link><description>BioNTech shares fell 2% after projecting lower 2025 revenues, citing reduced COVID-19 vaccine demand and oversupply challenges despite a solid $4.2 billion revenue in 2023. The company plans to pivot toward advancing cancer treatments and cost-cutting measures while preparing for new vaccine launches to offset declining pandemic-related sales.</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 19:37:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Making Just-in-Time Oncology Trials Work: Overcoming Barriers and Unlocking Potential</title><link>https://www.fiercebiotech.com/premium/webinar/1368918</link><description>Just-in-time (JIT) oncology trials aim to accelerate research and improve patient access by activating trial sites only after identifying eligible patients, requiring strong collaboration between sponsors, sites, and IRBs to streamline processes and pre-negotiate agreements. An upcoming webinar will explore strategies like data-driven prescreening, standardized protocols, and centralized oversight to overcome operational barriers and expand the use of JIT trials in delivering faster, cost-effective cancer treatments.</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 19:50:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Virtual physical therapy startup Hinge Health files to go public</title><link>https://endpts.com/virtual-physical-therapy-startup-hinge-health-files-to-go-public/</link><description>Hinge Health, a virtual physical therapy startup focused on treating musculoskeletal issues and chronic pain through remote software, has filed for an IPO, ending a lull in digital health public offerings. The company aims to list on a stock exchange, marking a potential resurgence in investor confidence for the telehealth sector.</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 04:00:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bristol Myers buys out cell therapy partner 2seventy bio</title><link>https://endpts.com/bristol-myers-buys-out-cell-therapy-partner-2seventy-bio/</link><description>Bristol Myers Squibb has agreed to acquire 2seventy bio, its longtime partner in developing the CAR-T cell therapy Abecma for multiple myeloma, in a $286 million all-cash deal. The acquisition strengthens Bristol Myers' foothold in cancer therapies, building on the companies' existing collaboration aimed at advancing cutting-edge immunocellular treatments.</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 08:13:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Arvinas and Pfizer’s PROTAC vepdegestrant works in subset of breast cancer patients</title><link>https://endpts.com/arvinas-and-pfizers-protac-vepdegestrant-works-in-subset-of-breast-cancer-patients/</link><description>Arvinas and Pfizer's partnered experimental breast cancer drug, vepdegestrant, failed to outperform existing therapies in the Phase 3 VERITAC-2 trial, casting doubt on its competitive potential. The results highlight challenges for the collaboration’s aim to deliver a differentiated treatment in the crowded protein degrader landscape.</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 11:56:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Lundbeck’s amlenetug gains orphan drug status in Japan for MSA</title><link>https://www.pharmaceutical-technology.com/news/lundbeck-amlenetug-japan-msa/</link><description>Lundbeck has received Orphan Drug Designation (ODD) from Japan's Ministry of Health, Labor and Welfare for its treatment amlenetug for multiple system atrophy (MSA). This designation may enhance Lundbeck's ability to bring this promising therapy to market, providing hope for patients with this rare condition.</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 13:47:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Beam’s Gene Editor Achieves ‘First Ever’ Genetic Correction in AATD</title><link>https://www.biospace.com/drug-development/beams-gene-editor-achieves-first-ever-genetic-correction-in-aatd</link><description>William Blair analysts highlighted BEAM-302 as a breakthrough therapy, praising its superior efficacy in its sector in a recent investor note. While the report emphasized the drug's potential to redefine treatment standards, it did not mention any specific business deals, partnerships, or acquisitions related to the product.</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 13:52:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Pfizer, Arvinas Post Mixed Late-Stage Breast Cancer Data for Closely Watched PROTAC Drug</title><link>https://www.biospace.com/drug-development/pfizer-arvinas-post-mixed-late-stage-breast-cancer-data-for-closely-watched-protac-drug</link><description>Vepdegestrant’s mixed trial results—stalling on broad progression-free survival but showing promise in a niche patient group—sparked a 43% plunge in Arvinas’ stock, with analysts casting doubt on the drug's long-term viability. While no new deals were announced, the setback raises questions about the company’s ability to attract future partnerships or advance the drug’s commercial prospects.</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 14:08:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Corrected: Merck opens billion-dollar US facility to make Gardasil</title><link>https://endpts.com/merck-opens-billion-dollar-facility-to-make-bladder-cancer-immunotherapy/</link><description>Merck has launched a new North Carolina-based manufacturing facility to produce HPV vaccines, including Gardasil and Gardasil 9, to meet rising global demand for cervical cancer prevention. The plant’s opening aligns with Merck’s strategy to expand production capacity amid increasing vaccine rollout efforts worldwide.</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 14:50:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>2seventy bio, Bluebird’s cell therapy spinout, sells to Bristol Myers for less than $300M</title><link>https://www.biopharmadive.com/news/2seventy-bio-bristol-myers-deal-abecma-bluebird/742142/</link><description>2Seventy Bio's recent acquisition has terminated its brief stint as an independent firm, marking the end of a turbulent period marked by strategic restructuring and asset sales. The company, which shed research segments and saw its market value plummet by nearly 100%, now shifts focus under new ownership amid financial struggles.</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 16:05:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Arvinas gets positive breast cancer data, but finds differentiation a hard sell</title><link>https://www.biopharmadive.com/news/arvinas-pfizer-vepdegestrant-breast-cancer-data-veritac/742135/</link><description>Arvinas and Pfizer's partnered breast cancer drug, vepdegestrant, showed promising results in a specific patient subgroup compared to fulvestrant, though it didn't meet overall trial goals. The mixed outcomes highlight the experimental therapy's potential niche benefits while underscoring the challenges of broad efficacy in cancer treatment.</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 16:45:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Viking inks CordenPharma deal to boost obesity drug supply</title><link>https://www.biopharmadive.com/news/viking-cordenpharma-obesity-drug-manufacturing-deal/742139/</link><description>A biotech firm is investing $150 million in a strategic alliance to secure expanded production capacity for a high-profile weight-loss therapy, positioning itself to meet soaring demand. The partnership underscores the company’s aggressive push to capitalize on the competitive but rapidly growing market for obesity treatments.</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 17:25:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BMS to acquire longtime cell therapy partner 2seventy bio for $286m</title><link>https://www.pharmaceutical-technology.com/news/bms-to-acquire-longtime-cell-therapy-partner-2seventy-bio-for-286m/</link><description>2seventy bio has recently entered into a significant deal following a tough period marked by the divestment of several research programs. This strategic move signals a potential shift in the company’s direction amidst its previous challenges.</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 20:57:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Updated: Zealand partners with Roche on its amylin analog in a deal worth up to $5.3B</title><link>https://endpts.com/zealand-partners-with-roche-on-petrelintide-in-a-deal-worth-5-3b/</link><description>Zealand Pharma has secured a significant licensing deal with Roche for its amylin analog petrelintide, marking the largest partnership to date for an obesity treatment. This collaboration highlights the growing interest and investment in obesity therapeutics.</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2025 08:10:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ono licenses rare blood disease drug from Ionis for $280M upfront</title><link>https://endpts.com/ono-licenses-rare-blood-disease-drug-from-ionis-for-280m-upfront/</link><description>Ono Pharmaceutical is investing $280 million upfront to acquire the global rights to Ionis Pharmaceuticals' treatment for a rare blood disorder, highlighting a significant partnership in a growing therapeutic area. This strategic move underscores both companies' commitment to advancing solutions for underserved medical needs.</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2025 10:34:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Merck MS tablet set for wider use by NHS in England</title><link>https://pharmaphorum.com/news/merck-ms-tablet-set-wider-use-nhs-england</link><description>Thousands more patients with multiple sclerosis in England will soon have access to Merck KGaA's take-at-home tablet Mavenclad, enhancing treatment options for this condition. This expanded availability signifies a significant move in improving patient care for those battling multiple sclerosis.</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2025 11:02:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Zealand and Roche strike $5.3bn obesity treatment deal</title><link>https://www.pharmaceutical-technology.com/news/zealand-and-roche-strike-5-3bn-obesity-treatment-deal/</link><description>Zealand Pharma and another company have partnered to develop Zealand’s amylin analogue, petrelintide, for use both as a standalone treatment and in combination therapies. This collaboration aims to enhance treatment options in the therapeutic space.</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2025 11:13:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EU proposes legislation to bolster medicines supply chain</title><link>https://pharmaphorum.com/news/eu-proposes-legislation-bolster-medicines-supply-chain</link><description>The EU's proposed legislation aims to ensure a reliable supply of critical medicines, but both pharmaceutical companies and patient advocacy groups have raised concerns regarding the specifics of the measures. Stakeholders are calling for clarity to avoid unintended consequences that could impact access to essential treatments.</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2025 12:28:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Gilead, GSK-ViiV Move Ahead With Long-Acting HIV Options Following Early-Stage Readouts</title><link>https://www.biospace.com/drug-development/gilead-gsk-viiv-move-ahead-with-long-acting-hiv-options-following-early-stage-readouts</link><description>Gilead is moving directly to Phase III clinical trials for its once-yearly lenacapavir, while GSK and ViiV are advancing their long-acting antivirals following promising early-stage results. Both companies are focusing on these developments as they aim to enhance treatment options in the antiviral market.</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2025 13:13:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Insilico nabs $110M Series E for AI drug discovery after stalling Hong Kong IPO plans</title><link>https://endpts.com/insilico-nabs-110m-series-e-for-ai-drug-discovery-after-stalling-hong-kong-ipo-plans/</link><description>Insilico Medicine raised $110 million in a megaround, achieving a unicorn valuation for its promising pipeline of 30 treatment candidates. This funding will fuel its AI-driven drug discovery efforts as the company continues to innovate in the pharmaceutical sector.</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2025 13:48:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ascletis’ not-so-great weight loss data; Vivace’s $35M Series D</title><link>https://endpts.com/ascletis-not-so-great-weight-loss-data-vivaces-35m-series-d/</link><description>Ascletis has reported disappointing results for its obesity therapy ASC47, which showed a placebo-adjusted weight loss of only 1.7%. The outcome raises concerns about the drug’s effectiveness in the competitive obesity treatment market.</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2025 14:22:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Roche builds in obesity with $5.3bn Zealand licensing deal</title><link>https://pharmaphorum.com/news/roche-builds-obesity-53bn-zealand-licensing-deal</link><description>Roche has made a significant $1.4 billion upfront investment to acquire rights to an obesity treatment candidate from Zealand Pharma. This deal underscores Roche's commitment to expanding its portfolio in the obesity therapeutics market.</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2025 14:26:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ono pays $280M to license Ionis rare disease drug</title><link>https://www.biopharmadive.com/news/ionis-ono-sapablursen-polycythemia-vera-licensing-deal/742269/</link><description>Ionis Pharmaceuticals is advancing its drug, sapablursen, which is currently undergoing a Phase 2 trial for the treatment of polycythemia vera. The trial's progress could significantly impact the company’s position in the market for therapies addressing this blood disorder.</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2025 15:12:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>#CROI25: Merck’s troubled HIV drug heads to regulators; ViiV seeks longer-acting HIV treatment</title><link>https://endpts.com/croi25-mercks-troubled-hiv-drug-heads-to-regulators-viiv-seeks-longer-acting-hiv-drug/</link><description>At the annual Conference on Retroviruses and Opportunistic Infections in San Francisco, Merck announced positive Phase 3 results for its two-drug HIV regimen, highlighting its effectiveness and potential impact on treatment options. This breakthrough positions Merck as a key player in advancing HIV therapy and could significantly alter the landscape for patients.</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2025 15:25:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Roche broadens obesity drug plans with $1.65B Zealand deal</title><link>https://www.biopharmadive.com/news/roche-zealand-license-obesity-drug-amylin-petrelinitide/742278/</link><description>The Swiss pharma has secured access to an experimental amylin-targeting treatment, which it will evaluate in combination with drugs obtained from Carmot. This deal highlights the company's strategy to enhance its therapeutic offerings through innovative partnerships.</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2025 16:20:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ono earmarks $940m to gain rare blood cancer therapy from Ionis</title><link>https://www.pharmaceutical-technology.com/news/ono-earmarks-940m-to-gain-rare-blood-cancer-therapy-from-ionis/</link><description>Ono Pharmaceuticals has acquired the global rights to sapablursen, an RNA-targeting therapy developed by Ionis for the treatment of polycythemia vera (PV). This partnership highlights Ono's commitment to expanding its portfolio in innovative therapies for hematological conditions.</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2025 16:46:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Why Gilead could lose its HIV product hopping case</title><link>https://endpts.com/why-gilead-could-lose-its-hiv-product-hopping-case/</link><description>The California Supreme Court is evaluating whether Gilead Sciences can be held liable for delaying the market release of a potentially safer HIV drug, despite allegedly being aware of its advantages over an existing blockbuster treatment. This case could have significant implications for the pharmaceutical company and its accountability in drug development and sales practices.</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2025 18:52:24 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>