<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Oncology</title><link>https://nrouizem.github.io/test/oncology_feed.xml</link><description>Daily curated &amp; summarized biopharma news.</description><atom:link href="https://nrouizem.github.io/test/oncology_feed.xml" rel="self"/><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2025 01:23:24 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Lilly’s FDA approval for Omvoh close up: Nearly 90% of one-year responders maintained remission through two years</title><link>https://www.drugdiscoverytrends.com/lillys-fda-approval-for-omvoh-close-up-nearly-90-of-one-year-responders-maintained-remission-through-two-years/</link><description>The FDA has approved Omvoh (mirikizumab-mrkz) for Crohn’s disease, marking its second authorization for inflammatory bowel disease (IBD) this year and introducing the first biologic with Phase 3 two-year efficacy data in over 15 years. In the pivotal VIVID-1 trial, 53% of patients treated with Omvoh achieved clinical remission at one year, significantly outperforming the 36% remission rate seen in the placebo group.</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2025 19:00:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>How 3T Biosciences’ platform targets immunologically cold solid tumors</title><link>https://www.drugdiscoverytrends.com/3t-biosciences-targeted-strategy-for-mss-colorectal-cancer/</link><description>3T Biosciences is addressing the challenge of immunotherapy resistance in solid tumors, particularly focusing on microsatellite stable colorectal cancer (MSS CRC), which shows over 90% non-responsiveness to checkpoint inhibitors. Their innovative platform aims to enhance treatment efficacy for these immunologically cold solid tumors, promising a potential breakthrough in oncology.</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 05:12:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Flatiron Health sees shift from “what if” to “what is” in real-world evidence in oncology</title><link>https://www.drugdiscoverytrends.com/flatiron-health-sees-shift-from-what-if-to-what-is-in-real-world-evidence-in-oncology/</link><description>Flatiron Health is transforming cancer care by moving from theoretical discussions about AI in healthcare to practical implementations, as noted by their head of outcomes research, Blythe Adamson. The company is experiencing increased confidence in real-world evidence applications post-ChatGPT, reflecting a significant shift in the industry.</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2025 03:39:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Rosnilimab phase 2b trial shows promise in treating RA</title><link>https://www.drugdiscoverytrends.com/rosnilimab-phase-2b-trial-shows-promise-in-treating-ra/</link><description>A phase 2b trial of rosnilimab has shown promising results in treating rheumatoid arthritis (RA) by targeting the PD-1 pathway to potentially reset the immune system. Unlike existing therapies that often fail to provide long-term remission, rosnilimab aims to offer a more effective solution for patients struggling with the complex disease.</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2025 14:07:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>COTA Healthcare announces AI milestone in real-world oncology data</title><link>https://www.drugdiscoverytrends.com/cota-healthcare-announces-ai-milestone-in-real-world-oncology-data/</link><description>COTA Healthcare has launched a groundbreaking generative AI platform that enhances the accuracy and profitability of large-scale curation of real-world oncology data. This innovation signifies a notable advancement in the shift towards automating the traditionally labor-intensive process of RWD abstraction in the healthcare industry.</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2025 19:00:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>AstraZeneca Builds Stomach Cancer Case for Imfinzi With Strong Phase III Data</title><link>https://www.biospace.com/drug-development/astrazeneca-builds-stomach-cancer-case-for-imfinzi-with-strong-phase-iii-data</link><description>AstraZeneca's cancer drug Imfinzi is poised to drive significant growth in 2025, with regulators set to decide on its expanded use in treating stomach and bladder cancers. The blockbuster therapy generated over $4.7 billion in sales last year, cementing its role as a key revenue driver for the pharmaceutical giant.</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2025 13:58:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Multi-Modality Testing of EGFR</title><link>https://www.fiercebiotech.com/resource/multi-modality-testing-egfr</link><description>Neogenomics highlights its new white paper advocating a multi-modality testing approach to improve clinical trials, offering deeper insights into patient responses and treatment effectiveness. The sponsored resource, available for download, underscores how integrating diverse testing methods can advance oncology research and therapeutic outcomes.</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2025 18:04:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Sun Pharma to acquire Checkpoint Therapeutics and its anti-PD-L1 antibody</title><link>https://endpts.com/sun-pharma-to-acquire-checkpoint-therapeutics-and-its-anti-pd-l1-antibody/</link><description>Checkpoint Therapeutics has pivoted from seeking a partnership for its newly approved cancer drug to being acquired outright by India’s Sun Pharma in a strategic immuno-oncology expansion. The deal, valued at $4.10 per share, marks a swift exit for Checkpoint and reinforces Sun Pharma’s growing footprint in cutting-edge cancer therapies.</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 12:20:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Amgen, Kyowa Kirin’s Rocatinlimab Picks Up Steam With Late-Stage Atopic Dermatitis Win</title><link>https://www.biospace.com/drug-development/amgens-rocatinlimab-picks-up-steam-with-late-stage-atopic-dermatitis-win</link><description>"September 2024 trial results for rocatinlimab, an experimental antibody, drew mixed analyst reactions due to its underwhelming efficacy in treating a targeted condition. The lukewarm data sparked debate about the drug's future potential, with some holding out hope for protocol adjustments while others questioned its market viability."</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 13:57:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BioNTech's shares dip after posting lukewarm revenue guidance</title><link>https://endpts.com/biontechs-shares-dip-after-posting-lukewarm-revenue-guidance/</link><description>BioNTech shares fell 2% after projecting lower 2025 revenues, citing reduced COVID-19 vaccine demand and oversupply challenges despite a solid $4.2 billion revenue in 2023. The company plans to pivot toward advancing cancer treatments and cost-cutting measures while preparing for new vaccine launches to offset declining pandemic-related sales.</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 19:37:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Making Just-in-Time Oncology Trials Work: Overcoming Barriers and Unlocking Potential</title><link>https://www.fiercebiotech.com/premium/webinar/1368918</link><description>Just-in-time (JIT) oncology trials aim to accelerate research and improve patient access by activating trial sites only after identifying eligible patients, requiring strong collaboration between sponsors, sites, and IRBs to streamline processes and pre-negotiate agreements. An upcoming webinar will explore strategies like data-driven prescreening, standardized protocols, and centralized oversight to overcome operational barriers and expand the use of JIT trials in delivering faster, cost-effective cancer treatments.</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 19:50:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bristol Myers buys out cell therapy partner 2seventy bio</title><link>https://endpts.com/bristol-myers-buys-out-cell-therapy-partner-2seventy-bio/</link><description>Bristol Myers Squibb has agreed to acquire 2seventy bio, its longtime partner in developing the CAR-T cell therapy Abecma for multiple myeloma, in a $286 million all-cash deal. The acquisition strengthens Bristol Myers' foothold in cancer therapies, building on the companies' existing collaboration aimed at advancing cutting-edge immunocellular treatments.</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 08:13:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Arvinas and Pfizer’s PROTAC vepdegestrant works in subset of breast cancer patients</title><link>https://endpts.com/arvinas-and-pfizers-protac-vepdegestrant-works-in-subset-of-breast-cancer-patients/</link><description>Arvinas and Pfizer's partnered experimental breast cancer drug, vepdegestrant, failed to outperform existing therapies in the Phase 3 VERITAC-2 trial, casting doubt on its competitive potential. The results highlight challenges for the collaboration’s aim to deliver a differentiated treatment in the crowded protein degrader landscape.</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 11:56:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Pfizer, Arvinas Post Mixed Late-Stage Breast Cancer Data for Closely Watched PROTAC Drug</title><link>https://www.biospace.com/drug-development/pfizer-arvinas-post-mixed-late-stage-breast-cancer-data-for-closely-watched-protac-drug</link><description>Vepdegestrant’s mixed trial results—stalling on broad progression-free survival but showing promise in a niche patient group—sparked a 43% plunge in Arvinas’ stock, with analysts casting doubt on the drug's long-term viability. While no new deals were announced, the setback raises questions about the company’s ability to attract future partnerships or advance the drug’s commercial prospects.</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 14:08:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Corrected: Merck opens billion-dollar US facility to make Gardasil</title><link>https://endpts.com/merck-opens-billion-dollar-facility-to-make-bladder-cancer-immunotherapy/</link><description>Merck has launched a new North Carolina-based manufacturing facility to produce HPV vaccines, including Gardasil and Gardasil 9, to meet rising global demand for cervical cancer prevention. The plant’s opening aligns with Merck’s strategy to expand production capacity amid increasing vaccine rollout efforts worldwide.</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 14:50:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Arvinas gets positive breast cancer data, but finds differentiation a hard sell</title><link>https://www.biopharmadive.com/news/arvinas-pfizer-vepdegestrant-breast-cancer-data-veritac/742135/</link><description>Arvinas and Pfizer's partnered breast cancer drug, vepdegestrant, showed promising results in a specific patient subgroup compared to fulvestrant, though it didn't meet overall trial goals. The mixed outcomes highlight the experimental therapy's potential niche benefits while underscoring the challenges of broad efficacy in cancer treatment.</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 16:45:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Telix’s new lead-212 generator could dispel medical isotope scalability hurdles</title><link>https://www.pharmaceutical-technology.com/news/telixs-new-lead-212-generator-could-dispel-medical-isotope-scalability-hurdles/</link><description>Lead-212-based alpha emitters demonstrate potential in cancer therapies, yet face challenges in commercial supply. The difficulties in production may hinder broader application in treatment protocols.</description><pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2025 11:34:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Sutro puts lead ADC on hold, cuts staff and changes CEO</title><link>https://pharmaphorum.com/news/sutro-puts-lead-adc-hold-cuts-staff-and-changes-ceo</link><description>Sutro has decided to discontinue its lead drug for ovarian cancer, marking a significant shift in its strategic focus. The company is now channeling its efforts towards three promising preclinical candidates.</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2025 11:00:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>AstraZeneca director says AI must be a “thought partner” in drug discovery</title><link>https://www.pharmaceutical-technology.com/news/astrazeneca-director-says-ai-must-be-a-thought-partner-in-drug-discovery/</link><description>AstraZeneca's senior director in oncology data science highlighted the company's innovative use of AI technologies to enhance drug discovery processes during a recent presentation. This approach aims to streamline research and development, ultimately accelerating the delivery of new cancer treatments.</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2025 16:29:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>