<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Oncology</title><link>https://nrouizem.github.io/test/oncology_feed.xml</link><description>Daily curated &amp; summarized biopharma news.</description><atom:link href="https://nrouizem.github.io/test/oncology_feed.xml" rel="self"/><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 01:18:21 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>How 3T Biosciences’ platform targets immunologically cold solid tumors</title><link>https://www.drugdiscoverytrends.com/3t-biosciences-targeted-strategy-for-mss-colorectal-cancer/</link><description>3T Biosciences is tackling the challenge of immunotherapy resistance in solid tumors, particularly in microsatellite stable colorectal cancer (MSS CRC), where over 90% of cases show limited response to current treatments. The company's innovative platform aims to enhance responses in immunologically cold solid tumors, addressing a critical need in oncology.</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 05:12:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>How Capsida’s unconventional funding strategy and capsid technology promise to reshape CNS treatments</title><link>https://www.drugdiscoverytrends.com/how-capsidas-unconventional-funding-strategy-and-capsid-technology-promise-to-reshape-cns-treatments/</link><description>Capsida Biotherapeutics has secured a significant $40 million license payment from AbbVie as the pharmaceutical giant exercises its option on their first neurodegenerative disease program. The gene therapy startup has primarily built its funding through strategic partnerships with major pharmaceutical companies, positioning itself to reshape treatments for central nervous system disorders.</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 21:05:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The FDA Fast-Tracked GNSC-001 gene therapy targets osteoarthritis at its root</title><link>https://www.drugdiscoverytrends.com/the-fda-fast-tracked-gnsc-001-gene-therapy-targets-osteoarthritis-at-its-root/</link><description>The FDA has fast-tracked GNSC-001, a groundbreaking gene therapy aimed at addressing osteoarthritis at its source, a condition affecting over 30 million Americans and imposing significant healthcare costs. This innovative treatment seeks to fill a crucial gap in effective interventions for this debilitating degenerative joint disease.</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2025 19:16:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Flatiron Health sees shift from “what if” to “what is” in real-world evidence in oncology</title><link>https://www.drugdiscoverytrends.com/flatiron-health-sees-shift-from-what-if-to-what-is-in-real-world-evidence-in-oncology/</link><description>Flatiron Health is transforming oncology care by shifting from speculative discussions about AI's potential to tangible outcomes in real-world evidence, according to Blythe Adamson, the company's head of outcomes research. This change in perspective has been fueled by advancements in AI, particularly after the introduction of ChatGPT, leading to increased confidence in integrating technology into cancer care.</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2025 03:39:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Rosnilimab phase 2b trial shows promise in treating RA</title><link>https://www.drugdiscoverytrends.com/rosnilimab-phase-2b-trial-shows-promise-in-treating-ra/</link><description>A phase 2b trial of rosnilimab, which targets the PD-1 pathway to reset the immune system, shows promise in providing long-term relief for rheumatoid arthritis (RA) patients who often struggle with existing treatments. This novel approach could offer a breakthrough for those cycling through therapies like methotrexate and biologics without sustained remission.</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2025 14:07:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>COTA Healthcare announces AI milestone in real-world oncology data</title><link>https://www.drugdiscoverytrends.com/cota-healthcare-announces-ai-milestone-in-real-world-oncology-data/</link><description>COTA Healthcare has announced a groundbreaking generative AI platform that transforms the curation of real-world oncology data, enhancing both accuracy and profitability. This innovation signifies a pivotal change in the industry's approach to automating the labor-intensive process of collecting cancer data.</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2025 19:00:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Finding Patients, Closing Treatment Gaps, and Building Better Messaging through AI and Real-World Data</title><link>https://www.fiercebiotech.com/premium/webinar/1368842</link><description>OM1's upcoming webinar, featuring experts Joseph Zabinski and Kathryn Starzyk, explores how AI-driven digital phenotyping and real-world data can help pharmaceutical teams identify underserved patient populations and align therapies with unmet clinical needs. The session will demonstrate strategies to bridge treatment gaps, refine market messaging, and ensure therapies reach overlooked communities through advanced analytics.</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 20:09:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>J&amp;J Axes Late-Stage Depression Trial After Underwhelming Efficacy</title><link>https://www.biospace.com/drug-development/j-j-axes-late-stage-depression-trial-after-underwhelming-efficacy</link><description>Despite aticaprant's Phase III setback, analysts say J&amp;J's neuroscience strategy remains intact, bolstered by its recent $14.6 billion acquisition of Intra-Cellular Therapeutics. The company’s confidence is further reinforced by the continued success of Spravato, its treatment for resistant depression, positioning it to maintain momentum in the sector.</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2025 13:46:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>AstraZeneca Builds Stomach Cancer Case for Imfinzi With Strong Phase III Data</title><link>https://www.biospace.com/drug-development/astrazeneca-builds-stomach-cancer-case-for-imfinzi-with-strong-phase-iii-data</link><description>AstraZeneca's cancer drug Imfinzi is poised to drive significant growth in 2025, with regulators set to decide on its expanded use in treating stomach and bladder cancers. The blockbuster therapy generated over $4.7 billion in sales last year, cementing its role as a key revenue driver for the pharmaceutical giant.</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2025 13:58:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>At $300M Kardigan startup, former MyoKardia team unveils its first drug, and it comes from Ionis</title><link>https://endpts.com/at-300m-kardigan-startup-former-myokardia-team-unveils-its-first-drug-and-it-comes-from-ionis/</link><description>Former MyoKardia executives launched a heart health biotech startup with $300 million in funding, leveraging undisclosed partnerships to secure in-licensed clinical-stage assets for cardiac therapies. The stealth-mode company remains tight-lipped about specific deals but signals a focus on advancing innovative treatments, attracting attention for its seasoned leadership and strategic collaborations.</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2025 16:16:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>J&amp;J scraps depression testing for potential blockbuster drug</title><link>https://www.biopharmadive.com/news/johnson-depression-studies-discontinue-aticaprant-neumora/741922/</link><description>A recent decision has dealt a "big blow" to a promising class of brain therapies, including Johnson &amp; Johnson’s experimental drug aticaprant and Neumora Therapeutics’ candidate, casting uncertainty over their development. While the article highlights setbacks for these specific treatments, it does not mention any new business deals, partnerships, or acquisitions related to the companies involved.</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2025 17:08:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Multi-Modality Testing of EGFR</title><link>https://www.fiercebiotech.com/resource/multi-modality-testing-egfr</link><description>Neogenomics highlights its new white paper advocating a multi-modality testing approach to improve clinical trials, offering deeper insights into patient responses and treatment effectiveness. The sponsored resource, available for download, underscores how integrating diverse testing methods can advance oncology research and therapeutic outcomes.</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2025 18:04:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>FDA approves Neurotech therapy for rare eye disease</title><link>https://endpts.com/fda-approves-neurotech-therapy-for-rare-eye-disease/</link><description>The FDA approved Neurotech Pharmaceuticals’ first-of-its-kind cell therapy for macular telangiectasia type 2, a rare eye disease causing progressive central vision loss, marking a major advancement for patients with no prior treatment options. The therapy, which implants cells to repair retinal damage, could transform care for the condition, though the article does not mention specific business deals or partnerships related to its development.</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2025 19:57:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Sun Pharma to acquire Checkpoint Therapeutics and its anti-PD-L1 antibody</title><link>https://endpts.com/sun-pharma-to-acquire-checkpoint-therapeutics-and-its-anti-pd-l1-antibody/</link><description>Checkpoint Therapeutics has pivoted from seeking a partnership for its newly approved cancer drug to being acquired outright by India’s Sun Pharma in a strategic immuno-oncology expansion. The deal, valued at $4.10 per share, marks a swift exit for Checkpoint and reinforces Sun Pharma’s growing footprint in cutting-edge cancer therapies.</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 12:20:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Novo Nordisk’s CagriSema shows 15.7% weight loss in second pivotal trial</title><link>https://endpts.com/novo-nordisks-cagrisema-shows-15-7-weight-loss-in-second-pivotal-trial/</link><description>Novo Nordisk announced Monday that its drug CagriSema achieved 15.7% weight loss in patients with obesity and type 2 diabetes after over a year of use, marking a potential advancement in dual-treatment therapies. The result underscores the drug’s efficacy in addressing these interconnected conditions, positioning it as a promising contender in the competitive metabolic health market.</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 12:21:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>J&amp;J’s Oral IL-23R Blocker Sets New Standard in Plaque Psoriasis, Beating BMS’ Sotyktu</title><link>https://www.biospace.com/drug-development/j-js-oral-il-23r-blocker-sets-new-standard-in-plaque-psoriasis-beating-bmss-sotyktu</link><description>New late-stage trial data reveals Johnson &amp; Johnson’s psoriasis drug icotrokinra outperformed Bristol Myers Squibb’s Sotyktu in clearing skin and reducing symptom severity for patients with plaque psoriasis. The findings could intensify competition in the dermatology treatment market, positioning J&amp;J’s therapy as a potential challenger in this therapeutic area.</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 14:03:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BMS’ Sotyktu Notches Phase III Win in Psoriatic Arthritis</title><link>https://www.biospace.com/drug-development/bms-sotyktu-notches-phase-iii-win-in-psoriatic-arthritis</link><description>In the plaque psoriasis market, Sotyktu is locked in a competitive battle with Amgen’s Otezla while bracing for new rivalry from Alumis’ investigational TYK2 inhibitor. The intensifying competition underscores the dynamic landscape of psoriasis treatments as emerging therapies threaten to disrupt established players.</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 14:07:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Novo Dips After CagriSema’s Latest Lower-Than-Expected Weight Loss Readout</title><link>https://www.biospace.com/drug-development/novo-dips-after-cagrisemas-latest-lower-than-expected-weight-loss-readout</link><description>New clinical trial results revealed CagriSema, a weight-loss drug from Novo, achieved 15.7% weight reduction in diabetic patients over 68 weeks but delivered a disappointing 22.7% in non-diabetic patients by December 2024, falling short of the company’s projected 25% efficacy. The underwhelming performance in non-diabetic trials raises questions about the drug’s competitive edge in the crowded obesity treatment market.</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 14:14:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mineralys shares climb on study data for blood pressure drug</title><link>https://www.biopharmadive.com/news/mineralys-lorundrostat-hypertension-study-results/742000/</link><description>New studies on Mineralys' hypertension treatment have validated the drug as a promising near-commercial product, with analysts hailing it as a "derisked, almost-commercial stage cardiometabolic asset." While no specific deals or partnerships were mentioned, the data bolsters the therapy’s market potential and positions it for future commercial opportunities.</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 15:30:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trevi Therapeutics stock soars on Phase 2a chronic cough data</title><link>https://endpts.com/trevi-therapeutics-stock-soars-on-phase-2a-chronic-cough-data/</link><description>Trevi Therapeutics' chronic cough drug demonstrated a 57% reduction in 24-hour cough frequency versus placebo in a Phase 2a trial, outperforming investor expectations and sparking a 40% surge in its stock ($TRVI) at market open. The breakthrough underscores the treatment’s potential and has ignited optimism among investors about the company’s clinical and commercial prospects.</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 15:51:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>J&amp;J, Protagonist outline first IBD win for potential immunological blockbuster</title><link>https://endpts.com/jj-protagonist-outline-first-ibd-win-for-potential-immunological-blockbuster/</link><description>Johnson &amp; Johnson and Protagonist Therapeutics have partnered to develop an oral IL-23 drug, aiming to create a breakthrough immunology treatment. The companies announced progress toward this goal on Monday, signaling potential advancements in bringing the blockbuster drug candidate closer to market.</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 16:04:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>#AAD25 roundup: Data from Amgen, Bristol Myers, J&amp;J, Alumis and more</title><link>https://endpts.com/aad25-roundup-data-from-amgen-bristol-myers-jj-alumis-and-more/</link><description>At the American Academy of Dermatology annual meeting, key players like Amgen, Bristol Myers Squibb, Alumis, and Kyowa Kirin spotlighted updates on their dermatology drug pipelines, though no mergers or acquisitions were highlighted. The event emphasized breakthroughs in treatments for conditions like psoriasis and eczema, showcasing the industry’s focus on advancing innovative therapies for skin diseases.</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 16:37:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Deep Dive: Cardiovascular Disease Back in the Spotlight</title><link>https://www.biospace.com/drug-development/deep-dive-cardiovascular-disease-back-in-the-spotlight</link><description>BioSpace highlights the rapid evolution of emerging therapeutic modalities, from gene editing to cell therapies, as biotech and pharma companies race to innovate in a competitive market. The article underscores the intensifying battles for dominance in this space, with advancements poised to reshape treatment paradigms and spur significant industry growth.</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 16:40:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Beam shares promising first clinical data on gene editing treatment</title><link>https://endpts.com/beam-shares-promising-first-clinical-data-on-gene-editing-treatment/</link><description>Beam Therapeutics' experimental gene-editing therapy demonstrated promising results in a small trial, reducing mutant proteins linked to lung-damaging alpha-1 antitrypsin deficiency and boosting corrected protein levels in nine participants. The early data underscores the treatment's potential as a one-time fix for the genetic disorder, though the article does not mention any business deals, partnerships, or mergers.</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 16:42:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Novo’s Wegovy successor disappoints in second large trial</title><link>https://www.biopharmadive.com/news/novo-nordisk-cagrisema-study-results-diabetes-weight-loss/742008/</link><description>A recent study found that CagriSema, a weight-loss therapy for individuals with obesity and diabetes, demonstrated effectiveness in aiding weight loss but fell short of outperforming Eli Lilly’s rival drug Zepbound. While the results highlight CagriSema’s potential, they solidify Zepbound’s competitive edge in the burgeoning metabolic treatment market.</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 17:17:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Beam base editing therapy gets ‘proof of concept’ in rare lung disease</title><link>https://www.biopharmadive.com/news/beam-aatd-base-editing-initial-data-results-302/742015/</link><description>Beam Therapeutics' shares dropped sharply despite promising early study results showing its gene-editing technology could address the genetic cause of alpha-1 antitrypsin deficiency. The stock decline highlights investor concerns even as the company advances its innovative treatment potential.</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 17:25:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BioNTech's shares dip after posting lukewarm revenue guidance</title><link>https://endpts.com/biontechs-shares-dip-after-posting-lukewarm-revenue-guidance/</link><description>BioNTech shares fell 2% after projecting lower 2025 revenues, citing reduced COVID-19 vaccine demand and oversupply challenges despite a solid $4.2 billion revenue in 2023. The company plans to pivot toward advancing cancer treatments and cost-cutting measures while preparing for new vaccine launches to offset declining pandemic-related sales.</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 19:37:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Making Just-in-Time Oncology Trials Work: Overcoming Barriers and Unlocking Potential</title><link>https://www.fiercebiotech.com/premium/webinar/1368918</link><description>Just-in-time (JIT) oncology trials aim to accelerate research and improve patient access by activating trial sites only after identifying eligible patients, requiring strong collaboration between sponsors, sites, and IRBs to streamline processes and pre-negotiate agreements. An upcoming webinar will explore strategies like data-driven prescreening, standardized protocols, and centralized oversight to overcome operational barriers and expand the use of JIT trials in delivering faster, cost-effective cancer treatments.</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 19:50:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The true cost of steroid-toxicity</title><link>https://www.drugdiscoverytrends.com/the-true-cost-of-steroid-toxicity/</link><description>Glucocorticoids, widely used for treating autoimmune disorders due to their effectiveness in reducing inflammation and immune system activity, seem like a low-cost option at first glance. However, the article highlights the long-term toxicity and hidden costs associated with their prolonged use, urging a reevaluation of their role in treatment protocols.</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 01:33:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bristol Myers buys out cell therapy partner 2seventy bio</title><link>https://endpts.com/bristol-myers-buys-out-cell-therapy-partner-2seventy-bio/</link><description>Bristol Myers Squibb has agreed to acquire 2seventy bio, its longtime partner in developing the CAR-T cell therapy Abecma for multiple myeloma, in a $286 million all-cash deal. The acquisition strengthens Bristol Myers' foothold in cancer therapies, building on the companies' existing collaboration aimed at advancing cutting-edge immunocellular treatments.</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 08:13:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Arvinas and Pfizer’s PROTAC vepdegestrant works in subset of breast cancer patients</title><link>https://endpts.com/arvinas-and-pfizers-protac-vepdegestrant-works-in-subset-of-breast-cancer-patients/</link><description>Arvinas and Pfizer's partnered experimental breast cancer drug, vepdegestrant, failed to outperform existing therapies in the Phase 3 VERITAC-2 trial, casting doubt on its competitive potential. The results highlight challenges for the collaboration’s aim to deliver a differentiated treatment in the crowded protein degrader landscape.</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 11:56:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Beam’s Gene Editor Achieves ‘First Ever’ Genetic Correction in AATD</title><link>https://www.biospace.com/drug-development/beams-gene-editor-achieves-first-ever-genetic-correction-in-aatd</link><description>William Blair analysts highlighted BEAM-302 as a breakthrough therapy, praising its superior efficacy in its sector in a recent investor note. While the report emphasized the drug's potential to redefine treatment standards, it did not mention any specific business deals, partnerships, or acquisitions related to the product.</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 13:52:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Pfizer, Arvinas Post Mixed Late-Stage Breast Cancer Data for Closely Watched PROTAC Drug</title><link>https://www.biospace.com/drug-development/pfizer-arvinas-post-mixed-late-stage-breast-cancer-data-for-closely-watched-protac-drug</link><description>Vepdegestrant’s mixed trial results—stalling on broad progression-free survival but showing promise in a niche patient group—sparked a 43% plunge in Arvinas’ stock, with analysts casting doubt on the drug's long-term viability. While no new deals were announced, the setback raises questions about the company’s ability to attract future partnerships or advance the drug’s commercial prospects.</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 14:08:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Corrected: Merck opens billion-dollar US facility to make Gardasil</title><link>https://endpts.com/merck-opens-billion-dollar-facility-to-make-bladder-cancer-immunotherapy/</link><description>Merck has launched a new North Carolina-based manufacturing facility to produce HPV vaccines, including Gardasil and Gardasil 9, to meet rising global demand for cervical cancer prevention. The plant’s opening aligns with Merck’s strategy to expand production capacity amid increasing vaccine rollout efforts worldwide.</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 14:50:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Arvinas gets positive breast cancer data, but finds differentiation a hard sell</title><link>https://www.biopharmadive.com/news/arvinas-pfizer-vepdegestrant-breast-cancer-data-veritac/742135/</link><description>Arvinas and Pfizer's partnered breast cancer drug, vepdegestrant, showed promising results in a specific patient subgroup compared to fulvestrant, though it didn't meet overall trial goals. The mixed outcomes highlight the experimental therapy's potential niche benefits while underscoring the challenges of broad efficacy in cancer treatment.</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 16:45:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Viking inks CordenPharma deal to boost obesity drug supply</title><link>https://www.biopharmadive.com/news/viking-cordenpharma-obesity-drug-manufacturing-deal/742139/</link><description>A biotech firm is investing $150 million in a strategic alliance to secure expanded production capacity for a high-profile weight-loss therapy, positioning itself to meet soaring demand. The partnership underscores the company’s aggressive push to capitalize on the competitive but rapidly growing market for obesity treatments.</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 17:25:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Agenus CMO touts immunotherapy advances on The Top Line</title><link>https://www.fiercebiotech.com/sponsored/agenus-cmo-touts-immunotherapy-advances-top-line</link><description>Agenus's Chief Medical Officer highlighted significant progress in the company's immunotherapy advancements during a recent interview on The Top Line. The discussion underscored Agenus's commitment to developing innovative cancer treatments and enhancing patient outcomes.</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 17:26:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Gilead, GSK-ViiV Move Ahead With Long-Acting HIV Options Following Early-Stage Readouts</title><link>https://www.biospace.com/drug-development/gilead-gsk-viiv-move-ahead-with-long-acting-hiv-options-following-early-stage-readouts</link><description>Gilead is advancing straight to Phase III clinical trials for its once-yearly lenacapavir, while GSK and ViiV are moving ahead with their long-acting antivirals following encouraging early-stage results. Both companies are aiming to enhance treatment options in the antiviral space.</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2025 13:13:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Amgen's Uplizna Deepens Response Against Myasthenia Gravis at 1 Year</title><link>https://www.biospace.com/drug-development/amgens-uplizna-deepens-response-against-myasthenia-gravis-at-1-year</link><description>Amgen is set to file a regulatory submission for Uplizna, currently approved for a rare ocular autoimmune disorder, for use in treating myasthenia gravis by mid-2025, following what analysts describe as "strong" data. This move reflects Amgen's commitment to expanding the therapeutic applications of its existing treatments.</description><pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2025 13:28:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Altimmune To Test Investigational GLP-1–Based Obesity Drug for Alcohol Use Disorder</title><link>https://www.biospace.com/drug-development/altimmune-to-test-investigational-glp-1-based-obesity-drug-for-alcohol-use-disorder</link><description>A Maryland-based biopharma is partnering with Eli Lilly and Novo Nordisk to trial a GLP-1 agonist aimed at addressing alcohol- and liver-related conditions. This collaboration aims to explore innovative treatment options in the growing field of metabolic health.</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2025 14:29:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>How biosimulation and virtual trials can bust through clinical trial roadblocks</title><link>https://www.drugdiscoverytrends.com/how-biosimulation-and-virtual-trials-can-bust-through-clinical-trial-roadblocks/</link><description>Over 300 million people globally suffer from rare diseases, with around 95% lacking FDA-approved treatments, highlighting the significant challenges traditional clinical trials face. However, emerging biosimulation and virtual trial methods are providing promising solutions to overcome these obstacles, as stated by Oxana Iliach, vice-chair.</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2025 15:54:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>AstraZeneca director says AI must be a “thought partner” in drug discovery</title><link>https://www.pharmaceutical-technology.com/news/astrazeneca-director-says-ai-must-be-a-thought-partner-in-drug-discovery/</link><description>AstraZeneca's senior director in oncology data science highlighted the company's innovative use of AI in drug discovery during a recent presentation. The integration of AI technologies is aimed at enhancing the efficiency and effectiveness of their oncology research efforts.</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2025 16:29:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>AbbVie builds the case for ovarian cancer drug Elahere</title><link>https://pharmaphorum.com/news/abbvie-builds-case-ovarian-cancer-drug-elahere</link><description>AbbVie aims to boost sales of its rapidly growing ovarian cancer treatment, Elahere, following the release of new survival data. The company anticipates that these positive results will enhance the drug's market position and patient outcomes.</description><pubDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2025 19:56:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Angelman Syndrome Race Heats Up Among Ionis, Ultragenyx and Neuren</title><link>https://www.biospace.com/drug-development/opinion-angelman-syndrome-race-heats-up-among-ionis-ultragenyx-and-neuren</link><description>Ionis and Ultragenyx are racing to bring oligonucleotide therapies to market for Angelman syndrome, showcasing their innovative approaches in treating this rare genetic disorder. Meanwhile, Neuren is working on a peptide treatment that could potentially challenge the advancements made by its competitors.</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2025 04:01:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>5 CAR T Cell Therapies With Autoimmune Readouts in 2025</title><link>https://www.biospace.com/drug-development/5-car-t-cell-therapies-with-autoimmune-readouts-in-2025</link><description>Biopharma is set to expand the successful application of CAR T therapies from cancer to autoimmune disorders, with several early- to mid-stage trial results anticipated this year. This shift reflects the industry's commitment to exploring innovative treatments beyond oncology.</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2025 04:01:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>GLP-1 Players Seek to Differentiate in Increasingly Crowded Weight Loss Space</title><link>https://www.biospace.com/drug-development/glp-1-players-seek-to-differentiate-in-increasingly-crowded-weight-loss-space</link><description>As obesity drug developers vie for the top weight-loss efficacy, experts suggest that achieving positive overall health outcomes, with promising studies in areas such as cardiovascular health and sleep apnea, could present a more significant market advantage. This shift in focus may reshape the competitive landscape of the obesity treatment industry.</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2025 04:01:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EC approves Bristol Myers Squibb’s follicular lymphoma CAR T therapy</title><link>https://www.pharmaceutical-technology.com/news/bristol-myers-squibb-fl-therapy/</link><description>The European Commission has granted expanded approval to Bristol Myers Squibb's (BMS) Breyanzi for the treatment of adults with relapsed or refractory follicular lymphoma. This decision marks a significant advancement in the treatment options available for patients suffering from this type of cancer.</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2025 08:22:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Latigo collects $150M to get non-opioid data to compete with Vertex in acute pain</title><link>https://endpts.com/latigo-collects-150m-to-get-non-opioid-data-to-compete-with-vertex-in-acute-pain/</link><description>Latigo Biotherapeutics aims to outperform Vertex Pharmaceuticals' newly approved pain treatment, Journavx, by developing a similar small molecule therapy. The company is focused on advancing its innovative approach in the competitive non-opioid pain management market.</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2025 09:00:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Taiho snaps up ADC partner Araris for up to $1.14bn</title><link>https://pharmaphorum.com/news/taiho-snaps-adc-partner-araris-114bn</link><description>Taiho has finalized an acquisition deal to purchase Swiss biotech Araris, following a collaboration that began 18 months ago focused on developing antibody-drug conjugates for cancer treatment. This strategic move enhances Taiho's capabilities in the oncology sector.</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2025 09:54:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Latigo raises $150m for non-opioid painkiller push</title><link>https://pharmaphorum.com/news/latigo-raises-150m-non-opioid-painkiller-push</link><description>Latigo has successfully raised $150 million in a Series B funding round to advance its development of innovative, non-opioid pain relief medications. This investment highlights growing investor confidence in alternatives to traditional opioid treatments.</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2025 10:30:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>HC Bioscience, a tRNA biotech backed by ARCH and Takeda, shuts down</title><link>https://endpts.com/hc-bioscience-a-trna-biotech-backed-by-arch-and-takeda-shuts-down/</link><description>Boston biotech startup HC Bioscience, which aimed to integrate transfer RNA (tRNA) biology into drug development, has abruptly closed its operations. The company, launched in 2022, struggled to establish itself in the competitive biotech landscape.</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2025 11:06:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>AstraZeneca spotlights first-in-human data for B7-H4-targeting ADC in endometrial cancer</title><link>https://endpts.com/astrazeneca-reveals-first-in-human-data-for-b7-h4-targeting-adc-in-endometrial-cancer/</link><description>AstraZeneca is moving forward with plans for a Phase 3 study of its B7-H4-targeting antibody-drug conjugate (ADC), following promising response and survival data from an early trial involving endometrial cancer patients. The drug's results have paved the way for further development as the company seeks to refine its research strategy.</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2025 11:20:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Otsuka's Taiho buys Swiss startup Araris with three ADCs nearing the clinic</title><link>https://endpts.com/otsukas-taiho-buys-swiss-startup-araris-with-three-adcs-nearing-the-clinic/</link><description>Otsuka's subsidiary is acquiring a small Swiss drug developer known for its innovative pipeline of three antibody-drug conjugates targeting oncology research and development. This acquisition highlights the growing interest and investment in next-generation cancer therapies.</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2025 11:30:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dyne's Duchenne Exon Skipping Oligomer Shows 'Differentiated' Clinical Effect</title><link>https://www.biospace.com/drug-development/dynes-duchenne-exon-skipping-oligomer-shows-differentiated-clinical-effect</link><description>Dyne is planning to file for accelerated approval of its drug DYNE-251 in early 2026, positioning it to compete with Sarepta's Exondys 51 in the same patient population that benefits from exon 51 skipping. This move highlights the competitive landscape in the treatment of genetic disorders.</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2025 12:30:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>AstraZeneca adds ‘in vivo’ cell therapy capabilities with EsoBiotech deal</title><link>https://www.biopharmadive.com/news/astrazeneca-esobiotech-acquire-in-vivo-cell-therapy/742643/</link><description>A pharmaceutical company is acquiring a Belgian startup for up to $1 billion, aiming to leverage its innovative technology for cancer and autoimmune treatments. This strategic purchase reflects the company's commitment to advancing its therapeutic pipeline.</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2025 13:28:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Latigo secures $150m for non-opioid pain treatment development</title><link>https://www.pharmaceutical-technology.com/news/latigo-non-opioid-pain-treatment/</link><description>Latigo has raised $150 million in a Series funding round to advance the development of its Nav1.8 inhibitors. This significant investment will help propel the company’s innovation in pain therapeutics.</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2025 13:54:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Orca Bio's T cell therapy may help blood cancer patients avoid transplant issues</title><link>https://endpts.com/orca-bios-t-cell-therapy-may-help-blood-cancer-patients-avoid-transplant-issues/</link><description>Orca Bio announced that its T cell therapy significantly lowers the risk of treatment complications associated with bone marrow transplants for patients with specific blood cancers. This breakthrough positions Orca Bio at the forefront of innovative cancer treatment solutions.</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2025 15:16:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Orca Bio to seek approval of T cell transplant after positive trial data</title><link>https://www.biopharmadive.com/news/orca-bio-t-cell-therapy-transplant-aml-study-results/742667/</link><description>Orca's treatment, featuring a purified mix of donor-derived T cells and stem cells, has demonstrated a safer profile compared to standard transplants in the treatment of specific blood cancers. This breakthrough could significantly impact the future of cancer therapy and improve patient outcomes.</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2025 15:30:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Incyte stock hit 11% despite paediatric dermatology trials hitting target</title><link>https://www.pharmaceutical-technology.com/news/incyte-stock-hit-11-despite-paediatric-dermatology-trials-hitting-target/</link><description>Incyte's dual trials of povorcitinib in patients with hidradenitis suppurativa (HS) reported over 40% of participants achieving a significant clinical response. These promising results may pave the way for further developments in HS treatment options.</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2025 16:11:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>AstraZeneca inks deal with Alteogen for subcutaneous cancer drugs</title><link>https://endpts.com/astrazeneca-inks-deal-with-alteogen-for-subcutaneous-cancer-drugs/</link><description>AstraZeneca is investing approximately $1.35 billion in Korean biotech firm Alteogen to develop under-the-skin formulations of various oncology therapies. The partnership will focus on licensing the compound ALT-B4, which enhances drug delivery by utilizing a specific enzyme.</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2025 19:40:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>How Proscia is using AI embeddings to transform drug discovery in pathology</title><link>https://www.drugdiscoverytrends.com/how-proscia-is-using-ai-embeddings-to-transform-drug-discovery-in-pathology/</link><description>Proscia has harnessed AI-powered pathology analysis to identify lung cancer patients who would benefit from a previously at-risk drug candidate, significantly altering its development trajectory. This innovative approach utilizes machine learning to enhance the precision of patient response predictions, potentially revolutionizing drug discovery in the field.</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2025 20:43:21 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>