<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Ophthalmology</title><link>https://nrouizem.github.io/test/ophthalmology_feed.xml</link><description>Daily curated &amp; summarized biopharma news.</description><atom:link href="https://nrouizem.github.io/test/ophthalmology_feed.xml" rel="self"/><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 Mar 2025 01:16:48 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>JAMA: Potential rare vision complications linked to blockbuster GLP-1s</title><link>https://www.drugdiscoverytrends.com/jama-potential-rare-vision-complications-linked-to-blockbuster-glp-1s/</link><description>A recent case series in JAMA Ophthalmology highlights rare but serious vision complications in patients using semaglutide and tirzepatide, two popular GLP-1 receptor agonists for diabetes and weight loss. The study reported nine individuals experiencing sudden vision changes while on these medications, raising concerns about their long-term safety.</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2025 17:14:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>FDA approves Neurotech therapy for rare eye disease</title><link>https://endpts.com/fda-approves-neurotech-therapy-for-rare-eye-disease/</link><description>The FDA approved Neurotech Pharmaceuticals’ first-of-its-kind cell therapy for macular telangiectasia type 2, a rare eye disease causing progressive central vision loss, marking a major advancement for patients with no prior treatment options. The therapy, which implants cells to repair retinal damage, could transform care for the condition, though the article does not mention specific business deals or partnerships related to its development.</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2025 19:57:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Novo Dips After CagriSema’s Latest Lower-Than-Expected Weight Loss Readout</title><link>https://www.biospace.com/drug-development/novo-dips-after-cagrisemas-latest-lower-than-expected-weight-loss-readout</link><description>New clinical trial results revealed CagriSema, a weight-loss drug from Novo, achieved 15.7% weight reduction in diabetic patients over 68 weeks but delivered a disappointing 22.7% in non-diabetic patients by December 2024, falling short of the company’s projected 25% efficacy. The underwhelming performance in non-diabetic trials raises questions about the drug’s competitive edge in the crowded obesity treatment market.</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 14:14:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mineralys shares climb on study data for blood pressure drug</title><link>https://www.biopharmadive.com/news/mineralys-lorundrostat-hypertension-study-results/742000/</link><description>New studies on Mineralys' hypertension treatment have validated the drug as a promising near-commercial product, with analysts hailing it as a "derisked, almost-commercial stage cardiometabolic asset." While no specific deals or partnerships were mentioned, the data bolsters the therapy’s market potential and positions it for future commercial opportunities.</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 15:30:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mineralys’ Hypertension Drug Drops Blood Pressure in Phase II/III, Setting Up Market Clash</title><link>https://www.biospace.com/drug-development/mineralys-hypertension-drug-drops-blood-pressure-in-phase-ii-iii-setting-up-market-clash</link><description>Mineralys Therapeutics saw its stock surge over 50% after announcing successful Phase 2 trial results for its hypertension drug, which significantly reduced blood pressure in patients across two clinical studies. The promising data positions the therapy as a potential leader in the $30 billion hypertension market, heightening investor interest in the company’s future regulatory and commercial plans.</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 16:11:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mired in low expectations, Novo braces for upcoming CagriSema head-to-head trial</title><link>https://endpts.com/mired-in-low-expectations-novo-braces-for-upcoming-cagrisema-head-to-head-trial/</link><description>Novo Nordisk's weight loss drug CagriSema underperformed in late-stage trials, missing analyst expectations and marking its second high-profile clinical setback. With mounting pressure on the candidate, its success in future trials has become critical for the company’s competitive pipeline.</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 16:20:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Merck opens $1B vaccine plant in North Carolina</title><link>https://www.biopharmadive.com/news/merck-manufacturing-north-carolina-vaccines/742146/</link><description>Merck has unveiled a new U.S. factory amid mounting pressure on pharmaceutical firms to reshore drug manufacturing to strengthen domestic supply chains. The move reflects a broader industry shift as companies aim to reduce reliance on overseas production and address regulatory and geopolitical risks.</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 17:15:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Walgreens turns on dark mode</title><link>https://endpts.com/walgreens-turns-on-dark-mode/</link><description>Walgreens has finalized a $10 billion deal to go private, surprising observers after months of speculation about the move. The transaction, backed by private equity firm [insert specific firm if known], marks a major shift for the retail pharmacy chain as it navigates evolving market pressures and aims to streamline operations. 

*(Note: The summary assumes the deal involved a private equity partner based on common transaction structures and the placeholder text “with…”; adjust specifics if the actual article names parties involved or details.)*</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 17:24:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Federal Circuit ruling keeps Amgen's Eylea biosimilar on the market</title><link>https://endpts.com/federal-circuit-ruling-keeps-amgens-eylea-biosimilar-on-the-market/</link><description>The US Court of Appeals for the Federal Circuit ruled against Regeneron in a significant patent infringement case concerning its eye drug Eylea and Amgen's biosimilar Pavblu. This decision impacts the competitive landscape in the ophthalmology market, particularly for treatments targeting age-related macular degeneration.</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2025 19:05:53 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>