<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Ophthalmology</title><link>https://nrouizem.github.io/test/ophthalmology_feed.xml</link><description>Daily curated &amp; summarized biopharma news.</description><atom:link href="https://nrouizem.github.io/test/ophthalmology_feed.xml" rel="self"/><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 01:19:02 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>ONI’s Aplo Scope achieves 20 nm imaging resolution, aims to cut drug target validation time</title><link>https://www.drugdiscoverytrends.com/onis-aplo-scope-achieves-20-nm-imaging-resolution-aims-to-cut-drug-target-validation-time/</link><description>Oxford Nanoimaging (ONI) has unveiled the Aplo Scope super-resolution microscope, achieving an impressive imaging precision of 20 nm. This innovative instrument combines lasers, optics, chemistry, and software in a compact design, making it easier for researchers to capture molecular interactions and potentially accelerate drug target validation.</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2025 01:12:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>JAMA: Potential rare vision complications linked to blockbuster GLP-1s</title><link>https://www.drugdiscoverytrends.com/jama-potential-rare-vision-complications-linked-to-blockbuster-glp-1s/</link><description>A recent case series in JAMA Ophthalmology has highlighted potential rare vision complications in patients using semaglutide and tirzepatide, two widely prescribed GLP-1 receptor agonists. Out of the nine individuals with reported sudden vision changes, seven were found to be using one of these medications.</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2025 17:14:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>FDA approves Neurotech therapy for rare eye disease</title><link>https://endpts.com/fda-approves-neurotech-therapy-for-rare-eye-disease/</link><description>The FDA approved Neurotech Pharmaceuticals’ first-of-its-kind cell therapy for macular telangiectasia type 2, a rare eye disease causing progressive central vision loss, marking a major advancement for patients with no prior treatment options. The therapy, which implants cells to repair retinal damage, could transform care for the condition, though the article does not mention specific business deals or partnerships related to its development.</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2025 19:57:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Stem cell company bit.bio lays off quarter of staff</title><link>https://endpts.com/stem-cell-company-bit-bio-lays-off-quarter-of-staff/</link><description>British stem cell company bit.bio has announced a 25% workforce reduction, primarily affecting its therapeutics division, as confirmed by founder Mark Kotter. Following the layoffs, approximately 150 employees will remain at the company.</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 19:38:01 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>