<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Ophthalmology</title><link>https://nrouizem.github.io/test/ophthalmology_feed.xml</link><description>Daily curated &amp; summarized biopharma news.</description><atom:link href="https://nrouizem.github.io/test/ophthalmology_feed.xml" rel="self"/><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2025 01:18:03 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>JAMA: Potential rare vision complications linked to blockbuster GLP-1s</title><link>https://www.drugdiscoverytrends.com/jama-potential-rare-vision-complications-linked-to-blockbuster-glp-1s/</link><description>A recent case series in JAMA Ophthalmology has highlighted rare but serious vision complications in patients using semaglutide or tirzepatide, popular GLP-1 receptor agonists for diabetes and weight loss. Nine individuals experienced sudden vision changes, raising concerns over the safety of these medications.</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2025 17:14:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>FDA approves Neurotech therapy for rare eye disease</title><link>https://endpts.com/fda-approves-neurotech-therapy-for-rare-eye-disease/</link><description>The FDA approved Neurotech Pharmaceuticals’ first-of-its-kind cell therapy for macular telangiectasia type 2, a rare eye disease causing progressive central vision loss, marking a major advancement for patients with no prior treatment options. The therapy, which implants cells to repair retinal damage, could transform care for the condition, though the article does not mention specific business deals or partnerships related to its development.</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2025 19:57:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Stem cell company bit.bio lays off quarter of staff</title><link>https://endpts.com/stem-cell-company-bit-bio-lays-off-quarter-of-staff/</link><description>British stem cell company bit.bio has laid off 25% of its workforce, primarily affecting its therapeutics division, as confirmed by founder Mark Kotter. The reduction leaves the company with approximately 150 employees as it navigates recent challenges.</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 19:38:01 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>