<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Ophthalmology</title><link>https://nrouizem.github.io/test/ophthalmology_feed.xml</link><description>Daily curated &amp; summarized biopharma news.</description><atom:link href="https://nrouizem.github.io/test/ophthalmology_feed.xml" rel="self"/><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 01:19:25 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>JAMA: Potential rare vision complications linked to blockbuster GLP-1s</title><link>https://www.drugdiscoverytrends.com/jama-potential-rare-vision-complications-linked-to-blockbuster-glp-1s/</link><description>A recent case series in JAMA Ophthalmology has highlighted rare but significant vision problems in patients taking semaglutide or tirzepatide, two widely used glucagon-like peptide-1 (GLP-1) receptor agonists for diabetes and weight management. Of the nine individuals studied, seven experienced sudden vision changes while on these medications, raising concerns about their safety.</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2025 17:14:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>FDA approves Neurotech therapy for rare eye disease</title><link>https://endpts.com/fda-approves-neurotech-therapy-for-rare-eye-disease/</link><description>The FDA approved Neurotech Pharmaceuticals’ first-of-its-kind cell therapy for macular telangiectasia type 2, a rare eye disease causing progressive central vision loss, marking a major advancement for patients with no prior treatment options. The therapy, which implants cells to repair retinal damage, could transform care for the condition, though the article does not mention specific business deals or partnerships related to its development.</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2025 19:57:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Insight and insitro partner on AI model to seek ocular biomarkers</title><link>https://www.pharmaceutical-technology.com/news/insight-insitro-ai-model/</link><description>Insight Health Data Research Hub and insitro have partnered to create an AI foundation model aimed at identifying ocular biomarkers. This collaboration seeks to enhance the understanding and diagnosis of eye-related health conditions through advanced technology.</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 10:47:43 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>