<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Ophthalmology</title><link>https://nrouizem.github.io/test/ophthalmology_feed.xml</link><description>Daily curated &amp; summarized biopharma news.</description><atom:link href="https://nrouizem.github.io/test/ophthalmology_feed.xml" rel="self"/><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2025 01:23:24 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>JAMA: Potential rare vision complications linked to blockbuster GLP-1s</title><link>https://www.drugdiscoverytrends.com/jama-potential-rare-vision-complications-linked-to-blockbuster-glp-1s/</link><description>A recent case series in JAMA Ophthalmology has highlighted rare but serious vision complications in patients using semaglutide or tirzepatide, two widely prescribed GLP-1 receptor agonists for diabetes and weight management. The study reported nine individuals experiencing sudden vision changes while taking these medications, raising concerns about their safety profiles.</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2025 17:14:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>FDA approves Neurotech therapy for rare eye disease</title><link>https://endpts.com/fda-approves-neurotech-therapy-for-rare-eye-disease/</link><description>The FDA approved Neurotech Pharmaceuticals’ first-of-its-kind cell therapy for macular telangiectasia type 2, a rare eye disease causing progressive central vision loss, marking a major advancement for patients with no prior treatment options. The therapy, which implants cells to repair retinal damage, could transform care for the condition, though the article does not mention specific business deals or partnerships related to its development.</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2025 19:57:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Novo Dips After CagriSema’s Latest Lower-Than-Expected Weight Loss Readout</title><link>https://www.biospace.com/drug-development/novo-dips-after-cagrisemas-latest-lower-than-expected-weight-loss-readout</link><description>New clinical trial results revealed CagriSema, a weight-loss drug from Novo, achieved 15.7% weight reduction in diabetic patients over 68 weeks but delivered a disappointing 22.7% in non-diabetic patients by December 2024, falling short of the company’s projected 25% efficacy. The underwhelming performance in non-diabetic trials raises questions about the drug’s competitive edge in the crowded obesity treatment market.</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 14:14:35 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>