<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Ophthalmology</title><link>https://nrouizem.github.io/test/ophthalmology_feed.xml</link><description>Daily curated &amp; summarized biopharma news.</description><atom:link href="https://nrouizem.github.io/test/ophthalmology_feed.xml" rel="self"/><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2025 02:01:35 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>JAMA: Potential rare vision complications linked to blockbuster GLP-1s</title><link>https://www.drugdiscoverytrends.com/jama-potential-rare-vision-complications-linked-to-blockbuster-glp-1s/</link><description>A new case series in JAMA Ophthalmology highlights rare but serious vision issues experienced by some patients taking semaglutide or tirzepatide, medications commonly used for diabetes and weight loss. The report documents sudden vision changes in nine individuals while using these glucagon-like peptide-1 receptor agonists.</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2025 17:14:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>FDA approves Neurotech therapy for rare eye disease</title><link>https://endpts.com/fda-approves-neurotech-therapy-for-rare-eye-disease/</link><description>The FDA approved Neurotech Pharmaceuticals’ first-of-its-kind cell therapy for macular telangiectasia type 2, a rare eye disease causing progressive central vision loss, marking a major advancement for patients with no prior treatment options. The therapy, which implants cells to repair retinal damage, could transform care for the condition, though the article does not mention specific business deals or partnerships related to its development.</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2025 19:57:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Novo Dips After CagriSema’s Latest Lower-Than-Expected Weight Loss Readout</title><link>https://www.biospace.com/drug-development/novo-dips-after-cagrisemas-latest-lower-than-expected-weight-loss-readout</link><description>New clinical trial results revealed CagriSema, a weight-loss drug from Novo, achieved 15.7% weight reduction in diabetic patients over 68 weeks but delivered a disappointing 22.7% in non-diabetic patients by December 2024, falling short of the company’s projected 25% efficacy. The underwhelming performance in non-diabetic trials raises questions about the drug’s competitive edge in the crowded obesity treatment market.</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 14:14:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mineralys shares climb on study data for blood pressure drug</title><link>https://www.biopharmadive.com/news/mineralys-lorundrostat-hypertension-study-results/742000/</link><description>New studies on Mineralys' hypertension treatment have validated the drug as a promising near-commercial product, with analysts hailing it as a "derisked, almost-commercial stage cardiometabolic asset." While no specific deals or partnerships were mentioned, the data bolsters the therapy’s market potential and positions it for future commercial opportunities.</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 15:30:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mineralys’ Hypertension Drug Drops Blood Pressure in Phase II/III, Setting Up Market Clash</title><link>https://www.biospace.com/drug-development/mineralys-hypertension-drug-drops-blood-pressure-in-phase-ii-iii-setting-up-market-clash</link><description>Mineralys Therapeutics saw its stock surge over 50% after announcing successful Phase 2 trial results for its hypertension drug, which significantly reduced blood pressure in patients across two clinical studies. The promising data positions the therapy as a potential leader in the $30 billion hypertension market, heightening investor interest in the company’s future regulatory and commercial plans.</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 16:11:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mineralys aims to raise $250M; Coherus discloses layoffs</title><link>https://endpts.com/mineralys-aims-to-raise-250m-coherus-discloses-layoffs/</link><description>Mineralys Therapeutics announced a $250 million follow-on offering following strong Phase 3 trial results for its hypertension drug lorundrostat, signaling investor confidence in its potential. The article does not mention specific deals, partnerships, mergers, or acquisitions involving BioNTech, Roche, Boehringer Ingelheim, or the other listed companies.</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 16:07:51 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>